Computer,
set heading 410 mark 32.
Course laid in.
Maximum warp.
Engage.
Time to Parada system.
One hour, 14 minutes.
Open a new file, computer.
O'Brien, Personal Log,
Stardate 47 581.2.
l've got to try to set
the record straight
about the last 52 hours.
l don't know
who's going to hear this.
l don't even know
if l'll be alive
by the time
this log is recovered.
l figure
they'll be coming after me.
lf l'm right
about this whole thing
they won't want me
to warn the Paradas.
Coffee, Jamaican blend--
double strong, double sweet.
l wish l could tell you
who they are
but that's a part of the puzzle
l haven't figured out yet.
A part of the puzzle, hell.
None of this whole damn thing
makes any sense.
l'm trying to remember
the first time l noticed
that things were wrong.
lt seems to me it was...
Yeah...
it had to be the first morning
after l got back
to the station.
What are you two
doing up so early?
Um, l had a lot of work
to catch up on at school.
Thought l'd get an early start.
At 5:30 in the morning?
Coffee, Jamaican blend--
double strong, double sweet.
l have a dozen essays to read.
Did you have sweet dreams,
darling?
Go away!
Don't l get my morning kiss?
No!
Well, what did l do
to deserve that?
lt's just a phase, Miles.
She doesn't mean it.
Huh?!
Don't let it bother you.
What time did you
get to bed last night?
l don't know-- late.
l didn't want to wake you.
l was tired.
l guess that trip
really took it out of me.
What did they have you doing?
The Paradas?
They put me
through basic training
on all the security measures
they want in place
for the peace talks.
Odo would have had a field day.
l wish he could have been there.
l'd better get going.
l'll drop Molly at day care
on the way to Ops.
Uh, that's okay.
l'm taking her with me.
Molly?
What? To school?
When you've got
all that reading to do?
That doesn't make
a lot of sense.
There's something
l want to show her.
Uh, a Vulcan program
that teaches basic
problem-solving skills.
At 5:30 in the morning?
l want to do it
while her mind is fresh.
Oh, if you say so.
See you later.
What's this?
Just getting a head start,
Chief.
Head start?
Everybody seems to be getting
a head start on me today.
Sir?
DeCurtis, l appreciate
your bushy-tailed enthusiasm
but l was waiting for Odo
to come back from Bajor
to do this.
We have to realign
the entire security net
for the peace talks.
The Constable might have
a few things
to say about it all.
Commander Sisko didn't feel
we should wait for Odo.
Sisko gave you permission
to start this
without asking me first?
l don't think so.
You might want to check
with him, sir.
l'm only following orders.
l'll check with him, all right.
Mr. O'Brien?
Carry on!
Computer, how much longer
to Parada system?
53 minutes.
Direct sensors
back toward the wormhole.
Scan for other warp signatures
on this heading.
One warp signature found.
Display.
Can you identify?
ldentification confirmed:
Starfleet Runabout Mekong.
Ah, l figured as much.
They'll wait for me
to drop out of warp and then...
Well, we'll have
to cross that bridge
when we come to it, won't we?
Please restate question.
Oh, disregard, computer.
Continue Personal Log.
Okay...
So, it was all a little curious
but who could have guessed
at that time?
l mean, the way they were acting
they might have been trying
to pull off
one of those surprise parties
that l can't stand.
Only my birthday's
not until September
and, believe me,
as it turned out
l had nothing else to celebrate.
Ah, there he is now.
l've been waiting for you,
Chief.
What is it, Julian?
No more excuses this time.
Excuses?
l'd like you
in my office in an hour.
For what?
Your physical.
You can't put this off
any longer.
Look, this isn't a good day.
lt's the perfect day.
Commander Sisko has arranged
to have you covered.
What are you doing,
going to the Commander
about my checkup?
Because this has been...
l know how you feel about...
Forget it.
l've got things to do.
l'm afraid l'll have to insist.
lf l have to order you
as your superior officer
l will.
ls there a problem?
Mr. O'Brien says
he's unavailable for a physical.
Make yourself available, Chief.
-Commander...
-Dr. Bashir's annual report
on the senior staff is due
at Starfleet next week.
We've all had
to go through this.
Fine. Fine.
l'll be there in an hour.
Commander, can l talk
to you for a minute?
Ensign DeCurtis mentioned to me
that you were a little upset.
Well, not upset, exactly.
No, no, no.
You have every right to be.
l'm sorry l assigned him
before advising you.
l guess l dropped
the ball on that one.
Well, l guess l just felt
a little left out
of the loop, you know?
Understood.
l've gone through your reports
on the Paradas.
They seem unusually preoccupied
with security.
Well, they may be
a little paranoid
but l suppose we would be, too
if we'd been engaged
in a civil war for 12 years.
Anything else l should
know about them?
Any unusual protocols
we should observe
when they get here?
No, nothing
too out of the ordinary.
lt's all pretty much
in my report.
Now, tell me something
that's not in the report.
Sir?
You know, the kinds of things
we don't include in reports
but might help me
in these talks.
Well, l'd have to give it
some thought.
Well, there was one thing
l noticed.
Well, l don't know if it means
anything or not
but the Paradas have an odor
from some kind of skin
excretions, l'd guess.
lt changes with their moods.
When they're upset, it can get
pretty strong, actually.
Oh, well, l'll try
not to get them upset.
Good idea.
Their leaders have been
in regular contact with us.
l've assured them
we'll be following
all of their security
recommendations to the letter.
l'll see to that.
Well, l certainly want you
to check everything
before they get here,
but the up-front work
can be done
by the engineering crews.
l have bigger problems for you.
Bigger?
All three upper pylons
are down again.
Well, that's impossible.
l went over that repair work
when l got back.
The pressure locks seemed
to be at maximum efficiency.
You'd better check again.
We had to tow in
a Bolian freighter
to a lower dock this morning.
Well, it can't be anything
that serious.
l rebuilt
that entire subsystem myself.
l'll get on it right away.
After your physical.
Yes, sir.
By the way,
l noticed you and Keiko
out in front of the school
this morning, talking.
ls there anything wrong?
Oh, Jake is having some problems
with his grades.
Oh, l'm sorry to hear that, sir.
Keiko's very fond of the boy.
l'm sure she'll work
that much harder to help him.
l'm sure she will.
Are you nearly finished?
l believe you've poked
into every orifice in my body
and created a few new ones.
Any dizziness?
Oversleeping?
Lack of energy?
Euphoria?
Yes! All of them!
Especially euphoria,
lots of euphoria!
Seriously.
Look, if you are determined
to keep me here
until you find
something wrong with me
l'll see if l can't grow you
a hangnail!
Eye problems?
Hearing? Headaches?
Headache-- there you go!
ln fact, l'm getting
a very bad one right now.
Short temper.
Flies off the handle under
the slightest provocation--
perfectly normal behavior.
Ah, l'm glad
you're enjoying this.
Sorry. l know how you feel
about doctors.
lt's not doctors
l have a problem with.
lt's you, Julian.
Well, your sense of humor
seems normal enough.
l don't have a sense of humor.
Cough.
How's the sex life?
l don't have a sense of humor.
Cough!
Everything all right
in that department?
That department is none of
Starfleet's business, or yours.
Mother and father
in good health?
Oh, come on, Julian!
You knew my mother died
two years ago.
Did l?
You don't remember me
telling you
when my father
remarried last spring?
Me blathering on about this
woman l've never met before?
Of course.
Now l remember.
Are you finished?
Not quite.
l just have
one or two more tests to run.
This is insane.
l haven't had a physical
take this long since l was born.
Look, unless l'm dying
or something
l think it's about time...
Wait.
That's it, isn't it?
l mean, there is
something wrong with me.
That's why everybody seems
so strange.
Relax, Chief.
l'm giving you
a clean bill of health.
You can get dressed.
Hey, Chief!
Hello, Jake.
l need a favor.
Sure, what is it?
l'm working
on a subspace transceiver
for my science project,
but l can't seem to figure out
how to get the emitter
crystal to work.
Subspace transceiver model--
l used to build them
when l was your age.
l'll be glad to help.
You don't think
it's a conflict of interest
or anything-- you being
married to the teacher?
Oh, we'll have to clear it
with Keiko
but l don't think she'll mind.
Besides, it's a chance
to help get
those grades of yours back up,
right?
Oh, my grades are great.
l just want to keep them
that way.
Sisko was telling the truth
about one thing:
The upper pylons
had failed again.
lt didn't make any sense
because the new pressure locks
l'd installed
seemed to be working just fine
so it had to be
an entirely new problem.
l realized it wasn't going
to be a quick matter
to track it down, after all.
And l couldn't help thinking
how this was going
to keep me occupied
while the security arrangements
for the Paradas were underway.
How's it coming, DeCurtis?
Chief, l thought
you had your hands full
with the upper pylons.
l do, but l thought
l'd take a break
check in on your progress.
Everything's on schedule here.
We made a complete sweep
of all the quarters
assigned to the Paradas.
Good. Open it up.
l'd like to look it over myself.
l can't, Chief...
That's an order!
Sir, the security seal
was activated
the minute we left.
Only Major Kira
has the access codes.
O'Brien to Kira.
Go ahead, Chief.
l'd like the access codes
to the Parada quarters.
Chief, what are you doing
down there?
Commander, l spent
the last week going over
these arrangements
with the Paradas.
l really need to be...
l want those upper pylons
operational, Chief.
That's your priority.
Understood?
Yes, sir.
Chief!
ls this the right inverter
for the subspace transceiver?
Where did you get this?
l haven't seen one of these
since l was a kid.
l replicated it.
l found the design
in a really,
really old data file
in the library program.
Really, really old?
Oh, l didn't mean that...
Don't worry about it.
Why don't you come by
my place tonight after dinner?
We'll see if we can add
the rest of the pieces.
Oh, that's great.
Jake, did anything unusual
happen here at the station
when l was
in the Gamma Quadrant last?
Jake, your father's
been looking for you.
l think he's back
in your quarters.
lt may be important.
See you later.
Everything under control, Chief?
Under control, Major.
l worked on the pylon controls
the better part of the day.
''A needle in a haystack''
wouldn't do this job justice.
When l finally found the crack
in the RF power conduit.
l couldn't imagine
how it could have occurred
so deep in the system
unless someone had broken
it deliberately.
Hard day?
Oh, yeah, you could say that.
You want to lie down
before dinner?
No, Jake's coming over
in a little while.
l promised to help him
with his science project.
Uh, Commander Sisko just called.
Jake can't make it tonight.
He isn't feeling well.
Really?
He seemed okay a few hours ago.
Well, you know
how it is with kids.
He probably just
ate too much junk
on the Promenade after school.
Where's Molly?
She's over at the Fredricksons
spending the night.
So, there's just
the two of us, then.
We'd better eat while
the food's still warm.
Well, the replicator
can keep it warm
and l can keep you warm.
What's the problem?
No problem.
Um, l'm just not in the mood.
l had a hard day, too.
Okay, we'll eat.
What is it?
Fricandeau stew.
But you don't like
fricandeau stew.
You do.
Yeah, but...
l just thought you'd appreciate
one of your favorite meals.
l know how you hate all that
terrible food when you're away.
A little endive salad,
sweet flan for dessert.
How thoughtful of you.
You're not having any?
l just feel like having salad.
You're not hungry?
l had a late lunch.
How is it?
You know,
l think l will lie down.
But you haven't eaten a bite.
Ah, l just don't seem
to have an appetite right now.
l don't know if there was
anything wrong with the stew
or not.
When l went back later to check
she'd already put it
into the disposal.
But all l could think of,
as l looked at her
was that this was not my Keiko.
Computer...
open O'Brien Personal Log.
Play back the last sentence.
...but all l could think of
as l looked at her
was that this was not my Keiko.
You're right.
She wasn't.
Continue log.
l didn't get much sleep
that night.
l waited for Keiko--
or whoever she was--
to go to bed,
and l started my search.
l had no idea
what l was looking for--
something odd,
something not quite normal
anything to explain
what might be going on.
Scan complete.
No unknown microorganisms
detected.
Check for traces
of any chemical agents
with bioactive properties.
No chemical agents with
bioactive properties detected.
Any unknown chemical agents?
Negative.
Access internal EM sensor grid.
Ready.
Scan for any evidence
of subharmonic transmissions.
Scan complete.
No subharmonic
transmissions detected.
Any unusual
neural wave patterns?
Negative.
Any telepathic activity
on board?
Negative.
Computer, display
all arriving vessels
from Stardate 47 550
through 47 57 1.
None from the Gamma Quadrant?
No ships arrived
from the Gamma Quadrant
within time parameters
requested.
Coffee, Jamaican blend,
double strong, double sweet.
You're drinking too much
of this stuff, O'Brien.
Anything to stay alert, O'Brien.
Okay, computer, play back
station logs chronologically
starting with stardate 47 550.
ldentify which officers' logs
are to be included.
All officers.
Vocal or transcribed?
Vocal.
Station Log, Stardate 47 552.9.
Admiral Gupta has arrived
to personally assess
the Cardassian movements
along the border.
Several Federation colonies
in the demilitarized zone
have complained of...
...discovered a new life-form
previously unreported.
We have tentatively classified
it as a protozoic species...
...lost in a shuttlepod
somewhere in the vicinity
of the third moon of Bajor Vll.
We have two runabouts to use...
...a request
by the Chamber of Ministers
that l find
absolutely ridiculous.
They have actually requested
that we begin to screen
all arriving...
...were completed at 1700 hours
and seemed to be functioning
with no further difficulties.
A level-1 diagnostic...
...The Admiral seemed satisfied
that the Cardassians
would not violate the treaty.
Access denied.
Denied?
Access denied to what?
Station Logs after Stardate
47 569.4 are restricted.
The day l got back.
Describe the restrictions.
Access restricted
to level-1 security clearance.
l am level-1.
Please enter
security verification.
Access denied.
Anything l can help you with,
Chief?
No, l'm just making sure
these upper pylons
are in working condition
by morning.
You're an inspiration
to us all.
There were several traps laid
into the computer subroutine.
No doubt to let someone know
if l'd penetrated
their security lockout.
l wasn't fooled for a minute
and released the protected
files without any problem.
What l found
in those hidden logs
didn't answer all my questions
but it sure as hell confirmed
what l'd been afraid of.
They were analyzing
and reanalyzing
everything l had put
into my report
about Paradan security.
They'd even broken
into my personal logs
to see what they could find
in there.
l hoped they enjoyed reading
the sexy letters to my wife.
There were several entries
by Sisko
about secured messages
from the Parada system
but no indication
what those messages were about.
Maybe they were afraid
l'd get into their files
even with a security lockout.
Smart people.
Chief.
Odo, we've got a problem.
l have to talk to you.
Hmm, it's good to see you, too.
Aside from Jake,
not one of them was...
l don't know, real.
l'm not sure who we can trust
in the station at this point.
Do any of them know
you're suspicious?
Probably.
l've asked a few questions
been a few places
that might have tipped them off.
They'll be keeping
close tabs on me.
l'd call Starfleet,
but what do l tell them?
My wife doesn't seem
like my wife?
Sisko's been making
security arrangements
without consulting me?
They might even call
Commander Sisko
and start asking
questions about you.
Well, that's
what l was afraid of.
And when are the Paradas due?
38 hours.
Hmm. l don't want them coming
anywhere near this place
until we get this cleared up.
Agreed.
Go on about your business.
Don't do anything
to get their attention.
ln the meantime,
l'll do some investigating.
lf l can confirm your suspicions
we can go to Starfleet
and the Bajoran authorities
at the same time.
l'm glad you're back, Odo.
We'll get to the bottom of this.
l felt better
than l had for a long time.
l finally had an ally.
Now all l had to do was wait.
l like to think
l'm a man with many talents
but waiting isn't one of them.
l had to cover my bets--
prepare myself for whatever
might happen next.
l still had a few tricks
up my sleeve.
The odds are against you,
O'Brien.
Against me?
What are you talking about?
You know what l'm talking about.
You look tired.
Have you been getting
enough sleep?
What are you talking
about, Quark?!
Racquetball, the rematch
with Bashir next week.
We never finished
the first one, remember?
My, we are jumpy, aren't we?
Change the subject.
Fine, we'll change the subject.
So, uh...
tell me about the Paradas.
They're going to be
here when-- tomorrow?
Why do you want to know
anything about the Paradas?
lt's always good business
to know about new customers
before they walk in your door.
Oh, and which Rule
of Acquisition is that?
Oh, one of the high numbers,
194, l think.
Well, you'll have to find
out about the Paradas
from someone else.
Odo to O'Brien.
Go ahead.
Can l see you in my office?
On my way.
l see what you mean.
What did you find out?
Sit down.
How much do you know
about the Paradan rebels?
Oh, don't ask me to explain
the politics of the situation
but l know they've been
fighting the government forces
for 12 years. Why?
l'm just trying to understand
the players involved here.
Odo, Sisko's logs indicate
that secret messages
have been coming
from the Parada system.
Could those messages have been
from the rebels?
As a matter of fact, they were.
That's already a breach
of the security agreement
we signed
with the Paradan government.
And it's a good enough reason
to cancel these peace talks.
That still might be premature.
What are you talking about?
We've got more than enough...
They got to you.
Don't be ridiculous.
l'm just trying...
No, they did, they got to you.
All right, let's have
a little talk.
Who the hell are you?
We don't want to hurt you.
Here, this will help you relax.
Computer, lock onto my combadge.
lnitiate emergency transport
to Runabout Rio Grande.
Unable to complete request.
Please contact Station Commander
for assistance.
Making it tough for me, huh?
Fine.
You want force fields,
l'll give you force fields.
There.
Now you want to get me?
You'll have to release them all.
Ha. Thank you.
Jake! You okay?
Yeah.
Good.
Listen to me.
Something isn't normal
around here.
Your dad, the others--
something's happened to them.
You and l are the only ones
who can help.
Jake Sisko to Security.
He's here.
Level H-2, Section Five.
lt will be okay.
Just surrender to them,
and you'll be fine.
l'll search all habitat range...
You two...
Spread out.
Check all quarters.
Advise people to stay
where they are
and not to let anyone in.
Yes, sir.
Shut down your engines.
Sorry, Commander.
l have no intention
of doing that.
You will not be
allowed to leave.
l repeat.
Shut down your engines now.
lf you check your systems
you'll find that the mooring
clamps are already unlocked
and your tractor beams
are off-line.
O'Brien out.
Shields up.
Are the shields holding,
computer?
Shields at 7 1 percent.
Warning, shields at 49 percent.
Transfer emergency life support
power to shield generators.
Transfer complete.
Shield status.
Shields at 93 percent.
Full impulse,
heading 41 mark 330.
Confirmed.
Computer, open a subspace
channel to Starbase 401.
Priority one, Admiral Rollman.
Stand by.
Admiral, Miles O'Brien
Chief of Operations,
Deep Space 9.
l know who you are.
Admiral, l must apprise you
of an emergency situation
on the station.
There's been some sort
of takeover, a conspiracy.
l believe it has something to do
with the Paradan peace talks.
Listen to me very carefully.
Return to DS9 immediately.
Admiral, you don't understand.
l believe Commander Sisko
and all of the senior officers
have fallen under
the influence of something...
Turn the ship around
and go back.
You will not be harmed.
lt seemed almost
unbelievable to me.
Had someone or something
started to infiltrate
all of Starfleet?
Computer, new heading.
180 mark 31, to the wormhole.
Coffee, Jamaican blend,
double strong, double sweet.
Time to Paradas system,
computer.
One minute, 20 seconds.
How much lead time
do we have on the Mekong?
At current speeds,
seven minutes, four seconds.
That will disappear in a hurry
once we drop out of warp.
Ah, at least, l get to choose
where they catch up.
Computer, identify the largest
planet in the Parada system.
Parada lV.
Adjust course
to approach Parada lV.
Confirmed.
How many moons
around Parada lV?
Seven.
Hmm, lucky seven.
Display coordinates.
Approaching the Parada system.
Drop to impulse.
Status of Mekong.
Mekong has dropped out of warp
and has adjusted course
to identical heading.
Perfect.
How much time
have they made up on us?
At current speed, the Mekong
is two minutes, one second
behind this vessel.
Adjust speed to let them catch
up to us in 30 seconds.
Dropping to point-four impulse.
Come on, l'm waiting for you.
Warning.
Entering polar-magnetic field.
Sensors will be nonfunctional
for 27 seconds.
Switch to manual navigation.
Switching.
Computer, full impulse.
Engage.
Confirmed.
Manual navigation in effect.
Shut down all engines,
all main power systems.
Maintain silent running status.
Confirmed.
Yeah, where did l go?
Now you see me, now you don't.
What's it going to be, fellas?
l can play hide-and-seek
with the best of them.
Hmm, no time for games, huh?
Computer, identify
Mekong's new heading.
41 mark 201.
Probable destination?
Parada ll.
Parada ll...
what's on Parada ll?
Specify parameters.
Computer, monitor
all transporter activity
to and from the Mekong.
The Mekong transporter
has been energized.
What?
They beamed to the surface?
Confirmed.
How many people?
Three people.
Anyone left on board?
Negative.
Put us on a course
for Parada ll.
Take us into synchronous orbit
above their location
on the surface.
Having a little
unscheduled negotiation
with the rebels, are we?
You don't understand.
Put down your weapons,
and we'll explain.
No.
l've got a better idea.
You put down yours first.
Do it!
You, too!
Everything you need
to understand
is behind this door.
Yeah, like a squadron of rebels
maybe, huh?
No.
lf you just permit me.
Just stay where you are.
Listen to him.
He's not your enemy.
We're not your enemy.
No?
Please, this will
explain everything.
l don't want to hurt you.
Doctor, we need you!
He's perfect.
He looks just like me.
Apparently,
he thought he was you.
No doubt they thought
that would make him
more convincing.
We believe there
was some triggering device
programmed into him
that would take over
during the peace talks.
The government scientists
have learned how to do
remarkable things
with replicants.
What was he programmed to do?
We're not entirely sure.
Assassinate someone
at the peace talks, we think.
Perhaps our entire delegation.
They were tipped off
by one of the informants
in their government.
There was a rumor
that you'd been abducted
and replaced by a replicant.
We've had people looking
for you ever since.
There was no way
to prove he wasn't you.
He passed a physical exam
with flying colors.
And he sure knew his way
around the station.
l had more wires
attached to my head
than you could count.
Now l know why.
We were trying to shut him out
of every sensitive security area
while they were searching
for you.
He must have wondered
what the hell was going on
with all of us.
By the time we'd learned
of your rescue
he'd already gotten away from us
and was on his way here.
l wonder why he was coming back.
lf it were me,
l'd be trying to warn somebody
there was something
wrong at the station.
Maybe in a strange sort of way,
he was trying to be a hero.
Keiko...
What about her?
Tell her...
l love...