Last time on Deep Space Nine...
This is the emblem
of the Alliance
for Global Unity.
They call themselves
the Circle.
What gives them the right
to mess up our station?
They're an extremist faction
who believe in Bajor
for the Bajorans.
l can't loan you
a Starfleet runabout
without knowing
where you plan on taking it.
To Cardassia lV to rescue
a Bajoran prisoner of war.
Come on.
We have a ship waiting.
What you did today, Major,
was declare war on Cardassia.
Thankfully, they declined
the invitation.
What if l told you
that l knew someone
who could bring
stability to Bajor?
Someone who could
unite the factions
and give us a chance
to do our job?
Bajor doesn't need a man.
lt needs a symbol,
and that's what you are.
The Navarch needed to return
here to assume his new post.
He's been made the Bajoran
Liaison Officer to Deep Space 9.
l already have
a liaison officer.
Not anymore, you don't.
Major Kira is no longer
assigned to this post.
She's been recalled to Bajor.
And now, the continuation.
Frankly, Commander,
l'm surprised at your reaction.
Oh, l don't think much
surprises you, Minister.
But l was expecting you
to be celebrating.
l was under the impression
Major Kira has been
nothing but trouble...
Who gave you that impression?
Common knowledge.
Major Kira
has my complete respect.
She's been invaluable
in establishing
this command post
and now she's been dismissed
without anyone consulting me
and l don't appreciate it.
Commander, Starfleet
doesn't consult us
when they wish to promote
one of their officers.
Are you suggesting that this
is a promotion for Kira?
Certainly, it is.
We need to find
the proper spot for her.
After all, she's the one
who brought Li Nalas back to us.
Well, then,
that's a different matter.
l'm glad you see it.
Yes, of course l do.
For a minute,
l was thinking to myself
''There's a warm wind
blowing in from Minicoy.''
l'm sorry?
lt's just
an old saying from Earth.
lt all started with a famous
ambassador from Minicoy
who used to bluster,
exaggerate and dissemble
to get what he wanted.
Not at all like you or me.
He was a bag of hot air
and everyone recognized him
for what he was.
May l assume you're satisfied
with the assignment of Li
to fill your vacant post?
l'd thought you'd want Li
to stay in the capital
to strengthen
the provisional government.
Frankly, l'm not sure
it's safe in the capital
with what's going on these days.
The Circle?
The fires and graffiti
were a nuisance
but two days ago
one of my fellow Ministers
was attacked and beaten.
We can't risk the same thing
happening to Li Nalas.
Look at it this way, Commander.
We're entrusting
Bajor's greatest hero to you.
Could you have
a better liaison
officer than Li Nalas?
l think not.
Commander, your son
has been waiting
to speak to you on the com.
Jake?
Dad?
l'm outside our quarters.
Could you come down
for a minute?
ls something wrong?
l really think you ought
to come down, Dad.
On my way.
What's the problem?
Look.
Come in.
You're not...?
Leaving?
l really don't have
much choice, do l?
You're not just leaving, Major.
You're surrendering.
You break the rules, you pay.
Wait a minute.
l want to be sure
l heard that correctly
because it doesn't sound
like the Kira Nerys
who has made a career
out of breaking the rules.
Well, l guess l broke
one too many.
Major, you've been
breaking one too many
for 141/2 years.
Cardassian rules, Bajoran
rules, Federation rules--
they're all meaningless to you
because you have a personal code
that's always mattered more
and l'm sorry to say,
you're in slim company.
l'll miss you too, Odo.
Have you asked Sisko for help?
l'm sure he'll do whatever he
thinks is best for the station.
You haven't even gone to him?
Well, what do you
want me to do, Odo?
Fight for what you want!
lt's what you do best!
Well, maybe l just want
a vacation.
Ach! ldiotic bureaucracy!
Now, l suppose they'll expect
me to break in a new man.
A great man-- Li Nalas
can handle the job, believe me.
Well, you did fairly well at it
once l smoothed
your rough edges.
Hah.
What's so funny?
l thought you did fairly well
once l smoothed
your rough edges.
Yes?
Am l disturbing anything?
Stick around.
You can help me cry
in my synthale.
l thought l should return
this epidellic lotion.
No. lf you like it...
Oh, it's wonderful.
Well, then keep it.
How can you be chatting
about skin lotion
at a time like this?
Do you have any idea
where you'll be stationed?
Come in.
Not yet.
They say that after l've
taken some leave time
l've earned a desk
at the Foreign Affairs
Building somewhere.
Doctor.
Foreign Affairs Building?
l came to give you my best.
Well, that's rather dull.
l beg your pardon?
Dull is a polite word for it.
Doctor, if you were Kira
wouldn't you at least be
complaining to Commander Sisko?
Look, l just wanted
to wish you good luck.
Thank you, Doctor.
Complaining about what?
Never mind, Doctor.
lf she doesn't care,
why should we?
Have they given you
any reason yet?
Did they give you
any alternative?
l do care.
No, they haven't.
No, they didn't.
l really ought
to finish packing.
You said she doesn't care.
You mean about
leaving the station?
By all means, come on in.
She's done well here.
She ought to stay here.
And l say she could use
a little support
from her friends, Doctor.
Well, yes, certainly, but...
Uh...
Chief! Come in.
l didn't mean to intrude.
l was just...
Don't worry, Chief,
it's all been said.
l have a good deal more to say,
thank you, Doctor.
Look, l could come back.
Odo, leave her alone.
This is Kira's
decision to make--
unless, of course, you
want me to talk to Sisko.
l knew what l was doing.
l knew the risk.
That's not what she asked.
l'd just like to say, Major
it's been a pleasure
serving with you.
Come in.
Will someone please explain
this conversation to me?
A party! Oh!
For you, l would have reduced
my catering rate.
lt's not a party.
Voodai.
What's that?
A bottle of my favorite
synthale, l think.
That's very thoughtful, Quark.
lt's also very small.
l was anticipating
a far smaller gathering.
l thought perhaps
an intimate farewell drink
a sympathetic smile...
a shoulder to cry on.
As l was saying, Major...
You'd be surprised
how often that works with women.
ls this a joke?
Did you plan this?
Nobody could have planned this.
Oh, we're open for business.
Come on in, join the crowd.
Vedek Bareil.
l hope l'm not interrupting.
No. Please come in.
These are my...
these are my friends.
l had no idea you were coming
to the space station.
Well, nowadays,
it's probably wiser
not to announce these things.
How bad is it on Bajor, Vedek?
The violence has
seriously escalated.
lt almost seems there are
more weapons on the street now
than during the occupation.
How could that be?
Where would they be coming from?
l try to concentrate
on more spiritual matters.
Yes, of course.
l mean... l didn't mean
to suggest that you...
l understand
your duties here are finished.
Yes, they are.
Do you have any immediate plans?
l haven't really had much chance
to give it any thought.
Then perhaps l have
the perfect solution.
Come and stay
at our monastery for a while.
lt can help when the spirit
gets a little bruised.
Thank you.
Major?
l just want you to know that,
uh...
if there's anything
l can do to help.
Major...
l'm sorry.
l didn't want this job.
Neither did l.
l mean, back when l was
sent here in the first place
but it, um, turned out
better than l expected.
l'm sure it will
for you as well.
l don't even know
what l'm supposed to do here.
How does a ''Navarch''
fit into
this command structure?
As l understand the position
you report directly
to the Prophets
but, from time to time,
l might ask your help.
Commander
anything you need from me,
l will try my best to do
but l know that l can
never replace Major Kira.
No one could.
Thank you, sir.
Request permission to disembark.
l'm going to get you back,
Major.
l promise that to both of us.
Docking Bay 3.
May l make
a friendly observation?
-lt's crooked.
l've been adjusting it
for an hour.
lt looks fine from over here
but then l go
over there and it's...
This isn't working, Bareil.
lt's only a row of stones.
No, it isn't.
lt's me.
The stones are straight.
l'm the one who's crooked.
ls that really
how you see yourself?
Sometimes.
Sometimes l even like
being that way.
lf l stay here much longer
l'm sure l could destroy
your entire arboretum.
Well, perhaps you'd
rather try your hand
at woodcrafts.
Can l tell you something
very personal?
Of course.
You won't tell?
l'm a Vedek.
l have absolutely
no artistic skills.
l was the worst finger painter
at the four-year-old level.
My parents were humiliated.
lt'll be our secret.
The point is...
l'm useless here.
So?
l need to feel useful.
lt might be interesting
to explore useless for a while--
see how it feels.
Oh...
Well, you don't know me.
l'm beginning to.
lt's time, isn't it?
Time?
Come inside with me.
l really should finish...
Come.
l've never been to this part
of the monastery before.
May it be the first
of many visits.
Bareil, maybe we
should talk about...
Oh, Bareil...
all my life, l dreamed of this.
lt is the Third Orb--
the Orb of Prophecy and Change.
What do l do?
Be useless, Nerys.
Allow the Prophets to guide you.
The Chamber of Ministers.
Dax.
Listen to them, Kira.
l can't hear them.
lt's all right.
Listen.
Can you hear them now, child?
l hear them, Major.
They're calling to me.
Don't listen to him, Nerys.
Allow yourself to hear them.
They're calling to you.
Blasphemy.
Listen to them, Nerys.
Help me to hear them.
l don't know how.
But you do.
You do.
Last night alone,
we had dozens of beatings.
They're everywhere--
till we go looking for them
and then they're nowhere.
Which would suggest
they have powerful friends
to warn them and protect them.
Probably.
We've got to put a stop to this
before it gets out of hand.
Now, the provisional government
is bringing troops
into the capital.
Troops?
That will put an end
to the Circle.
And you keep your eyes open
up there, old friend.
l always do.
No, l haven't made any progress
in finding the ones
who assaulted you.
lt's over, Odo.
The investigation isn't closed.
lt's just...
You don't understand.
lt's over.
What are you talking about?
Everything.
Bajor, the provisional
government
the Federation being here--
all of it.
We got to leave.
Well, l do anyway.
You can just turn into a couch.
You mean because
of this Circle business?
They're just
a bunch of hooligans
who use violence
to get attention.
l happen to know
they have enough weapons
and explosives and supplies
to support an army.
How do you know that?
l've been asking questions
of people
who don't answer questions
from people like you.
Where would the Circle
be getting so many weapons?
The Kressari.
The Kressari?
That doesn't make any sense.
The Kressari
don't even have a military.
They're botanic DNA traders.
Well, they're not
delivering flowers these days.
l know, Odo.
Computer, when's the next
Kressari vessel due here?
The Kressari Vessel Calondon
is scheduled to arrive
in 36 hours.
Do you know
where these weapons
are being sent to on Bajor?
No, not exactly.
Find out.
Are you out of your mind?
My plan is to put
as much distance as possible
between me and Bajor,
thank you very much.
Quark, l hate to do this,
but l guess l'll have to.
That's not fair.
l haven't done anything yet.
Whatever you're going to do,
it's not fair.
You're a deputy.
lt's not-- what?
l want you to find out
where the weapons
are going on Bajor.
Meanwhile...
l'm going to find out
exactly where
they're coming from.
You and me, a team?
That's right.
Good-bye.
Either that
or l'm putting you in a cell.
That's not fair.
On what charge?
lmpeding an investigation--
unless you want
to reveal the identities
of the people
you've been talking to.
You know l can't do that.
lt's your choice.
You're a deputy
or you're a prisoner.
l'm a deputy.
l've got to go to Bajor.
Odo has some information
that suggests
we may be facing a coup
and l've got to check
things out.
ls there any way l can help?
Your military contacts--
see if you can get a feeling
for how much support
the provisional government has.
No problem. What about the
station while you're gone?
Dax and Mr. O'Brien
can handle things in Ops.
lf you need any other help...
Help?
l can't even sneeze
without three people
handing me handkerchiefs
but l was thinking
we might want
to establish a curfew.
Another cargo bay was
vandalized last night.
Good idea.
l've asked Odo
to assign you a bodyguard.
Oh, it's not necessary.
l think it is.
Docking Bay 1.
Woodcrafts--
definitely the way to go.
ls that where the Prophets
led you?
Yeah. Lots of, uh,
hammers and nails and saws
surrounded by monks
and Vedeks--
very safe and secure.
You don't want to talk about it.
No.
Can l tell you something
very personal?
l'm not a Vedek,
but l can keep a secret.
The last time
l encountered the Third Orb
you were part of my vision.
Me?
lt's the reason
l came to the station
to invite you here.
What...
what part did l play
in your vision?
lt's not important.
l was just wondering
if l was part of yours.
No. No, you weren't.
How could there be a storm
on a day as lovely as this?
That's not thunder.
l know that sound.
That's gunfire.
What a pleasure to come upon
such a flowing exchange
of spiritual harmony.
Vedek Winn.
We've met before,
haven't we... Major?
Major...
Kira Nerys.
That's right.
Major Kira.
From the space station.
What brings you here?
l do, Vedek Winn.
Good for you, Vedek Bareil.
After working so hard,
you deserve a little recreation.
Major Kira is here
to explore her pagh.
A worthy endeavor
for someone who has led
such a life of violence, child.
And l'm sure the Assembly
would have had no objection
to your encounter with an Orb
had Vedek Bareil consulted us.
No one has ever been held
to that formality.
You're right, of course.
But l've always consulted
with the Assembly in advance.
l think of it as a courtesy.
Nothing more, nothing less.
How long will you be with us,
Major?
l'm not sure.
Feel free to stay as many days
as you like.
Even a week, if necessary.
Have them withdraw
from the northeast quadrant.
Move them to join
the 14th column
south of the city.
General Krim.
l'm Benjamin Sisko.
We met during a session
of the Executive
Committee last year.
l remember, Commander.
l was impressed by your talk.
As l recall, you disagreed
with all of it.
Yes.
But you presented
your arguments well.
What can l do for you?
l understand you're in command
of the forces
defending the city.
l'd hardly call it
There is concern
in some quarters
that the military is unwilling
to confront the forces
of the Circle.
l don't know with whom
you've been speaking, Commander.
l've been observing
troop movements.
Every time there is
a potential confrontation
the military withdraws
to a safer position.
You can't possibly appreciate
that this is Bajoran
against Bajoran.
l appreciate that the
provisional government
will stand only
if the military supports it.
We are all patriots, Commander.
We have intelligence
that the Circle is being armed
by the Kressari.
The Kressari?
l hadn't heard that.
We've been trying
to track the movement
of those shipments.
lf we could determine
where they're stored,
then we can...
l'd like to know.
You'll be the first one
l contact.
Thank you.
There is one other thing,
General.
My First Officer,
Major Kira Nerys...
Yes, l know Major Kira.
l understand
she hasn't been reassigned yet.
lt would mean a great deal to me
to get her back.
That's out of my purview,
Commander.
You might want to discuss it
with Minister Jaro.
Commander Sisko...
you told me about the Kressari
before you asked the favor
regarding Kira.
You could have tried
to trade that information
for the favor.
l wouldn't do that.
l'll remember that about you.
He's calling again.
What do you think we should do?
l think he's getting
tired of seeing me smile.
Anything new
from O'Brien or Odo?
They haven't come up
with anything yet.
All right.
Put him on the screen.
l will give this a try.
l am First Officer Li Nalas.
Can l help you?
Somebody better be able
to help me.
l have been delayed
for six hours.
l can assure you
the Kressari government
will lodge a formal protest.
My apologies.
Apparently, there has been
some confusion
with your manifest interface
in our computer inventory
system that had to be...
Yes, yes.
l know all of that.
l didn't know they were going
to be opening
every container
in my cargo hold!
Do you understand
these are highly sensitive
herbaceous materials?
l am sure that all necessary
precautions are being taken.
This is ridiculous.
l have a schedule to keep!
We should be able to have this
all cleared up in a few minutes.
That's what l was told
a few hours ago.
Dax to O'Brien.
Yes, Lieutenant?
We don't want to hold up
the Kressari
any longer than necessary.
Well, there isn't much more
we can accomplish for now.
The ship's due back here
the day after tomorrow.
Perhaps we'll be able to correct
any additional problems then.
Yeah, we'd come
to the same conclusion.
O'Brien out.
A fair voyage to you, Captain.
Prepare for immediate departure.
Major.
Commander.
l didn't hear you.
l'm sorry if l interrupted
your meditation.
Daydream.
Daydreaming...
l think l remember doing that
a long, long time ago.
l've discovered
it's like riding a bicycle.
lt comes back to you
right away.
Can l bring you
back to reality for a minute?
Back to reality...
or back to DS9?
Are you still interested?
A lot has happened here.
l encountered an Orb,
Commander.
lt's given me
a great deal to think about.
They do have a way
of doing that, don't they?
Well...
l just came to let you know
that we haven't given up yet
but for the moment
there seem to be
some bigger problems
for the leaders down here.
l heard the gunfire
in the distance.
That distance is getting closer.
The Circle is for real, Major.
They've been armed for a coup.
And l'm not at all convinced
that the military
is going to back
the provisional government.
l didn't realize it...
We've been so isolated.
Well..
l guess l'd better get back.
Commander...
Me, too.
l told you l haven't given up.
Begin transport.
l think you'll find
everything's in order.
Very well.
lf you'll sign off
on the shipment
we'll be on our way.
Return transport.
Good afternoon.
So... you're involved
with the Circle.
l am the Circle, Major.
Now l understand why you wanted
to ship Li Nalas
off to the station.
The last thing l need right now
is a great war hero
capturing the devotion
of the Bajoran people.
How can you betray
your own government?
Major, l don't have to tell you.
l've heard your opinion
of this government.
Government?
They can't even agree
it is a government
so they call it ''provisional.''
lt's just another word
for powerless.
l won't allow the Bajoran people
to be powerless anymore.
We have been doormats
to the Cardassians,
and now the Federation--
any great power that happens by.
We will not be that again.
We are a people who brought art
and architecture
to countless planets.
We don't deserve to be victims.
lf you want to change
the government, Minister Jaro
you vote to change it.
You don't sneak up
from behind it with a dagger.
We'll discuss politics
at another time.
l need to know, please,
what the Federation will do
once our objective
becomes clear.
Major, l've heard you have
no love for the Federation.
l'm not an unreasonable man.
l'm willing to send you back
to the station
if that's what you want.
l'll give you that station
after we get rid of Starfleet.
Now, do you believe
they will continue
to support
the provisional government?
How about our own military?
l'd worry about them first
if l were you.
What will the Federation do,
Major?
What will Sisko do?
You know him better
than any Bajoran.
No one despises the Cardassians
more than l, Major
but we did learn
a few things from them.
Like how to encourage people
to talk.
Let's go.
Bareil says there were
no signs of a struggle.
Maybe somebody saw them leave.
That's what we need to find out.
What if they transported
her off the grounds?
Let's hope they didn't.
Now, we can't expect much help
from the local authorities.
They've got their hands full.
Commander, l should be able
to get some cooperation.
lf my name carries any weight,
let's use it.
Good.
When's Odo due back?
Not for another 12 hours.
Who needs Odo when you've got
his number one deputy?
Quark, this isn't the time.
No, this is exactly the time.
l think l know
where you can find Kira.
Go on.
You see, uh, Odo blackmailed me
into helping him.
A matter which l've been meaning
to bring to your attention,
Commander.
Quark.
l managed to find out
where the Circle's
headquarters is.
ln the labyrinths beneath
the Perikian peninsula.
Sisko to security.
Go ahead.
l need a couple of officers
to go on a rescue mission
to Bajor.
Report to Runabout Pad C.
On our way.
Doctor, Lieutenant,
you're with me.
Mr. O'Brien,
you'll be our pilot.
Configure the runabout sensors
for a full sweep
of the peninsula.
Once we find the base,
l'll depending a great deal
on your famous
transporter talents.
Aye, sir.
Commander, l'm going.
No, it's too dangerous.
Don't you understand?
l can do this.
l don't know what it means
to be a Navarch
but l can fight in the trenches
and l take orders well.
Besides, l owe her one.
Dax, you're in charge.
We can discuss appropriate
compensation for this
at a more convenient time!
Need one.
Check all the settings
on those phasers.
Two men, Sector B.
Take your positions.
Yes, sir.
Only five, but they've got
more firearms
than a Galaxy-class starship.
Where the hell's it coming from?
All right, straight power play.
Nothing fancy.
Expect heavy resistance.
Anyone who finds Kira
pin this on her, and call
for transport immediately.
Let's do it.
Kira!
Chief, get us out of here!
We don't have time for this.
Ow, ow.
Ouch.
Do not talk.
We have to assume
Jaro will move quickly
now that we've got you back.
Li is the only
chance we've got.
Me?
Jaro knows you're the only
force that could stop him.
lf we could get him to the
Chamber of Ministers...
lt's much too great a risk.
He'd be dead before he
had a chance to speak.
Courtesy of a Cardassian weapon.
The Circle's being supplied
by the Cardassians.
What?
l borrowed the proof.
lt's got a Gul's thumb scan
on it.
The Circle hates
the Cardassians.
They don't know
it is the Cardassians.
They think they've been buying
from Kressari traders.
l don't understand.
Why would the Cardassians
want to help Jaro
if he hates them?
Because it gets them
what they want the most.
Rid of us.
They're just using Jaro.
Once the Federation
is forced to leave...
The Cardassians come back.
We've got to do something.
l've got to do something.
Sisko to Ops.
Go ahead.
Dax, open a channel to Bajor.
Tell them that Navarch Li Nalas
wants to address the Chamber
of Ministers on subspace.
l can't do it, Benjamin.
All frequencies
to Bajor are jammed.
We lost all communication with
the planet five minutes ago.
Then, it has started.
Get me Admiral Chekote
at Starfleet Command.
l feel the Prophets
smiling on me today, Vedek.
The Prophets have rarely
encountered a pagh
as forceful as yours,
Minister Jaro.
So, what's it to be, Winn?
Be?
Don't tease me.
l can't interpret
the prophecies for you, Essa.
l know the future.
lt belongs to me.
l don't need
your interpretation.
Then what?
Your support.
l've made it very clear
to you how l feel.
Your public support.
Support from the Vedek
of an order so small as mine
surely would not be significant.
You stand for a return...
to orthodox values, as do l.
We're a match
made by the Prophets.
l wish there were more
with that opinion.
Unfortunately, as my assembly
approaches the selection
of a new Kai
l fear my voice is rarely heard.
That can change.
Can it?
Think of the prestige of having
the new leader of Bajor
being a member of your order.
lf you are the new leader.
Have the Prophets given you
a reason to doubt it?
l didn't say that.
Then let them bless
my ascension.
Tell the people
the Prophets are with me.
That's a lot to ask.
l know that.
l need more than just prestige,
Essa.
l know that, too.
The people need leadership
to return to the old values--
yours and mine.
l can think
of no one more worthy
of being the next Kai
than you, Winn.
l shall do everything
in my power
to see that you are.
The Prophets are smiling
on you today, Minister.
Dax?
l have Admiral Chekote
on subspace.
ln my office.
Commander, two assault vessels
are headed this way
on direct course from Bajor.
They've given all non-Bajorans
seven hours to evacuate.
Admiral, are you up-to-date
on my communiqués?
l think so, Commander.
How's it look?
Not good--
Jaro has the military
communications have been cut off
and assault vessels
are on their way here.
Are you preparing to withdraw?
Admiral, we've just
obtained evidence
that the Circle's
been receiving weapons
from the Cardassians.
lf we withdraw,
we'll be giving Bajor--
and the wormhole-- back to them.
Damn.
That's a hell of a turn.
How can these Bajorans
get in bed with the Cardassians?
They don't even know
the Cardassians are involved.
Then you're saying that it's
a genuine political revolution
internal to Bajor.
Supported by the Cardassians.
But internal to Bajor.
The Cardassians
might involve themselves
in other people's civil wars,
but we don't.
The Prime Directive applies,
Ben.
Admiral.
Would you say that our people
on the station are in danger?
Yes.
Then there's no other choice
but to evacuate.
We'll have to worry
about the long-term
political implications
down the road.
That's an order, Commander.
Chief, how long will it take us
to evacuate Deep Space 9?
l'd say we could have
all of our people
out and away in... three hours.
l mean a complete evacuation.
l intend to take all Starfleet
instruments, materiel...
in fact, all Federation
property of any kind.
How quickly can we do that?
Well, sir, that'll take days--
one week, for all l know--
but those assault vessels are
going to be here in seven hours.
Then, l guess some of us
won't quite be done
by the time they get here.