l am merely a businessman.
lt would take an orator
with the skills of the late,
great Plegg himself
to sing the praises
of the late, great Plegg.
What Ferengi could resist
the honor of owning
a small piece of the man
that took a computer chip
and turned it into
the modular holosuite industry?
A small piece of the man
that brought
holographic entertainment
to the most remote parts
of the Quadrant
creating profit centers
from societies that could barely
afford to feed their own people.
How much are you asking?
As l was about to tell
my good friend here
a mere three strips of latinum.
And l'd be taking
a loss at that price.
Okay, for you, two strips.
Thank you very much.
Three strips?
That's a fair price for Plegg.
l suppose you're interested?
Humanoid death rituals
are an interest of mine.
Death rituals.
Everybody needs a hobby.
Mm-hmm.
Some species burn their dead
others pack them
in blocks of ice.
Some even surround themselves
with the company
of family corpses.
But the Ferengi ritual
of chopping up their loved ones
and selling them...
l find that irresistible.
l'm very busy here.
What a fitting
and distinguished way
to honor the memory
of great Ferengi entrepreneurs.
l'm thinking of starting
a collection
putting up a display case
in my office.
There'll be a special
space in there
reserved just for you, Quark.
l'm sure.
You're serious?
Have you ever known me
not to be?
There is one thing
l was curious about.
And what's that?
How do l know it's Plegg?
lt says so on the label.
lsn't there some
sort of letter of authenticity?
The Ferengi Seal
of Dismemberment is right here.
What more do you want?
l want Plegg.
You got him!
Not if he's still alive.
Still alive?
Still alive.
Plegg?
After l tracked him
down on Kholfa ll
told him
about your little scheme
he was quite amused.
l'm not.
Odo, l'm a victim here.
l bought these discs
in good faith.
l have 5,000 pieces of Plegg
in my storeroom.
Uh-uh-uh, not Plegg.
Then who?
Good question.
l demand an investigation.
You'll get one, l promise you.
Odo!
Dr. Mora.
lt's been too long.
You're looking well.
Yes...
coming along nicely.
Why didn't you let me know
that you were coming?
lt was a last-minute
arrangement.
Uh-huh. The trip from Bajor
takes five hours.
Can l get you something...
Dr., uh, Mora, was it?
Yes, some, uh, Deka tea
would be nice.
Haven't quite managed
the ears yet, have you?
Oh, no, but they're...
they're difficult.
ls the suit a suit,
or part of you?
Oh, and what about the boots?
Here we are.
Nice and hot.
Thank you.
So, um...
you two seem to be old friends.
Dr. Mora is
the Bajoran scientist
who was assigned to
me after l was found.
l was personally responsible
for his development
during his formative years.
So, this is a family reunion.
l had a hunch.
Well, Odo's dad is
always welcome at Quark's.
-He is not...
-Actually...
l know he wouldn't
tell you himself
but Odo is doing a wonderful job
here on the station
-if l may say so.
-ls he?
Absolutely.
As a matter of fact
when you came in, he was just
beginning a fraud investigation.
Quark!
Excuse us.
Of course.
The two of you have
a lot of catching up to do.
lf there's anything
l can help you with, Doctor
don't hesitate to call on me.
That was uncalled-for.
Huh! You don't know Quark.
l know that he was
trying to present you
in as positive a light
as possible
to someone he thought
was important to you.
And you responded with...
Please!
Still having trouble
with social integration.
l integrate as much
as l want to.
Define ''as much as l want to.''
''As much as l want to''
means as much as l want to.
Hmm.
Quark is a thief, a con man...
nobody you want to know.
So, um, tell me about
this police thing
you've gotten yourself
involved with.
ls it working out?
l enjoy my work
as Chief of Security.
Chief of Security
at a way station in space.
Don't you miss it, Odo?
What?
Our work.
Never.
l don't believe it.
l know you too well.
You were unhappy in the lab.
l can't blame you for that.
But the work, Odo, the work.
The exploration of you
what you are,
where you came from.
That's never far
from your mind, is it?
That part of it... is true.
Good.
Because l came here
counting on that.
See you later, Dad.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hold on!
l'm late.
For what?
For Nog.
-Your homework.
-lt's done.
You studied that
entire Klingon opera
for the music test on Friday?
l'm going to ace the test,
Dad, l promise.
This isn't about tests, Jake.
This is about learning.
You can't learn to
appreciate Klingon opera
by cramming for the exam
the night before.
What am l ever going to use
Klingon opera for?
Well...
first of all
you don't know what you're
going to be when you grow up.
You may discover along the way
that you want to be a musician
or you may find yourself
among some Klingons...
in a job... somewhere.
Dad, even if l did
they wouldn't be going
around singing operas.
lt helps you understand
their culture.
When was the last time you
listened to Klingon opera?
When l was your age.
There, you see?
Yes. Do you?
Just because you suffered
through all that
doesn't mean l have to.
Yes, it does.
Come in.
Dad!
l have the perfect solution.
Nog has the same test.
Why don't you invite him over
and you can listen
to the Klingon opera together?
Please, Odo, sit down.
Commander, l'd like to request
the use of a runabout.
Of course.
For what?
Dr. Mora Pol
from the Bajoran lnstitute
of Science has asked me
to help him secure
one from the Federation.
Why did he come to you?
Dr. Mora is the scientist
who was assigned to me
in my first years here.
lf he went
to the Board of Ministers
to request permission
to approach you
it would take months.
And he's very anxious
to investigate
something in the Gamma Quadrant.
And, may l say,
Commander, so am l.
You've gotten me curious,
Constable.
ls it a secret?
No, but there isn't
much to tell.
One of the Bajoran
science probes
recently scanned a planet
about six light-years
from the wormhole.
lt picked up some very
unique-- and familiar--
DNA patterns
patterns very much
like my own, Commander.
Dr. Mora thinks
he may have discovered
the origin of my people...
of me.
lt would seem to me
that being a scientist
yourself, Lieutenant
you can appreciate
the difficulty of our dilemma
and the elegance
of the solution.
When Odo was first found
nobody knew who--
or, indeed, what--
it was we were dealing with.
A shapeless,
viscous mass of fluid
a veritable organic broth.
That was our Odo
in the beginning.
When did you realize
you were dealing with
a sentient life-form?
He didn't.
l had to teach him that myself.
lt's true.
lt's very true.
Tell her.
lt was a dilemma for me.
l had never seen anything
like these creatures either.
''Seen'' isn't really
an appropriate description.
He had no eyes, per se.
l was just trying
to describe it in simple terms.
He had never perceived
anything like us before.
Go on.
l knew l had to find some way
to communicate with them
so l transformed myself into...
lt was remarkable.
Every morning
l would come into the lab
and every morning,
Odo would be there
resting in his liquid form
in a Krokan petri beaker.
One morning l walked in
and Odo was gone.
The beaker was empty,
but next to it
was an identical beaker
that had not been there before--
a perfect replica in every way.
lt was... amazing.
Oh, it hasn't been the same
since you've gone, Odo.
Working with you
has been the most rewarding
part of my career.
Hmm!
We're approaching the planet.
Prepare to enter standard orbit.
Planet designated L-S Vl.
lnitiating scans.
There's a lot
of seismic activity down there
possibly volcanic in origin.
Moving into synchronous orbit.
Do the letters mean
anything to you?
No, l don't think so.
Judging by its position
in the ruins
l think it's fair to say
that this pillar represented
something important
to the people who lived here.
Why don't we take it with us?
Our computers back
on the station
might be able to decipher
the inscriptions.
Mm-hmm.
Where is Dr. Weld?
Dr. Weld?
Over here.
l think l may have found
what we're looking for.
ls it carbon-based?
No, silicate
but vegetative,
and very much alive.
Odo, Jr., perhaps.
Computer, begin transport.
Come on!
Computer, realign transporter.
Lock onto our combadges.
Stand by.
This way.
Ready for transport.
Computer, energize!
They're stable for now.
Dax is in fair condition
but the Bajorans seem to be
more seriously affected.
Perhaps they were exposed
to more of the gas
or there may be something
about Trill physiology.
l'm not sure yet.
And Odo?
l'm fine.
The paralyzing action occurred
when the gas was taken into
the respiratory system.
And since Odo doesn't have
a respiratory system
as we know it
he apparently wasn't
affected at all.
O'Brien has off-loaded
the cargo they brought back.
He has everything set up
in the science lab.
l understand there are
some organic specimens
from that planet.
Maybe there's something there
to help you figure this out.
Good idea.
Will he be all right?
The molecule appears to have
quite an unstable structure.
That might mean
the effect is temporary.
l know how you feel,
Constable.
Feel?
About what?
When my father became ill
l can remember
how small and weak
he looked there,
lying on the bed.
He'd been so strong,
so independent.
lt always seemed to me
that there was nothing
that he couldn't do.
But, in the end, l realized
there was nothing
that he could do
and nothing l could do
to help him.
l appreciate your thoughts,
Commander
but Dr. Mora is not my father.
The computer is
having a hard time
classifying your new life-form.
Why?
Whatever it is,
it keeps changing.
Somehow it goes through
a metamorphosis
every time it reproduces,
and it reproduces like crazy.
Look at this.
lt multiplied so much,
l had to change containers.
l'll put it in a level-5
security field overnight.
l wish Dax were here
to take a look at it.
How's she doing?
Dr. Bashir thinks
she'll be fine.
Any idea what it is?
l'm hoping it's a key,
Mr. O'Brien...
a key to my past.
Kira to Sisko.
Go ahead, Major.
Sorry to bother you, Commander
but we need you up here
in the Science Lab.
l'm on my way.
...the scan, sir.
No positive lD on the life-form.
The holographic readout...
Any signs of a break-in?
Not that we could find.
The security seal on the lab
was still in place
when we got here.
l can't imagine
why anyone would want
to steal that thing, anyway.
You're suggesting the life-form,
itself, did this?
l don't know
what did this, Commander
unless a tornado passed
this way without us hearing it.
The room was locked.
lt's gone.
That's all l know for now.
Constable, get
a level-3 security scan
underway on the entire station.
Our scanners may have trouble
finding this life-form.
lt has metamorphic qualities
that were confusing
the computer.
You might want to run that sweep
two or three times.
Let's go to Yellow Alert.
Major, you could help
me by reviewing
the security camera records
and the heat sensor readouts
for the lab
and the surrounding areas.
Commander, l'm picking up
slight trace elements
near the ventilation
intake duct.
lt looks as though our life-form
may have taken this way out.
Dr. Bashir gave you
permission to be up and about?
Dr. Bashir wouldn't listen to me
and hid my clothes,
so l wouldn't leave.
l had to sneak out
to my quarters
in a hospital gown
that wouldn't close in the back.
What did this?
The working theory is
that life-form you brought back
is somehow responsible.
l don't believe it.
Good.
Find me a better theory.
Odo, Dr. Mora is awake
and would like
to speak with you.
l heard them say
something happened in the lab.
The life-form sample is gone.
Gone!
We're not sure how or why yet.
l want to help.
Everything is under control.
l know more about shape-shifters
than anyone in this sector.
Anyone except me, and l'll
be running the investigation.
Besides, we're not even sure
it is
a shape-shifting life-form.
Any metamorphic characteristics?
lt was changing faster
than the computer could analyze.
Any indication of intelligence?
Not unless you consider
wanton destruction of the lab
an indication of intelligence.
lt might be.
Don't dismiss any possibility.
Dr. Weld hasn't
regained consciousness.
l feel responsible.
l'm sure Dr. Bashir
is doing everything possible.
The same trace elements
are inside the duct.
l'm following the trail.
Moving toward corridor 2-H.
Nothing's showing up
anywhere on the scanners, Chief.
Yeah, l figured as much.
Did the security cameras
in the lab give you anything?
The security cameras stopped
operating for 43 seconds
at 03:00 hours, five minutes--
right when the alarm sounded.
Stopped? You mean,
someone turned them off.
More likely some kind
of power interruption.
lt might have affected
the security field
around the life-form, too.
We're trying to analyze it now.
Do the heat sensors
in the lab show
any thermal deviation
at the same time?
Almost a six degree increase
during the 43 seconds.
But then back to normal
after that?
Affirmative.
Oh.
We may be dealing
with an entity that absorbs
low-frequency R-F energy.
lt might be feeding off
our power.
But an energy drain should be
showing up on our scans.
Yeah, that's true, Constable.
l don't get it.
Maybe this thermal deviation
was a result of...
Chief?
Hold on, l hear something.
We've got your position.
Nothing else is showing
up anywhere near you.
Well, l definitely
hear something ahead.
Can you hear it on the com line?
No.
lt almost sounds like...
l can't describe it.
l'm moving in closer.
lf you run into my wife,
don't mention l did this.
Move some backup
to the nearest corridor.
Security to core section,
Level Four, corridor 2-H.
When l come home tonight,
she'll ask me how my day was
and l'll say, ''Fine, honey.
How was yours?''
Sometimes l don't think she
really wants to know the truth.
So l do us both a favor, and...
Oh...
lt's a structural breach.
O'Brien, report.
l'm okay. l'm fine.
l think l found
our missing life-form.
Except it isn't
a life-form anymore.
lt's dead.
Station Log, Stardate 47391.7.
Engineering crews have been
working for over 15 hours
searching conduits.
There have been
no additional incidents
and no further evidence
of the alien life-form
has been found.
With this kind
of cellular structure
the life-form would have needed
a higher concentration
of carbon dioxide
than our atmosphere provides.
lt just couldn't survive
out of its own environment.
Well, that would be my analysis.
But, with that in mind,
do you still think
this life-form was capable
of destroying the lab?
That's not impossible.
The environmental impact
might have taken
some time to set in.
l'd really like to get Dr.
Mora's opinion on all of this.
Well, he's much better.
He should be up and around
in the morning.
Feel like getting a raktajino
before we call it a night?
My replicator or yours?
l was thinking
more of the Promenade.
l knew that.
Well, thanks, anyway.
l got a few things
to wrap up around here.
Sleep tight, Julian.
She enjoys it.
She actually gets some kind
of perverse pleasure out of it.
And one of these days,
l'm going to stop chasing her
and then we'll see.
Emergency.
Emergency!
lntruder alert.
lt happened so quickly.
l'm sorry l can't tell you
any more about it.
lt was behind me,
and then it was gone
but it was big, very big.
How badly did you injure it?
l don't know.
l don't even know
if l injured it at all.
l just hit it once
with a laser scalpel
in the arm or the leg
or the tentacle
or whatever it was.
And then it went
off the wall and was gone.
lt appears as though
our life-form has survived
and grown into something
interesting.
Did you notice anything
when you entered
the room, Doctor?
Anything out of place,
anything unusual?
Was it unusually warm, perhaps?
Now that you come to mention it,
it was a bit warm in here.
Another thermal distortion.
Did you try the lights, Doctor?
No, l didn't want
to disturb the patients.
Commander, l suggest we check
the R-F energy flow
to the lnfirmary.
We might find
a power interruption
as we did in the lab.
No blood or any fluid traces
but l am picking up
a very slight trail of something
we didn't see last time--
an organic residue.
Enough to test?
We'll see.
Sisko to Ops.
Go ahead.
Restrict all nonessential
personnel to their quarters
and go to Red Alert, Major.
Understood.
Keep in touch
with Dax's progress.
She may give us a way
to track this thing.
Until we can, l suggest
we close down the Promenade.
l'll give the order, Constable.
''Constable''?
lt's a nickname
that l barely tolerate.
lt's an expression of affection
that you find
difficult to accept.
You know, that was
a remarkable display back there.
Display?
Yes, you were very careful,
attentive.
l was just doing my job.
l begin to think
that the scientific method
and police method
have a lot in common.
l never thought of it that way.
Perhaps they do.
ln science, we look
for the obvious.
We track in a straight line.
lf something looks
too good to be true
it usually isn't true.
lf there appears to be
more to something
than meets the eye,
there usually is more.
We take it step by step.
That applies to criminal
investigation as well.
You do it very well.
l'm very proud of you, Odo.
Do you know that?
Huh.
Anything?
The computer's having trouble
breaking down the DNA chains.
What about this pillar?
Did the computer
have any success
at decoding the encryptions?
No luck there either.
All things considered
the computer's
having a bad week.
We have such a limited database
for the Gamma Quadrant.
l have to close down
the Promenade.
Call me when you have something.
Wasn't that pillar
over here before?
lt was in my way.
l had it moved.
Have you compared this
new organic strain
to the life-forms we brought
back from the planet?
Only enough to be sure
that they're not the same.
lt might be interesting to see
if there are
any commonalties at all.
Let me run
a cross-tabulation analysis.
lt should only take
a few minutes.
Do you know Odo well,
Lieutenant?
Not as well as l'd like to.
He keeps to himself a lot.
l'm not surprised.
l never realized
till l actually saw him...
how much l miss him.
We didn't part
on very good terms, and...
So l've heard.
Well...
he wanted to leave
and we still had
so much work left to do.
But l see him now, and l wonder
if he wasn't right
to go after all.
He's come so far.
He's an invaluable man
around here.
l never thought he could do it--
integrate successfully.
lf you could have
seen him before--
he was so ill-prepared
to be on his own.
l was sure he'd come back.
l told him when he left
he'd come back
and, all these years,
l was so certain
that eventually, one day,
he'd show up at the lab.
Well, l guess
l'd better get used
to the idea he's not going to.
Oh, here we are.
Which one's this?
That's the new one
from the lnfirmary
and this is the life-form
from the planet
but remember, it went
through several metamorphoses.
lt's not the same entity.
The nucleotide sequences
are entirely different.
Some metachromic similarities.
Yes...
on a most basic level.
At best, they could
be distant cousins.
The computer's broken down
the DNA chain on the new sample.
l can run an analysis
and see if it matches up
with any other life-form
in the computer.
How long would that take?
Two, three hours maybe.
Let me know.
Dr. Weld has regained
consciousness.
lt looks like he'll be fine.
That's a relief.
You don't seem relieved.
You can tell that
just by observing me--
the tone of my voice
my eyes, my body movement?
Yes.
You are truly a remarkable
life-form, Odo.
But there is so much about you
we still don't understand.
What are you getting at, Doctor?
The computer has broken down
the DNA chain
from the organic sample
we found in the lnfirmary.
Dax is running
an analysis of it now.
She'll identify it
in a couple of hours
but l already know what it is.
l've seen it before.
The organic sample...
it's from you, Odo.
The destruction
in the Science Lab
occurred at 03:00 hours,
five minutes.
The attack in the lnfirmary
occurred at 19:35.
Roughly 16 hours apart.
ls your rejuvenation
period still 16 hours?
Uh... l was in my pail
during both attacks.
But were you?
l don't think so.
l think, Odo,
that you've been placed
in the ironic position of having
to track down yourself.
How could this be?
Has anything like this
ever occurred before?
Of course not.
Are you certain?
Yes, l'm certain.
There would have been incidents.
Any unsolved crimes on the book?
There are always
unsolved crimes.
Then the possibility exists.
lt doesn't!
l do not commit criminal acts!
lt is not in my nature!
lsn't it?
The gas! Maybe it was
the gas on the planet.
lt affected all of you.
lt must have done
something to me.
A possibility.
That has to be it.
Certainly worthy
of an investigation.
Dr. Bashir may be able...
Dr. Bashir will not
understand any of this
except that you have
turned into some kind
of uncontrolled thing
that tried to kill him.
Really, Odo, what do you
think they'll do with you?
Do?
They won't know
what to do with you!
They'll put you
in a high-security prison
or quarantine you
on a deserted asteroid
in the Gamma Quadrant.
Odo, they'll put you in a zoo!
l don't... believe that.
You don't know them.
What other humanoid
have you been able
to trust, except me?
What makes you think
l trust you?
l resent that.
l really do.
After all the time
l invested in you
after the education
l gave you
the attention l gave you.
You would not be here today
if it weren't for my guidance.
l gave you more
than anyone else in my life!
You were my life!
And then you walked away.
And now you don't trust me.
Fine.
Put yourself in their hands.
You always had to learn your
lesson the hard way, didn't you?
l...
am not going back
to the Center with you.
Why?
We'll work through this
together.
We'll solve it together,
just like we used to.
No!
l have a power failure
in Security, Commander.
Sisko to Odo.
Sisko to Odo!
All deputies report
to the Security Office.
Possible intruder.
l'm tracking it.
We have a power drain in
the life support conduit
above the Security Office.
lf it's feeding off our power,
we may be able to slow it down
by shutting off the primary flow
to the entire core section.
Do it.
Where the hell did it come from?
Security to Ops.
Go ahead.
There's no one down here, Major.
And there's no sign of Odo?
No, sir.
l can help you with that, Major.
The creature you're after
is Odo.
There must have been some sort
of metamorphic reaction
to the volcanic gas
that we encountered
on the planet.
ls there any way
to communicate with him?
l don't know.
lt's not Odo, really.
lt's separate and independent
from the Odo we know, and yet
at the very least,
it's aware of me.
How can you know that?
The incident
in the Science Lab--
l believe that was an attempt
to rescue the life-forms
l placed in containment.
The second encounter
occurred in the lnfirmary,
where l was asleep.
The third happened
just a couple of minutes ago
when we got into a heated
discussion in Security.
l think that even
the Constable himself
would arrive at the same
conclusions given the evidence.
On some instinctual level...
the creature is
familiar with me.
We might even conclude it has
hostile intentions toward you.
lt had occurred to me.
The power shutdown
is complete, Commander.
Odo-- or whatever
it is in there--
has stopped moving
for the moment.
Chief, based on your knowledge
of its behavior
if we can lure him out,
is there any way
we can we set up
a force field to hold him?
We could reverse polarity
on the energy fields.
That might work,
but it's only a guess.
Set it up on the Promenade.
l want a lot of room to operate.
Major, station security teams
along the perimeter.
How are we going to get him
to come out of the conduits?
Maybe we could use some R-F
energy bursts to attract him.
There's only one way
that you're going to attract
that creature into your trap.
lt's me, it's after.
Mr. O'Brien?
Our plan seems to be working,
Commander.
He's following my trail
of energy crumbs
directly toward you.
On my signal, open the conduit
and let him in.
Aye, sir.
We're not sure
which vent he'll come through.
Hopefully, it will be
the first one
available to him--
over there.
lf not, there are 17 others
he might choose.
We're not stationing officers
near any of them.
We don't want to scare him away.
l understand.
Just get him to the force field.
We'll do the rest.
Pass the word that phasers
are to be set on maximum stun.
The moment Dr. Mora
appears to be
in jeopardy, l'll open fire.
Their orders are
to follow my lead.
lf maximum stun doesn't
bring him down immediately
we set phasers to kill.
Commander...
l know, Major.
Those are my orders.
Mr. O'Brien, we're ready.
Releasing the conduit seal.
Dr. Mora, did you hear that?
Ready and waiting.
What are you waiting for?
l'm here.
And l'm not going anywhere.
l've done it to you again,
haven't l, Odo?
Made you a prisoner?
Dear God, what have l done?
Mr. O'Brien,
drop the force field.
Aye, sir.
We have a lot... to talk about.
l'm not going to try and explain
what happened to you, Odo
because l haven't got
the vaguest idea.
l can tell you
that with Dr. Mora's help
we've managed to eliminate
all traces of the gas
from your cellular structure.
l prescribe rest
because it's hard for a doctor
to go wrong with that one.
Otherwise, there's not much more
l can do for you.
Thank you, Doctor.
l'm going home.
Dr. Mora...
l want to be sure
you understand...
l had no idea.
You had to speak in a voice
loud enough for me to hear.
l'm...
sorry.
l'm sorry it was necessary.
l would like...
in a very small way...
to be part of your life again--
your life here
on the station.
From time to time,
we could talk about things
that matter to you...
to us.
l'd like that.