l didn't kill him, you know.
A lot of people
believed it was me.
That shape-shifter thought so.
But he was wrong.
lt was a long time ago.
Say what you will
about the Cardassians
at least they could keep
the power on.
Would you like more ice?
l'm fine.
You were always very kind.
Was l?
You made life a little easier.
l ran a black market
for anyone who could pay.
Never exactly thought
of myself as ''kind.''
There was always
that little extra ginger tea
in that package you gave me,
wasn't there?
You didn't call me to Bajor
to talk about tea.
No.
l need a favor.
For old times' sake?
That's right.
l'm still as kind as ever.
l can pay you.
l'm listening.
My husband kept a strongbox
in our shop on the station
buried in the wall.
l want you to bring it to me.
What's in it?
Nothing anyone would value.
Anyone but you.
Sentimental reasons.
Why not take a sentimental
journey back to the station?
lf it's your property.
l couldn't stand
being back in that shop
where my husband was murdered.
Or maybe you'd rather not
let Odo see you there.
l'm sure he's forgotten
all about that by now.
Can you neutralize
the security system?
lt's behind the paneled wall
on the left as you enter.
Four panels in, five up.
Four in...
five up.
And l can pay you
five bars of latinum.
Five?
And, as always, my...
personal gratitude.
A day...
maybe two.
Commence Station Security Log,
Stardate 47282.5.
At the request
of Commander Sisko
l will hereafter
be recording a daily log
of law enforcement affairs.
The reason for this exercise
is beyond my comprehension
except perhaps that humans
have a compulsion
to keep records
and lists and files--
so many, in fact, that
they have to invent new ways
to store them microscopically.
Otherwise, their records would
overrun all known civilization.
My own very adequate memory not
being good enough for Starfleet
l am pleased to put my voice
to this official record
of this day.
Everything's under control.
End log.
Now, when we get
to the entrance
you stay flat against the wall.
Uh-huh.
lt's a pulsatel lockseal.
l can get it to release
in 25 seconds.
25 seconds?
But somebody will see us.
Let me do it.
You?
We'd be at it all night.
All night?
No, only about ten seconds.
How would you get
a pulsatel lockseal
to release in ten seconds?
You have one
on the storeroom door.
So?
Sometimes, when you forget
to leave me the desealer
l have to get
the storeroom open.
You've unsealed the storeroom
without my knowledge?
Only to serve
a customer's needs.
ln ten seconds?
You forget fairly often.
Ten seconds...
We'll see how you handle
the desealing rod.
That's all right,
l have my own.
What?
Nog made it for me.
Boy's always been
clever with his hands.
My storeroom...
Time this, brother.
You'll be very proud.
There, you see?
Thief! Don't deny it.
You've been stealing from me.
Brother, l never...
Tomorrow morning
l'm changing
my entire lock system.
Four in...
five up.
Here, it's behind this one.
Keep an eye on the Promenade,
while l burn off the panel.
The glare
could attract attention.
l have a better idea.
A better idea?
l took the liberty
of bringing along
a small vial of magnasite drops.
Magnasite drops?
What are magnasite drops?
A compound that will eat
through duranium.
One on each corner
and the panel will fall off.
How do you know that?
When you were
in the Gamma Quadrant overnight
we did very good business.
Naturally, l had to keep
your profits safe
but you had the only key
to the latinum floor vault.
You got
into my latinum floor vault?
With that?
l didn't want to tell you
because then you'd know
l burnt off your floor plates.
But l replaced them
out of my own salary, brother.
My vault...
Should l take it out for you?
Don't touch it!
Don't you touch anything
ever, ever again.
Just a piece of paper?
A treasure map, perhaps?
What does it mean, brother?
l have no idea.
Eight names,
all of them Bajoran.
l want to get
a picture of this list
before l reseal the box.
Go, get me an imager.
Go!
You can't be in here--
we're closed.
Well, if you really
want a drink...
She sent you, didn't she?
She knew you couldn't resist
opening it.
l'm sorry.
Yeah...
me, too.
Brother!
Brother?
Help!
Somebody, help!
My brother's been killed!
Ten cc's of cortolin.
l want an antigrav lift
in here, stat!
Ready the cortical stimulator.
What kind of weapon?
l am waiting for an answer!
Whatever it was had
to get by the scanners.
My best guess is a compressed
tetryon beam weapon.
Okay, okay, that's consistent
with what l'm seeing.
Get the stimulator over here.
Doctor?
Thoracic cavity rupture,
extensive neural trauma.
Now.
Rom says it was a robbery.
Was anything taken?
He says he doesn't know,
but he knows.
Security's stopping
everyone at the airlocks
but it took them five minutes
to get into position.
The assailant
may already be on a ship.
Delay all outgoing vessels
as long as you can.
Advise their respective
security details.
We've got to get him
to the surgery.
Help me get him up here.
l got him.
Easy now.
Slide him in.
All right.
Watch his head.
He's dying, isn't he?
He's dying.
What am l going to do
if my brother dies?
Do? Oh, you'll have a lot to do
once this place is yours.
But if he dies...
Mine?
''Wives serve, brothers inherit.''
Rule of Acquisition Number 139,
if l'm not mistaken.
l hadn't thought of that.
Really?
l had, because it's
a solid motive for murder.
Yes, actually.
l have heard of a few
untimely deaths that seemed...
Wait a minute.
You're not suggesting
that l...
l've had my eye on you
for a long time, Rom.
You're not as stupid
as you look.
l am, too.
l would never...
Constable, it's his own brother.
My own brother.
l hardly...
Stay out of this, Commander.
l know these Ferengi.
They'd sell their own flesh and
blood for a Cardassian groat.
Odo, he's a family friend.
His son is very close
to my boy.
Well, you'd better tell his son
that dad's going
to the lunar prison
on Meldrar l--
200 degrees in the shade.
l didn't!
lt's not true!
Oh...
lrony of ironies.
l finally get the bar
and l'm falsely accused
of my brother's murder.
Rom...
as a friend
if you know anything
that might be helpful
l think you should tell us.
lt was a list.
The man who shot my brother
stole a list.
What kind of list?
Of names...
eight Bajoran names.
lt was in this box
we... we found.
Found?
ln a manner of speaking.
My brother was hired by someone
on Bajor to retrieve it.
Who?
He didn't tell me.
He never told me anything.
l tried so hard
to earn Quark's trust.
Now he's dead, and l can
never earn his trust.
Just his share of the profits.
l swear l don't know
who hired him.
All l know is that the box
had been hidden years ago.
How many years ago?
l'm not sure... when
the Cardassians were here.
When the ship's store used
to be the chemist's shop.
The chemist's shop?
That's right.
Here? This is where
you found the box?
Behind a duranium wall panel.
l'll show you which one.
Do you want me to open it?
l can do it in ten seconds.
You asked to see me?
Yes... yes, please come in.
l'm Gul Dukat.
We've met before.
Have we?
l wouldn't expect you
to remember.
l was one of the guests
at the reception
at the Bajoran Center
for Science.
lt must have been two years ago.
Ah, yes...
when the Cardassian
High Command was invited to...
view me.
You were very amusing
that night.
Was l.
Yes... you did
a Cardassian neck trick.
Brought the house down.
The Bajoran scientist
who worked with me
thought you might
find it entertaining.
He made me practice
for weeks on the...
Cardassian neck trick.
Gul Hadar couldn't
stop talking about it.
He wanted to send you out
to entertain the troops.
l, on the other hand,
began to wonder
if you couldn't provide
a more valuable service
for the Cardassian Empire.
l've stayed informed
about you, Odo
ever since you walked out
on your Bajoran keepers.
l simply felt l could learn
more outside a laboratory.
Yes, you've become
quite the student
of humanoid nature,
haven't you?
Just what is it
you need, Gul Dukat?
Have you ever seen
a dead man before?
Yes.
ln your mines.
Oh, those are casualties.
This...
is murder.
And l've decided
you're going to investigate it.
Me?
Why me?
l'm no investigator.
Ah, but l suspect
you'd make a good one.
Shape-shifting your way into
places the rest of us can't go.
l have no intention
of being a Cardassian agent.
Not an agent.
An investigator.
There's a difference?
We can't have
these Bajorans running around
murdering each other,
now, can we?
l'm talking about order here,
justice.
There's very little justice
in the Cardassian
occupation of Bajor.
Don't push me, Odo.
My superiors would have me
''solve'' this murder
by rounding up ten Bajorans
at random and executing them.
l'm hoping you'll give me
a better alternative.
Now, these Bajorans
won't talk to us
but they seem to trust you.
l understand you used to
sort out petty disputes
concerning food, blankets,
everyday sorts of things.
They come to you.
l suppose l'm considered
a neutral observer.
Of course...
you're not one of them.
And for that,
you should be thankful.
So...
here's one more petty dispute.
Only this time...
l'm bringing it to you.
Find the murderer.
Are there any witnesses?
l'm sorry to keep you
waiting, Mrs. Vaatrik.
This is Odo.
He'll be investigating
your husband's death.
Perhaps you two
already know each other.
Have you been into the shop?
No, l don't use chemicals.
l've assigned this space to you.
We'll get you anything you need.
Madam, my sympathies.
Good hunting.
l'm sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
Do you...
have any idea
who might have done this?
l have a very good idea.
You do?
May l be honest with you?
That might be helpful.
My husband was having an affair.
Some girl showed up on the
station a couple of weeks ago.
He became infatuated with her,
l don't know.
Why are men like that?
Believe me, l have no idea.
We had two wonderful years
together...
until she arrived.
And now...
You loved him very much.
Of course l did.
Then perhaps you could
explain something
l don't understand.
What's that?
Mr. Vaatrik was found dead
two hours ago.
Mrs. Vaatrik hasn't shed a tear.
What makes you think...
By necessity,
l'm an observer, Mrs. Vaatrik.
When a humanoid cries
the epidermis below the eyes
swells noticeably.
Your epidermis is
perfectly normal.
l've been too angry to cry...
l, l... the shock...
Of course.
So...
you were about to accuse
this other woman of the murder,
l believe.
He confessed his indiscretion
to me days ago
but said it was over.
And when he broke
it off with her
she killed him
in a jealous rage.
Something like that.
Do you know her name?
No, but l can point her
out to you.
Move along.
Step back from the gate.
All of you.
That's enough.
Attention.
All bio-organic materials
must be disposed of
according to regulations.
When was the last time
you saw Mr. Vaatrik alive?
At dinner.
He went back to the shop
to do some inventory
work afterwards.
You don't live
in community quarters.
No, we were lucky enough
to be assigned a private room.
l guess because we ran the shop.
But at least we had
a little privacy.
Uh-huh.
There... that's her.
Odo!
We haven't picked up anyone
at the airlocks.
l can't hold up outbound
traffic any longer.
l'm sure he disposed
of the weapon before he left.
l heard about the list.
The one that Quark
got out of the wall.
Rom said it had been hidden
there during the occupation.
l couldn't help wondering
if it had something
to do with Vaatrik.
l've been wondering
the same thing.
Security Log, Stardate 47284.1.
ln this job, there is
no unfinished business.
This assault on Quark reopens
a five-year-old murder case
that l've never--
not for a moment-- closed.
Patience is a lost virtue
to most; to me, an ally.
l barely saw it!
l'm sorry.
l don't remember
any of the names.
All right, all right, let's...
just relax for a moment.
l really ought to be
getting back to my bar.
He's not dead yet, Rom.
They're not keeping him alive
by artificial means, are they?
My brother wouldn't want that.
No, he's clinging to life
all on his own.
Typical.
All right, let's try again.
Close your eyes.
Take a deep breath.
Clear your mind
of everything in it...
if there's anything there.
Breathe.
Now... what do you see?
The bar.
Yes?
With my name on it.
The past, Rom, not the future.
The box opens.
There's a piece
of paper inside it.
Yes! Yes, l see it.
Quark unfolds it.
Uh-huh.
There's a list of names,
Bajoran names.
Right.
The one at the very top
catches your eye.
And the first letter is...
''C!'' lt's a ''C!''
And the next letter is...
Oh... l...
Skip to the last letter
in the name, Rom.
''O!'' lt's an ''O!''
Starts with a ''C,''
ends with an ''O.''
And... and there's
a mark in the name.
An apostrophe.
Ches'so!
You're sure?
Yes!
Maybe.
Maybe?
lt's something like Ches'so...
l think.
Oh...
Call me day or night
if you remember something else.
Uh-huh.
Anything?
Ches'so.
Might be the first name
on the list.
Remember anyone from those days
on the station with that name?
No, but l wasn't here very long.
Hmm, so l recall.
We never talked about it.
We never had to.
l would have been executed.
You were innocent of the crime
l was investigating.
That wouldn't have mattered
to the Cardassians.
lt mattered to me.
Remember your passes.
You there, keep moving.
This way, this way.
Radiation workers
report to observation level.
Hi, Dad.
Hey, how are you?
Do you mind if l join you?
Sector Four salvage team
report at once
to your work stations.
A pretty girl like you
shouldn't be eating alone.
l don't do
whatever it is you want--
not for money, not for food.
No, you misunderstand...
l'm sorry.
Of course, l can see
how you could.
Let me start over.
You some kind
of security officer?
How did you know that?
You are, aren't you?
Unofficially,
l suppose that's true.
Unofficially-- what's
that supposed to mean?
Gul Dukat asked me
to investigate the murder
of a Bajoran man named Vaatrik.
l understand you knew him.
Who says l did?
His widow.
l suppose she also
told you l killed him.
Did you?
No.
On the contrary,
you were in love with him.
No.
But... he was
in love with you.
No.
Doesn't sound
like much of a romance.
We weren't having a romance.
Then why would he tell his wife
that you were?
You'll have to ask him.
lf you were having an affair
l promise you,
l'll find out about it.
All you're going to find
is that l've been here
for two weeks.
l met the man
right after l arrived.
He had Pyrellian ginger tea.
How he managed to get it,
l don't know
but l happen to like ginger tea.
We became friends.
Maybe he was attracted to me.
lt never went anywhere.
Why do you think
Dukat wanted you
on this investigation?
l'm sure he had good reasons.
Why not his own security people?
No Bajoran would talk to them.
That never stopped
the Cardassians before.
They have ways of getting
their information.
Something to think about.
Where were you last night?
l was at the bar.
l heard the Ferengi are allowed
to hire some Bajorans
for dog work.
lt's better than the mines.
You haven't spent any time
in the mines.
How do you know?
Your hands.
You're not bad at this.
You're right, my last job was
at a replicator plant on Bajor.
You're not allowed
to quit those jobs.
What happened?
l hit a supervisor...
for trying...
what l thought you were trying
a few minutes ago.
Oh, well, l appreciate
your restraint this time.
You're not planning on leaving
the station soon?
lf l were, would you have
the Cardassians stop me?
Yes.
Then, l'm not planning
on leaving the station soon.
Let me tell you something.
''Unofficially'' or not, you're
working for the Cardassians.
Sooner or later, you're going
to have to choose
whose side you're on.
l don't choose sides.
Everyone has to choose sides,
Constable.
l don't know
what you're talking about.
You knew nothing about a list?
Nothing.
Why would your husband have
hidden a list of Bajoran names?
l can't imagine why.
Are you sure it was his?
No.
Maybe the Cardassians
put it there
before they left.
Someone on Bajor told Quark
where to find it.
l wish l could help.
l sort of liked
that little Ferengi.
Well, don't write
his eulogy yet.
He's still with us.
l thought you said...
He was shot
at point-blank range.
The Federation doctor
saved his life.
Good for him.
Does the name ''Ches'so''
mean anything to you?
l don't think so.
Who is it?
Oh, just someone
l'd like to talk to.
Thank you for seeing me.
lf this has anything to do
with my husband's murder
l want to be of help
in any way l can.
Oh, there was one other thing.
l understand your power
was recently terminated
for lack of payment.
That's right.
Yet, you were able
to transfer funds
to the power company
this morning.
l don't appreciate you looking
into my private affairs.
Just part
of a routine investigation.
lf you could tell me
where you got the money.
A loan from a friend.
Of course.
And your friend's name?
Odo, this really has nothing
to do with your investigation.
Good, then you won't
mind giving me the name.
l'm sorry,
my friend is married.
l won't drag him into this.
Security Log, supplemental.
The Ferengi holds on to life
like it's gold-pressed latinum.
Maybe he just doesn't want
his brother to get the bar.
Or maybe he knows he's
the only real witness l have.
The next several hours
will tell the whole story.
We've done everything
we can for him.
l'll keep you updated.
l've got some good news
and some bad news.
l think l found our Ches'so.
Who is he?
A Bajoran mining engineer.
He's been very active
in charity work
for the war orphans.
What makes you think
he's our man?
Some connections from my past
suggested he might be.
His work brought him
to the station a lot.
The bad news is, he's dead.
Drowned in a pond
on his property last night.
l'm responsible.
How?
l mentioned the name ''Ches'so''
to the Vaatrik woman.
lf she recognized it
as ''Ches'sarro''
and thought that he might
lead us to her...
Security to the lnfirmary.
Acknowledged.
Major, l need some help.
Advise the medical examiner
that l want a complete
autopsy on Ches'sarro.
And that his death
is to be treated
as a suspected homicide.
l'll need
the communication records
for the Vaatrik home
for the past 52 hours.
And have the central bank
keep a supervisor
on duty all night.
l'll need several
bank records, as well.
Whose?
l don't know yet.
l want round-the-clock
armed security on Quark.
No visitors.
Yes, sir.
Stop by one of the holosuites.
Two programs
for the price of one.
l'm looking for the proprietor
of this establishment.
Does he owe you money?
No.
Are you here to arrest him?
Then you've found him.
Quark, at your service.
First drink on the house.
An old, dreadful
Cardassian tradition.
What'll you have?
l don't drink.
A soft drink, then.
l guess that's why we don't
see you around here much.
l'd like to ask you
a few questions
about the death
of the Bajoran chemist.
Wait a minute.
You're the shape-shifter.
You're the one
who's working for Dukat.
l'm not working for Dukat.
l'm just trying
to solve a murder.
No, l've heard about you.
You do some
Cardassian neck trick.
Am l right?
Not anymore.
That could go over big
in this room.
l'm checking on the alibi
of a young Bajoran woman
red hair, named Kira Nerys.
She says she was here
last night.
Yeah, l remember her.
She wanted a job.
How long was she here?
Long enough.
Long enough for what?
Oh, you know.
No, l don't.
Why don't you tell me?
She was showing me
her... initiative.
ls that some sort
of sexual reference?
These jobs are hard to come by.
Her credentials
were, um, very impressive.
Hey, listen!
Listen here,
what's the problem?
The problem is, you're lying.
You got me all wrong.
l want the truth.
Otherwise, l'll just
turn you over to Dukat
and he can get it for me.
Okay, fine, l didn't realize
we were dealing
with a murder here.
She didn't pay me enough
for that anyway.
She paid you for an alibi?
l wonder how Gul Dukat
will react when l tell
him about that?
l'm sure it'll cost me
a case of Cardassian ale.
Two cases at the very least.
A broken alibi?
That sounds like progress.
ls there someone
you want me to arrest?
Not yet.
But soon.
l need a name, Odo.
You'll get your name
when l'm certain
it's the right name.
Listen to the way
he speaks to me, Quark.
You're not afraid of anyone,
are you, shape-shifter?
Not even me.
l was right about you.
You are the man for this job.
Listen, l feel you and l...
we've gotten off
to a bad start here.
Let me make it up to you.
You need anything?
A little ginger tea?
No, you don't drink.
Um... chocolate?
Maybe, uh, companionship?
You look like you just lost
your best friend, Constable.
ls Quark, uh...
Quark is stable.
What's this?
The list.
You found it?
No, l assembled it
from the Vaatrik woman's
communication records.
She's been talking to each
of these people a lot.
Odd thing is, she had never
talked to any of them
until two days ago.
When the list was stolen.
lnterestingly,
every one of them
has transferred exactly
100,000 Bajoran litas
into her bank account
within the last 26 hours.
Blackmail?
Blackmail.
What did they have to hide?
For one thing, that they'd
come out of the occupation
with that kind of money.
You think they were working
with the Cardassians.
Selling out their own world
for a profit.
Collaborators.
Not even a Ferengi
would do that.
lt explains a lot of things.
Do you have enough
to charge her?
Not yet
but l'd like to bring her
in for questioning.
With your permission
l'll ask the Bajoran authorities
to transport her here.
Nobody ever had to teach me
the ''justice trick.''
That's something
l've always known.
A racial memory
from my species, l guess.
lt's really the only clue l have
to what kind of people they are.
Are these kinds of thoughts
appropriate for a Starfleet log?
l don't care.
There's no room in justice
for loyalty
or friendship or love.
Justice, as the humans
like to say, is blind.
l used to believe that.
l'm not sure l can anymore.
Yes, l lied about my alibi.
That doesn't make me a killer.
Where were you
when he was murdered?
Asleep, alone.
No one saw you
in the community quarters?
l wasn't there.
l found a small corner and...
You're lying.
l...
Don't bother.
Your whole face changes.
l should have seen it before.
You don't lie well.
Thanks.
So why don't you
start telling the truth?
Whose side are you going
to be on, Constable?
l'm not going to play your game.
When l tell you the truth,
you'll have to choose.
No, no, that's why
l was given this job.
That's why all of you
always come to me with problems.
l'm the outsider.
l'm on no one's side.
All l'm interested
in is justice.
lf you're innocent,
you'll go free.
lf not, l'll turn you over
to Cardassian authorities.
That's the only choice here.
l didn't kill him.
When he was killed,
l was on Level 21.
21? Ore processing?
Check the Cardassian
security logs.
You'll see a breach
on 21 last night.
l'm in the Bajoran underground.
l came here to commit
acts of sabotage
against the Cardassians.
Last night, l succeeded.
The ore processor was damaged
by a sub-nucleonic device
at 2500 hours last night.
lt'll be out of operation
for two weeks.
Give the mine workers
a little time off at least.
l'll describe the device l used
if you still don't believe me.
That's why you needed
an alibi from Quark.
lf you tell the Cardassians
the truth
none of this will matter.
l'll be executed
for the sabotage.
Who cares about Bajorans
killing Bajorans
when you can hang a rebel?
ls this her?
l told you
when l have the name...
ls this her?
No.
You can go.
lf you're lying,
shape-shifter...
lf you know as much about me
as you say you do, Gul Dukat
you know l don't lie.
l am convinced
that she did not kill Vaatrik.
ls it too late for visitors?
l'm sorry, sir.
No visitors are permitted here.
Then perhaps you could just
put these in water for him?
Of course...
Odo to Bashir.
Report to the lnfirmary
immediately.
On my way.
lt's over, Rom.
Over!
You're a hero.
l am?
You saved your brother's life.
l've never seen him before
in my life.
Really?
Your communication records
indicate
that you made several
calls to his home
and received several as well.
You also transferred
a large sum of money
into his account two days ago.
l want to confer
with my advocate.
Certainly.
l'll make arrangements
for you to speak with him.
Meantime, the two of you
can introduce yourselves
to one another.
l don't care what you think
you know, shape-shifter.
You will never be able to prove
that l killed my husband
because l didn't.
l know.
When did you realize?
The possibility occurred to me
when you got the name
Ches'sarro so quickly.
Your friends
from the underground
must have already suspected him
of being a collaborator.
Once l knew the eight names
were a list of collaborators
the murder of Vaatrik
made sense for the first time.
He must have been
a collaborator, too.
He had the money for ginger tea.
He had the private quarters.
l never had a motive
for his murder until now.
He kept his wife
in relative luxury.
She surely
wouldn't have killed him.
So who would kill
a Cardassian collaborator?
Someone in the Bajoran
underground, of course.
A colleague of mine
was given the job
of sabotaging the ore processor.
Vaatrik was my responsibility.
You were here to execute him.
No.
l was here to find the list.
The names of the Bajorans
who were selling us out.
We'd been informed that Vaatrik
was their direct link to Dukat.
Ah...
That must have been why Dukat
chose me to investigate.
He had to stay as far away
from this incident as he could
so as not to endanger his
network of Bajoran sympathizers.
Obviously, l never found
the list.
But that's what l was
looking for in his shop
when Vaatrik walked in on me.
l didn't have a choice.
l misjudged you, Major.
You were a better liar
than l gave you credit for.
You were working
for the Cardassians.
l haven't been
for more than a year.
You've had all that time
to tell me the truth.
l tried to tell you
the truth a hundred times.
What you think of me...
matters a lot.
l was afraid...
That it might affect
our friendship?
Maybe it doesn't have to.
Will you ever be able
to trust me the same way again?