Can't you ever just let go?
Let go?
The place is almost deserted.
There hasn't been a ship in
for three days
and yet you sit there
like a Baneriam hawk
looking for prey.
This is your chance to relax.
l could set you up
with a terrific
holosuite program.
Thank you,
but l don't accept gifts
from the likes of you.
Who said anything about gifts?
You pay like everyone else.
l'm just trying to get
you into the tent.
l have no time for fantasies.
No imagination, huh?
A waste of time.
Too many people dream
of places they'll never go
wish for things
they'll never have
instead of paying
adequate attention
to their real lives.
l could create
a shape-shifter playmate
for you.
The two of you could,
uh... intermingle.
You're disgusting.
lt's a living.
You're not allowing
young Mr. Sisko
in your holosuites, l hope.
lt's not what you think.
lt better not be.
You see that thing on his hand?
lt's a baseball mitten.
Every afternoon,
the boy goes up to play.
His father brought a program
with famous players.
You ever hear of Tris Speaker
or Ted Williams or Buck Bokai?
Afraid not.
Neither did l
until l made it my business
to find out.
With all these humans coming now
the true entrepreneur
knows how to...
sniff the wind.
Try it.
Go ahead.
l have no sense of smell.
You don't need one
to detect the scent
of op-por-tunity.
Opportunity.
Family entertainment.
That's the future, Odo.
There's a fortune to be made.
Little holocreatures
running around.
Rides and games for the kiddies.
Ferengis standing
in every doorway
selling... useless souvenirs.
You're going to replace
all your sexual holoprograms
with family entertainment?
No, no.
No. l'm expanding.
l'm negotiating
to lease the space next door
so l can use
the same hologenerators.
Well, you're still disgusting.
Till the day l die.
l'm sure you're exaggerating.
You are constantly
in my thoughts.
l can't even...
That was two raktajinos,
extra strong.
l can't even concentrate.
You seemed to be
concentrating just fine
on the Junior Lieutenant
at the reception
for Captain Stadius.
She was a poor substitute
for you.
And the Betazoid envoy
who was here last week.
A... barely...
adequate substitute for you.
Julian, you are
a wonderful friend.
l enjoy the time
we spend together.
Stop.
You're driving a stake
through my heart.
Try a high-pitched sonic shower.
lt will make you feel better.
No, it won't.
l've already tried it.
Sorry l'm late.
l was having dinner with Julian.
How is our young doctor?
Young.
Anything going on?
We were just looking
at an unusual energy reading.
Elevated thoron emissions
in the plasma field.
We thought it might be
an environmental byproduct
created by the increased
traffic in this area.
lt could be.
Ships have always avoided
the Denorios Belt.
And we have no idea
how the presence
of so many warp
and impulse engines
might affect it.
The question is--
is this going
to cause us any problems?
We were hoping
you could tell us.
''...and the messenger
from the queen
''watched the little man as he
danced and sang and laughed.
''How he would soon have
the daughter he always wanted
because they would never guess
that his name was...?''
Rumpelstiltskin.
''Rumpelstiltskin.''
Right.
''And the next day
''when the little man
came and asked
'''Now, Mrs. Queen,
what is my name?'
''She said, at first, 'Well,
are you called, um... Jack?'
'''No,' he answered.
'''Are you called Harry?'
''And then she said,
'Then perhaps
'your name is...?'''
Rumpelstiltskin!
'''Rumpelstiltskin.'
''And, at the sound
of his own name
''the old man was so furious
''that he stamped his foot,
shaking the entire kingdom
''and he broke in two
and disappeared
''and the king and the queen
and their daughter
lived happily ever after.''
Good night, little one.
Sweet dreams.
l'm not tired.
Ah, ah, ah.
None of that.
Good night, sweetheart.
Now, then, shall l tuck you in
with a bedtime story, too?
Mmm! Only if you're
tucked in with me.
Mmm. Naturally.
Mommy?
What is it, honey?
He's in my room.
Who?
Rumpelstiltskin.
Sweetheart...
that was just make-believe.
Rumpelstiltskin
isn't real, okay?
All right.
l'll come in and check,
but then it's bedtime.
Why do we tell her stories
about evil dwarfs
that want to steal children?
Well, don't look so distraught.
l'm only here
to offer you my services
if you should need them.
Take her out of here.
What's wrong?
Miles, what...?
Please, just go.
A pity you're sending
the ladies away.
lt's as if all the life
just went out of the room.
O'Brien to Security.
Go ahead.
lntruder alert.
Send a team to my quarters
immediately.
On our way, Chief.
So where's the straw?
l assume you want gold
spun from straw.
What are you?
Well, surely you must know.
You were just telling
the little one all about me.
l know what you look like,
but you're not...
Ah! Don't say it.
l don't like the sound of it,
you know.
Rumpelstiltskin.
Now, you didn't think
that would make me break in two
and disappear, did you?
Not this time.
l learned my lesson
back in the kingdom.
l don't make deals
like that anymore.
Ah, the local constabularies.
Gents, show me
a small bit of courtesy
and l'll be very pleasant
but try and lay a hand on me
and you'll soon regret it.
Besides,
l'm much too fast for you.
And now, my good host
if gold is not your pleasure
tell me your needs
and l'll tell you my price.
O'Brien to Sisko.
Go ahead, Chief.
l need you in my quarters
on the double.
l'm on my way.
Dad, l've got to talk to you.
Now, Jake, l don't have time.
l'm...
Hello, Ben.
He followed me home
from the holosuite.
Mmm...
Jadzia!
Hello, Julian.
What are you doing here?
Watching you.
Waiting for you to wake up.
l'm awake.
ls something wrong?
Funny, l was about
to ask you the same question.
lt... it...
must be this Larosian virus
that's been going around.
How do you feel?
Wonderful.
Um...
Mmm...
No... no fever.
Uh... must be me.
Must be me.
Uh... must be
an allergic reaction
to the replicated antipasto
l had at lunch.
Perhaps...
l must be hallucinating.
Why are you fighting this?
Why am l fighting this?
Why... am l fighting this?
l have no good answer
to that question.
All senior officers
report to Ops immediately.
Okay.
l get it.
Very funny.
Did O'Brien put you up to this?
l don't know
what you're talking about.
''Senior officers to Ops.''
We all walk in
everybody has a good laugh
at my expense.
This is not a joke, Julian.
We'll see.
Ah. Good.
lt seems we have
a small mystery on our hands.
Lieutenant Jadzia Dax
and Dr. Julian Bashir
l'd like you
to meet Harmon Bokai
a baseball player from the
London Kings who's been dead
for 200 years.
Don't look at me.
l can't figure it out either.
And a medieval
fairy tale character
named Rumpelstiltskin.
Oh, fine.
Now everyone knows my name.
Until today, he only
existed in storybooks.
A pleasure, l'm... l'm sure.
Could this be related
to the increased
thoron emissions
in the plasma field?
Thoron emissions?
l think you'd better ask me,
Benjamin.
l was hitting a few to the boy.
He's really been moving well
under the ball lately, Ben.
We would have worked
on some baserunning
except, uh... well,
he was getting hungry
and l realized l was, too.
A hologram with an appetite?
Hologram?
On the contrary, Major.
He's quite real.
They all seem to be.
What the hell
they talking about, Ben?
You.
You're not actually Buck Bokai.
So how come
l'm wearing his uniform?
You're a holographic image
of Buck Bokai that l created
so Jake and l could
play ball with you.
But l remember.
l remember all the games.
All the opening days.
The homer
that won the '42 World Series.
The squeaker that went
under Eddie Newson's glove.
The day l broke
DiMaggio's consecutive streak.
l programmed it
into the computer--
all of it-- every statistic.
What foreign tongue
are they speaking?
This one didn't come out
of any holosuite.
But he did come out
of your imagination
just as Buck came out of Jake's.
His imagination?
Then, l must have come out
of your imagination, Julian.
Uh... not necessarily.
Well...
maybe.
How could this sort of thing
possibly happen?
A subspace disruption.
Maybe some kind
of dimensional shift.
l didn't see an anomaly
when l scanned the plasma field
but it could have been so small
the sensors missed it.
Julian, let's go
to your quarters.
Please.
l haven't got time for this.
Odo to Sisko.
Go ahead.
ls there something
you want to tell me?
l'm in no mood for games,
Constable.
What do you need?
Are the environmental controls
broken down?
lt's snowing on the Promenade.
Snowing?
We're looking at five
or six centimeters down here.
Bring in
all available security, Odo.
We're going to Yellow Alert.
What's going on?
lt seems we're letting
our imaginations run wild.
As soon as l have an
explanation, l'll give you one.
Sisko out.
Yellow Alert?
Against our own imaginations?
You have a better idea?
l think l've got something.
Look at the wave patterns
of the plasma field.
The wave fronts are converging
toward a single point.
The particle density rises
as you get closer to the center
but then it looks like it
just drops off completely.
You're right.
l'm not getting any particulate
readings from the core.
What does that mean?
Whatever falls in there
is just gone.
You were right.
lt is some kind
of subspace disruption.
l want a full analysis.
Chief,
get a class-4 probe ready.
Aye, sir.
ls there anything
l can do to help?
Odo to Ops.
Go ahead.
The snow's disappeared
but now there's a Gunji jackdaw
running loose around here.
Just try to keep things
under control, Odo.
We're working on it.
Understood.
Come along now.
Come along.
There we go.
Ladies and gentlemen
may l have your attention,
please?
Ladies and gentlemen
and all androgynous creatures
your attention, please.
As you may have noticed
we're experiencing
some difficulties.
l'm going to have to ask you all
to please refrain
from using your imaginations.
Just because you
don't have an imagination
don't ruin it
for the rest of us.
Let me guess.
Another clever Federation
experiment has gone awry
and you've turned
the whole station
into one vast holosuite.
The phenomenon is being
investigated as we speak.
Uh-huh.
Well, uh, tell them
to take their time.
l haven't had a chance
to show the ladies
my collection
of Tartaran landscapes yet.
l'm surprised
by your attitude, Quark.
Ah, yes.
Well, you simply don't have
the same appreciation for...
art as l do.
Dabo.
l'm surprised because every one
of your customers is winning.
What?
They're taking you
to the poorhouse.
Dabo. Another winner!
No.
No, that's not possible.
Let me through.
Lose. Lose...
One cross...
Two cross.
No! No!
You're outnumbered, Quark.
Pardon me.
l was afraid of this.
The proximity of the wormhole
is amplifying the rupture.
The proton counts
are going through the roof.
Dax to O'Brien.
How are you coming
with that probe, Chief?
l'll have
the subspace scanners programmed
in less than an hour.
Keep me informed.
Dax out.
l have the wave
intensity analysis.
Computer, scan all data files
for comparable wave
intensity patterns.
Stand by.
Jadzia...
l find this difficult to say
but l want you to know,
l would...
Julian, there's really
no need to apologize.
ln a way
l feel as if we've
invaded your privacy.
We all have fantasies and dreams
we keep to ourselves--
thoughts
that should remain private.
l'm glad you understand.
Of course l do.
l was a young man... once.
So we can put
all this behind us?
Of course.
Good.
The computer seems
to be having trouble
finding a match.
She really is submissive,
isn't she?
ls that how you want
me to be, Julian?
So submissive?
l am not submissive.
Am l?
Uh, no.
Um, uh...
well, l don't think so.
l'm just not the cold fish
you are.
Cold fish?
Now, l, uh, never said that.
lf you'd get down
off your high horse
you'd start
to appreciate Julian.
She has a sense of humor
as l've always imagined you do.
l could use one about now.
Come on, Lieutenant.
Stop denying all those
yearnings you feel.
Yearnings?
lf you don't
you'll never know
what you missed.
Pattern match found.
Just in the nick of time.
A similar subspace rupture
was reported
in the Hanoli system
in the mid-23rd century.
The Hanoli system.
l don't believe
l know where that is.
There's no reason you should.
When the rupture expanded,
the system was destroyed.
Station Log, Stardate 46853.2.
We have launched a probe
to study the subspace anomaly.
Meanwhile, more than half
the people aboard DS9
have reported manifestations
of their imagined thoughts.
All probe systems
are reading normal.
Calibrating sensors
for subspace.
Three minutes to coordinates.
Wave patterns should begin
fluctuating any time now.
There.
The probe is penetrating
the thoron field.
Two and a half minutes
to coordinates.
Ah, for simpler times, eh?
Go away.
l only want to help.
You're in the way.
A farmer from Derry
once tried to chase me off
until l saved his crops...
from locusts.
Two minutes to coordinates.
Thoron emissions are stable.
You know what l find
most intriguing
about you, my good host?
You're afraid.
Of me.
Look, figment
l'm not afraid of anybody,
least of all you.
90 seconds to coordinates.
Figment, am l?
A figment of my imagination,
that's all.
And yet, you can't deny
how this imagination of yours
empowers me, can you?
Empowers me in a way
that somehow terrifies you.
You should be getting
some primary data, Commander.
They're coming in now, Chief.
Stand by.
She is your firstborn,
isn't she?
30 seconds to coordinates.
Thoron emission
patterns unstable.
Probe hull temperature
dropping rapidly.
Ten seconds.
The probe's approaching
the perimeter of the anomaly.
That's strange.
What is it?
Negative readings
on all sensors.
We may be looking
at some sort of folded space.
Let's see
what the optical scanner
on the probe gives us.
lt's drawing in all the matter
from the surrounding space.
Benjamin, it's getting larger.
Feel like taking
a few ground balls?
Look, l tried to tell you
you're on a space station
in the 24th century.
The only ball field around
is a holographic simulation.
lt's not real,
and neither are you.
Oh, you see, l don't get it.
l can pinch myself
and it hurts
and l am here with you,
aren't l?
Right now you are,
but, in a minute, who knows?
l hope when we get this thing
figured out, you'll...
Disappear for good?
l hope so.
Oh, you do, huh?
Well, so let's just say
for a moment l don't.
So what am l supposed to do,
huh?
You got room on your team
for a switch-hitting
third baseman
with good power?
Good power from the left side.
Left side?
Ben, hey.
Hey, Ben.
What are you talking about?
l hit over 20 homers
right-handed
in each of my first three years
in the majors.
And never more
than ten after that.
That was because Old Crow
moved me to second in the order.
l wish l had more time for this.
Well, that was baseball's
epitaph, wasn't it?
Nobody seemed to have
time for us anymore.
You know, l could have
played five more years
if they hadn't killed the game.
You were the best
that ever played.
l know.
l've played with them all.
l've got work to do.
Hey, Ben.
lt really meant a lot to me--
how much you cared.
That day we won the World Series
there were only 300 people
in the stands.
301 in my version.
l heard you cheering.
Meant a lot to me.
l just thought
you should know, you know
in case l do finally disappear.
Ops.
We don't know any more
than when we started.
Why would mine create
a woman and then reject her?
Why would mine create a dwarf
that could terrify him?
We should abandon
the whole thing.
Not yet.
l made a connection with mine.
A curious one.
l sense a feeling from him--
an affection for this ballplayer
who died 200 years
before he was even born.
And how much longer
do you suggest
we devote to this?
As long as it takes.
lt ain't over till it's over.
Station Log, supplemental.
The subspace anomaly
continues to expand.
As of yet, we've been unable
to find a way to contain it.
As a precaution
we have diverted
all incoming ships
away from the station.
A Vulcan science mission
to the Hanoli rift
detonated a pulse wave torpedo
at the coordinates of the tear.
Five minutes after they did,
the rupture expanded radically.
They were wiped out
along with the entire
Hanoli system.
What happened
to the rupture after that?
lt's not still there?
lt reached a critical mass point
and imploded
and then disappeared
from normal space altogether.
Were there any reports
from the Vulcans
about hallucinations on board?
Anything similar
to what we're experiencing?
No, sir, but they were
only within range
of the anomaly for 12 hours.
And Vulcans don't have
the most active imaginations.
Were there
any explanations offered
for the initial cause
of the rupture?
Dozens, nothing confirmed.
But we do know
there were no wormholes
and very little starship
activity
in the area before it formed.
We've looked high and low
for some common ground--
something to give us a fix
on how to attack this thing
and frankly, sir,
as funny as it sounds
we think pulse wave torpedoes
may still be the best approach.
Wait a minute.
lf it didn't work
very well last time, why...
The Vulcans were using
a primitive device.
ln the past 200 years
we've developed far better ways
of controlling the flux density.
We should be able to contain
the internal reaction this time.
And if we can't, we destroy
the whole Bajoran system.
Major, the rupture
is already expanding.
We have to seal it
or it's going to destroy
this system anyway.
The smaller it is,
the better chance we have.
How long will it take to create
one of these torpedoes?
We could have one ready
by 2200 hours.
lf the rift expands at all
before imploding
we have to be prepared.
Route auxiliary power
to shields.
Major, l'd like for you
to coordinate evacuation
of the pylons.
Odo can help you.
Dismissed.
Kira to Odo.
What is it, Major?
l need you to do a security
sweep through the pylons.
We're going to evacuate them.
l'll get on it
as soon as possible.
l've got my hands full
right now.
Clear the way!
Get out of the corridor.
Let them through.
Clear the way now!
Kira to Ops.
Lower Pylon 1 is gone.
l need emergency...
Sisko to Kira.
Report.
Kira, can you read me?
Major Kira, report.
Disregard, Commander.
False alarm.
Kira out.
All personnel in Lower Pylon 1,
report to Outer Ring Airlock.
Prepare for evacuation.
Clear the way now.
Clear the way.
Please stay inside.
This isn't a show.
Odo!
You, get out of the way!
Odo! Odo!
Odo!
Thank goodness.
l want to report
two missing persons--
a blonde and a brunette.
Can't you see l'm busy?
Don't scare them.
One minute, they're whispering
sweet nothings in my ear.
The next minute,
the sweet nothings are gone.
Will you get off
the street, before...
Girls!
l've been looking
everywhere for you.
Don't ever do that to me again.
So, Odo, what have you
conjured up
during all this, hmm?
Me?
l should have guessed--
nothing at all.
l've spent all my time
chasing incarnations
of the Prophets
long-dead lovers,
Gunji jackdaws
blizzards, trollops...
Ah!
As l always said,
a man without any imagination.
Come along, my dears.
l'll show you what
a fertile imagination can do.
lmagination...
Computer, run a level-1
personnel sweep of all pylons.
Requested function will take
approximately three minutes.
Let me out of here!
Get the Nagus on subspace.
l want to talk to him,
and l mean now!
l'm not spending another minute
in this cell.
How did you get in there?
How did l get in here?
You put me in here.
Oh...
l guess l did, didn't l?
Yeah.
No imagination indeed. Ha!
Heads up, Jake.
So, what are you doing here?
l can't go.
l've got homework to do.
But you'd rather be
at the ballpark.
You don't understand.
lf l go to the holosuite
without finishing my homework
my dad'll kill me.
Kill you?
Yeah.
You really believe
he'd kill you?
l know he would.
Well, if that's true
why you still thinking
about going?
l'm trying not to.
But you're wondering
if you can get away with it,
aren't you?
Well?
l couldn't understand
the directions.
The computer accidentally erased
the instruction page.
You really expect me
to believe that?
No, l guess not.
l've really got homework to do.
l need to see you, Benjamin.
What do you have, Dax?
ln the last hour alone,
the rupture's expanded 27%.
The rate of expansion
is increasing.
Can we gain any time
by moving the station?
lf the rift collapses
the implosion would overtake us
almost immediately.
How soon can you
be ready, Chief?
l'm installing
pulse wave devices
in the torpedoes now,
Commander.
Six, seven minutes.
The rift's gotten large enough
to pick up on visual scanners.
On screen.
Magnify.
All pylons are secured.
Everyone's been moved
to the Habitat Ring
for the time being.
You're worried.
You bet l am.
lf this doesn't work
nothing real or imagined
is going to survive.
Hold me.
Please.
Torpedoes ready.
Status of shields?
All available power's
been transferred.
Reading shield strength
at 158% above normal.
Let's hope it's enough.
Red Alert.
Fire!
All systems functioning
properly.
Torpedo guidance
is on nominal track.
30 seconds to coordinates.
lmpulse sustainer
throttling down.
Arming pulse wave initiator.
Torpedo hull temperature
dropping.
Activating pulse waves.
Compression level at 1,400
and rising.
20 seconds.
Compression at 2,900.
3,000.
Terminal targeting spread
confirmed.
3,500.
Holding compression.
Ten seconds.
Ready to detonate.
Ready, sir.
Five seconds.
Now.
Wave intensity
from the rift is dropping.
The thoron field boundary
is shrinking.
Particle energy is rising.
Wait a minute.
What's this?
Wave emissions are fluctuating.
We're not getting
a controlled collapse.
Chief?
Damn it, we're picking up
an exothermic reaction pattern.
lt may be neutralizing
the pulse waves.
Stand by.
Perimeter sensors are picking up
a subspace oscillation.
What the hell does that mean?
Proton counts have tripled.
Residual pulse wave activity
from our torpedoes
is down to 14%.
The flux density readings
inside the rupture
are off the scale.
Odo to Ops!
Ops! Ops!
Com circuits are down.
l'll try to reroute pathways.
Life support is normal.
Shields.
A generator's down.
Section Four is exposed.
Odo to Ops.
There we go.
Constable, check for casualties.
Have your deputies move
everybody out of Section Four.
We have shield damage.
Acknowledged.
What are we getting
from the rift?
Sensors aren't operating.
Stand by, sir.
l can't feel my hands.
Lie still, lie still.
There's an emergency medical kit
in the cabinet there.
Get it.
l'm sorry...
Shh.
Here you go.
l never meant to bother you.
No, no.
You didn't bother me.
l can't keep my eyes open.
Don't close your eyes.
l want you awake.
You have a nasty concussion.
l can't help it.
Dax.
Dax!
Sensors are back on line.
The rupture is continuing
to widen... 340 times larger
than before.
ls it showing
any signs of collapsing?
Wave emissions from the rift
are still fluctuating.
l can't make any sense
out of these readings.
Proton counts are lower
than before.
And now
they're beginning to rise again.
The pulse waves
from our torpedoes
have been completely
neutralized.
lt's just a matter of time
before the rift
starts expanding again.
How much time?
Minutes.
Suggestions.
Run out of ideas, friend?
l have a suggestion.
Maybe l can help.
You?
You created me with powers
beyond those of mortal men
and l would be more than happy
to use them to assist you.
For a price.
l've always wanted a daughter.
Miles?
Perimeter sensors are picking up
subspace oscillations again.
You're telling me you can seal
that rupture out there?
l can spin straw into gold,
my friend.
This seems no more difficult.
Well, do it, damn it!
Will you meet my price?
This is crazy.
You're out of a storybook,
a fairy tale.
Are you willing to give her up
to save so many others?
No.
He doesn't have to.
Dax, when did our sensors
first pick up traces
of the rupture?
You were there, Benjamin.
When we were first
trying to figure
this whole thing out.
And if l remember correctly
you said
that your previous scans
hadn't picked up
any anomalies at all.
l thought whatever was out there
was too small for the scanners
to identify.
So you imagined
that we had a subspace rupture
and that's exactly
what it turned out to be.
That is what l imagined.
And once you'd learned
about the rift
that destroyed the Hanoli system
we all imagined that we might
have another just like it.
Mr. O'Brien, drop the shields.
Sir?
There is no rupture.
There is no threat
to this station, or this system.
End Red Alert
and drop the shields.
Aye, sir.
And believe it, Mr. O'Brien.
lt's important
that you believe it.
Aye, sir.
Are your sensors picking up
any magnetic shock waves, Major?
Yes, sir.
Perimeter readings still show...
No shock waves at all.
None at all.
Lieutenant, proton counts.
Normal.
lt's gone.
You're going to be fine.
Of course l am.
l have the best doctor
in the galaxy.
None of this makes any sense.
l mean, why did they appear
in the first place?
lt might still be related
to the elevated thoron emissions
in the plasma field.
The readings still
haven't returned to normal.
Continue your analysis, Dax
but, this time, no speculations
just facts.
Yes, Benjamin.
Major, keep us on Yellow Alert
for the next 26 hours
till we see that everything
is back to normal.
Chief, take your family home.
That's an order.
Aye, sir.
This imagination of yours--
it's a tough concept
for us to get a handle on, Ben.
You're not simply a figment
of my imagination, are you?
We're on an extended mission
exploring the galaxy.
A while back,
we followed one of your ships
through that hole in space
out there.
We've been watching you.
Trying to figure out
the rules of your game.
Why didn't you just
talk to us like this?
Well, we've learned
that you can never tell
how someone will treat
the visiting team.
l understand.
That's what this has been
all about--
learning to understand.
Was it really necessary
to put the whole station
in jeopardy?
But we didn't, Ben.
lt was you.
lt was your imaginations
that created everything.
We were just watching
to see where it took you.
Oh, this imagination of yours.
We have never seen
anything like it.
lt's very real to all of you
but yet it's not.
At first, it seemed to us
to be a curse
an irritation.
That Odo fellow
even called it a waste of time.
l disagree with him.
l knew you would.
l learned that about you.
That you could have
such an affection
for someone you never even met.
l wonder if you appreciate
how unique that imagination
of yours really is.
Not always.
We got to go.
But you haven't told us anything
about your species.
l'd like to.
Maybe next year.