Last time on Deep Space Nine...
A number of Admirals
at Starfleet Command are worried
the destruction of the Bok'nor
might jeopardize the treaty.
Oh, are they really?
As the two ranking officers
along the Cardassian border
we've been asked to assess
the potential risk.
l wish to procure weapons.
l beg your pardon?
Guns, phaser banks,
photon torpedoes...
-Shh.
-...troop transports
and a number
of cobalt-thorium devices.
You're a gun runner?
l'm here unofficially
to help you find out
the truth about the Bok'nor.
Why would you want to help me?
Because l already know
the truth.
l've got people out there
killing people, Major.
You suggest l turn
a blind eye to that?
They don't have a right
to defend themselves?
They've crossed the line!
lf Starfleet is unwilling
to defend their people...
They chose to live
with the Cardassians!
Well, l didn't!
But l lived with them
for 26 years
before the liberation came.
Every Bajoran lived with them
in constant fear.
l know what those colonists
are going through.
We just received
a general subspace transmission
from somewhere
in the Demilitarized Zone.
A group there is taking credit
for the kidnapping of Dukat.
They're calling themselves...
''the Maquis.''
l'm glad to see you had
no trouble finding us, Ben.
lt seems that one disaster
after another
keeps bringing us
back together again.
And now, for the conclusion.
You should have seen
the look on your face
when you saw me
standing there, Ben.
l hardly recognized you
without your uniform.
Well, it's been feeling
a little tight lately.
Just like that.
lt's just a uniform, Ben.
ls that all it is?
l remember
when you first put it on.
Yes-- graduation day
at the Academy.
We both swore
that we'd be starship captains
by the time we were 30.
And admirals by 40.
Yes.
l think we've both done
pretty well for ourselves.
Yes, we have, haven't we?
But now,
l've got something better.
These settlers, Ben--
if you saw all they
have accomplished
without any help
from the Federation
then you'd fight
along with them.
l don't think so.
They've traveled out here
to the back of the beyond
and built homes
out of the wilderness.
Now, maybe the Federation
can turn their backs on them
but l can't.
l'm not asking you to
but your joining the Maquis
isn't helping anyone.
Your actions have only
endangered the treaty
and put millions
of lives at risk.
The Federation believes
that it can solve
every problem with a treaty,
but out here, on the frontier
without the power of the
Federation to back them up
a treaty is only
a piece of paper.
Do you have evidence
that the Central Command
has violated the treaty?
Not yet, but we will.
lf you're depending
on Gul Dukat for proof,
you're going to be disappointed.
We'll find out, won't we?
l want him back, Cal.
He's not here.
Then where is he?
l never thought l'd see the day
when you'd side with a
Cardassian against me.
Damn it, Cal, l'm on your side.
You've got a funny way
of showing it, Ben.
l'm trying to stop you
from making
one of the biggest
mistakes of your life.
The Federation
believes in the treaty.
lf you destroy it,
Starfleet will come after you
and they won't be satisfied
until you're behind bars.
lf we work together
to end the violence...
The violence will never end
as long as Central Command
continues to smuggle weapons
to their colonies.
l wish there were a better way
to handle this thing.
l really do.
Nobody wants peace
any more than the Maquis.
And you're willing
to blow up Cardassian ships
to get it?
The Bok'nor will never
smuggle weapons again.
And its crew members
won't be returning home
to their families either.
Look, you say
the Central Command
is behind the smuggling.
Fine, let's prove it.
How?
We'll go to Cardassia,
find the evidence
you need to back up your claim
and when we do, we'll
take it to the Federation.
No, the Federation abandoned us.
Told us to take care
of ourselves.
Well, that's what we
intend to do, Ben
but you--
you could be invaluable to us.
Let us use your station.
For what?
A maintenance facility
for our ships.
l can't allow that.
Every week, innocent people
are murdered by the Cardassians.
l will not allow those deaths
to go unpunished.
You don't want peace, Cal.
You want revenge.
l prefer to call it retaliation.
l am sorry we won't be
working together, Benjamin.
lt would have been nice.
Like... old times.
Commander!
Sorry, Benjamin.
No!
Okay, let's go.
Knowing Ben's temper
when he wakes up,
we won't want to be here.
Come on, let's move out.
Come on, here we go.
Let's go, come on.
Lieutenant, l want to speak
with the Cardassian
Central Command.
Then you're in luck.
Legate Parn will be arriving
within the hour.
A Legate?
l feel honored.
While l'm waiting,
l want to speak with Starfleet.
Admiral Necheyev's already here.
Chief, the Maquis must have
transferred Dukat off their ship
before they reached
that asteroid.
l want to know
where they've hid him.
l can retrace their warp trail.
See if they met up
with any other ships.
Do it.
Admiral.
Commander, the Cardassian
Central Command
has gone on military alert
in response to the kidnapping
of Gul Dukat.
l'm not surprised.
This Security Chief of yours,
this shape-shifter...
-Odo.
Are you sure you
wouldn't be better off
with a Starfleet officer
heading your security team?
Admiral, l have complete faith
in Odo's ability to do his job.
lf you say so, Commander.
l do.
And as for Gul Dukat,
l assure you
we are taking all possible
steps to locate him.
Good. Keep me informed
of your progress.
l will.
But, Admiral
there is a bigger issue
here than rescuing Dukat.
And what is that?
The Maquis.
The Maquis are a bunch
of irresponsible hotheads.
These hotheads are responsible
for the bombing of the Bok'nor.
l'm aware of that, Commander.
We never should have allowed
those colonists to remain
on the Cardassian side
of the Demilitarized Zone.
Well, they're there, Admiral,
and they're not leaving.
What about Commander Hudson?
He's lived with these people.
What's his analysis
of the situation?
l'll... have to ask him.
You do that.
And Commander,
l want you to find the Maquis.
Talk to them.
Remind them
that they're citizens
of the Federation.
That it is imperative
that we preserve
the treaty with the Cardassians.
A treaty the Cardassians
may not be honoring.
Are you questioning
Federation policy, Commander?
All l know
is that the situation
in the Demilitarized Zone
is deteriorating rapidly.
Personally, l think you're
overstating the problem.
Establish a dialogue
with the Maquis.
They're still
Federation citizens.
l'm sure
they'll listen to reason.
Good luck, Commander.
''Establish a dialogue.''
What the hell does she think
l've been trying to do?
Commander.
Just because a group of people
belong to the Federation
that does not mean
that they are saints.
Excuse me.
Do you know
what the trouble is?!
No.
The trouble is Earth.
Really?
On Earth, there is no poverty,
no crime, no war.
You look out the window
of Starfleet headquarters
and you see paradise.
Well, it's easy to be a saint
in paradise,
but the Maquis do not live
in paradise.
Out there,
in the Demilitarized Zone
all the problems
haven't been solved yet.
Out there, there are no saints,
just people--
angry, scared, determined people
who are going to do
whatever it takes to survive
whether it meets with the
Federation's approval or not.
Makes sense to me.
Well, l'm glad
someone understands.
Legate Parn's ship just put in
at Docking Bay 5.
Maybe you'd like to give
the same speech to him.
l just might do that.
Odo to Sisko.
Go ahead, Constable.
l think you'd better
get down to Security.
l've caught one
of the Vulcan's accomplices.
l assure you, l had no idea
Sakonna was planning
to kidnap Gul Dukat.
Really?
Then perhaps you could explain
why the two of you
were spending
so much time together.
Surely it's no crime
keeping company
with a beautiful female.
You ought to try it, Odo.
lt might improve
your disposition.
Do you expect us to believe
that a Vulcan
would be interested in you
for your lobes?
Vulcans are a species
that appreciate good ears.
Commander,
this is very embarrassing
having to discuss my personal
life in such surroundings.
Embarrassment is going to be
the least of your problems
unless you tell me what kind
of business arrangement
you had with this woman.
All right, but first
l want to make it clear
that l was led astray
by Sakonna's feminine wiles.
Save the excuses, Quark.
Just tell us
what you were up to.
Sakonna was in the market
for certain items
which l was able to obtain.
At a considerable discount,
l might add.
What items?
We're waiting.
Let's see... where to begin?
She wanted
some deflector shields
navigational arrays
maybe a couple hundred
photon torpedoes...
Photon torpedoes!
And pulse cannons
and some high-energy disrupters.
Weapons! You sold weapons
to a terrorist group.
l did not.
The Pygorians
sold them the weapons.
l merely...
made some introductions.
Besides, l hadn't even heard
of the Maquis
until after Dukat was kidnapped.
l want a complete list
of every weapon she purchased.
Of course,
and if you need someone
to testify against Sakonna
in court
l'd be more than willing.
Would you?
ln a second, and let me know
if there's anyone else
who needs testifying against.
l'll tell you one thing,
Commander.
Sakonna was on a tight clock.
Whatever she needed
those weapons for
it's going to happen
within the next few days.
Just get me the list.
Sir, l assume
you'll be going out
to search for Dukat again.
As soon as O'Brien
tells us where to look.
As Chief of Security,
l'd like to go along.
l'll be happy to have you along.
And one other thing--
how long do l keep him here?
Forever.
Odo...
This isn't funny.
Odo!
This is Legate Parn.
He insisted
on seeing you immediately.
Because my business
here is crucial
it demands immediate attention.
And as a member of the
Cardassian Central Command
l must assure you, Commander
that what we have to discuss
is most crucial, indeed.
l understand.
l assure you
we are doing everything we can
to find Gul Dukat.
Please, Commander,
your efforts are appreciated
but unnecessary.
You see, Central Command
has learned that Gul Dukat
was the leader of a small group
of misguided officers
who were funneling
weapons to our colonies
in the Demilitarized Zone.
Then the Maquis were right.
The Cardassian settlers
are being supplied
by Central Command.
Dukat and the others
were operating entirely
without our knowledge.
Central Command would
never sanction anything
that would violate our treaty
with the Federation.
We've arrested
Dukat's coconspirators
and they shall be
dealt with accordingly.
Where does that leave Dukat?
With the Maquis,
where he belongs.
Are you saying
you don't want him back?
l assume the Maquis
will execute him for his crimes.
l wouldn't be surprised.
Well, then l don't see
what difference it makes
whether we do it
or they do it.
How do we know
they won't use Dukat's death
as an excuse to send troops
into the Demilitarized Zone?
l can assure you, Commander
that there shall
be no retaliation.
The Cardassians have no
desire to go to war again
with the Federation.
You have my word.
Your word.
Major.
l found our little
talk very enlightening.
l hoped you would.
Unfortunately, l have
some business to attend to
but l do hope
you'll take the time
to enjoy the station.
Thank you, Commander
but l, too,
must attend to my business.
Besides, l am afraid
this place has lost its charm
since the last time l was here.
l don't believe a word he said.
Neither do l.
But he did tell me something
that l needed to know.
Cal was right.
The Central Command
is smuggling weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone.
We just received a report
that three Federation settlers
were killed on Hakton Vll.
The Cardassians claim
it was in response
to the destruction
of the Bok'nor.
Which gives the Maquis
a new excuse to strike back.
Chief, what have you found?
Based on the residual
subspace distortion
of their warp drive,
l was able to plot the course
of the Maquis ship
that took Dukat.
As you can see,
long-range sensors
show no signs
of any other vessels
traveling along that route.
All right, they didn't transfer
him to another ship.
What about a planet?
lt's possible.
Their course took them
past five M-Class planets.
l've downloaded
their coordinates
into the Rio Grande's computer.
Good work.
Sisko to Odo.
Yes, Commander.
Find Dr. Bashir
and meet me immediately
at Landing Pad C.
On our way.
Commander, you know
there's no reason
to go after Dukat.
l mean, you heard Legate Parn.
They don't want him back.
Are you suggesting
we leave him to the Maquis?
Why risk our lives over someone
who's caused so many deaths?
The way l see it
he's getting exactly
what he deserves.
The Central Command
wants him dead.
That's reason enough
for us to want him alive.
Landing Pad C.
My mind to your mind.
Your thoughts to my thoughts.
My mind to your mind...
What is wrong?
lt's not working.
That is what's wrong.
This is quite puzzling.
l am unable to establish
a mind-meld.
lt would appear
he has the ability
to shield his thoughts.
Simply a matter of discipline.
Now what do we do?
l will rest awhile
and then l will try again.
You people really do not
do this very well, do you?
Now, on Cardassia, we know
how to extract information
though it can get
a bit... unpleasant
and we all know
how the Federation
dislikes unpleasantness.
l share very few sentiments
with the Federation.
Ooh, that's right.
You're renegades,
aren't you?
Or so you'd like to think.
Unfortunately, the Federation
has taught you your lessons
all too well.
You simply lack
the commitment it takes
to do what is necessary.
You tell that to the crew
of the Bok'nor.
Oh, anyone can blow up a ship.
But to look your enemy
in the eye
knowing you'll
remember his face
for the rest of your life,
now, that takes...
a stomach much stronger
than you'll ever have.
We'll see about that.
No.
He's right.
We do not possess
the Cardassian gift
for inflicting pain.
There. You see?
Nor would we want such a gift.
But we do need to know
when the Central Command
is sending
its next weapons shipment.
So, if it's all the same
to you, Sakonna
l'll take over
this interrogation.
Then we can find out
just how committed l am.
l don't think
anyone's that interested.
Put down your weapons.
We're not here to fight you.
lf that is true, then you will
let us go about our business.
l'm not leaving without Dukat.
Then you're not leaving.
Look, we're all
on the same side here.
We all want to stop
the arms shipments.
Why not work together?
Will you stop talking
and shoot them?
No, that's not what we want.
What are you waiting for?
Put down your weapons.
Do as he says.
Shoot them!
Let him go!
l said let him go!
Odo, get these people
secured on the runabout.
With pleasure, Commander.
Except this one.
You mean l'm free to go?
Tell Cal Hudson
l haven't told Starfleet
anything yet.
Tell him, we can still
solve this thing together,
but we're running out of time.
Tell him, l still
have his uniform.
He can have it back
anytime he wants.
Ah.
Enter.
l just came by to see
how you were doing.
l find a good meal
extremely relaxing
especially
after a difficult day.
-So do l.
-Really?
l wonder what else
we have in common.
Very little, l imagine.
Other than the fact
that you have my office.
Tell me, what's going to happen
with your prisoners?
They'll be tried
for their crimes
under the Federation
Code of Justice.
And if they're found innocent?
l doubt that they will
but, if they are,
they'll be set free.
How barbaric.
ln Cardassia,
the verdict is always known
before the trial begins
and it's always the same.
ln that case, why bother
with a trial at all?
Because the people demand it.
They enjoy watching justice
triumph over evil every time.
They find it comforting.
lsn't there ever a chance
you might try
an innocent man by mistake?
Cardassians don't make mistakes.
l'll have to remember that.
Commander...
one thing does puzzle me.
Surely the Central Command
was informed of my kidnapping.
They learned about it
almost as soon as it happened.
Then why was l rescued by you?
Why wasn't the station
surrounded by Cardassian ships
demanding my release?
We did receive a visit
from Legate Parn.
Ah! l'm sure he made some rather
ugly threats on my behalf, hmm?
He said that you
were the one responsible
for smuggling weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone.
That if the Maquis
did not execute you
then the Central Command
would...
after a comforting trial,
l'm sure.
Well...
it seems my relationship
with the Central Command
has somewhat deteriorated.
l knew this was inevitable
the moment we withdrew
from Bajor.
Are you saying they blamed you
for the withdrawal?
Ha! There are those who believe
l should have killed
every last Bajoran
while l had the chance.
Oh, well.
lt's too late for that,
l'm afraid.
Commander, it seems l was mis...
Mistaken
about the arms shipment?
lt appears l was misinformed.
l'm beginning to believe
the Central Command
is indeed smuggling weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone
after all.
Then you really
didn't know, did you?
No.
They never bothered to tell me.
lf l help you stop the smuggling
will you help me
stop the Maquis?
You have a deal.
l've scheduled
a staff meeting for 0900.
l'll be there.
Commander... thank you
for coming to my rescue.
l'm sure you would have done
the same for me.
Constable, do you have
the list of weapons
Sakonna bought from Quark?
l do, and quite a list it is.
Six ship-mounted
high-energy disrupters
three particle accelerators,
200 photon torpedoes
and a dozen pulse cannons.
With that kind of firepower
the Bajorans
could have launched
a full-scale assault
on Cardassia.
And lost.
Sounds like the Maquis
have had their fill
of border skirmishes.
They're ready
for something bigger.
According to Quark
they're planning
their first attack any day now.
Have you been able to make
any headway with Sakonna?
Have you ever tried
to interrogate a Vulcan,
Lieutenant?
No.
Well, neither had l,
until today.
l wouldn't advise it.
That calm, measured voice
that tells you nothing
that impassive stare--
it can be quite frustrating.
Perhaps l could question her.
l don't think so.
Pity.
l like a challenge.
You want a challenge?
Find out how the Central Command
is getting weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone.
My guess would be by way
of a Xepolite free trader.
Why the Xepolites?
Because the Xepolites
have often served
as intermediaries for us
in the past.
So have the Lissepians.
Ah, but the Xepolites
have never been caught.
The Xepolite ship isn't
responding to our hails, sir.
Of course
they're not responding.
Would you respond
to a Federation hail
if your cargo bays
were full of Cardassian weapons?
Scan their ship, Major.
Let's see what they're carrying.
Our scanners can't
penetrate their hull.
No wonder.
lt's composed of
a sensor-reflective material.
They obviously value
their privacy.
Chief, you and Gul
Dukat remain here.
Major, you're with me.
Let's go see
if it's their privacy
or their guilt,
they're trying to protect.
Sorry, Commander,
you can't transport over.
They just raised their shields.
You're wasting time.
Xepolite ships can reach
a maximum speed of warp 9.8.
lf they decide to run,
we'll never catch them.
Well, what would you suggest?
l would breach their shields
with my phasers
and destroy their Bridge.
Killing everyone there.
That's correct.
Then l would lock onto the ship
with my tractor beam
and tow it, and its cargo,
back to the station.
Very simple, very effective.
And needlessly bloody.
Sounds like a Cardassian
plan to me.
Chief, fire a phaser
over their bow.
Let's see if we can
get their attention.
Yes, sir.
That woke them up.
They're hailing us.
On my monitor, Chief.
l am Drofo Awa,
Hetman of this vessel.
What do you want from us?
l'm Commander Benjamin Sisko
of the United Federation
of Planets.
We believe you're carrying
Cardassian weapons
to their colonies
in the Demilitarized Zone.
Well, then, you believe wrong,
Commander.
My ship is carrying
five kilotons of Regrean
wheat husks, nothing more.
Five kilotons--
that's a lot of wheat husks.
With your permission,
l'd like to come aboard
and see what that looks like.
Permission denied.
And if there's any attempt
to board my vessel
l will consider it
an act of piracy.
ls that clear?
You can call it
anything you like
but you're not going anywhere
until we search your ship.
ln that case, Commander...
ln that case, you will do
exactly as you're told.
You will allow us
free access to your ship
so that we can verify
you are indeed smuggling
Cardassian weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone.
You will then follow us back
to Deep Space 9
where your cargo
will be confiscated
and you will make
a full confession
detailing everything you know
about smuggling weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone.
Then you will sign
that confession
after which, you and your ship
will be allowed on your way.
ls that clear?
l don't understand.
You're a Cardassian.
l'm not just any Cardassian.
l'm Gul Dukat, Commander
of the Second Order.
You have 15 seconds
to lower your shields
or we'll destroy you.
No, wait!
Ten seconds.
No, it's not that simple!
Seven seconds.
l've already been paid!
Four seconds.
Stop counting!
He's lowering his shields.
l'll await your arrival,
Commander.
l think you can
handle it from here.
l hope you're happy.
l am a Vulcan.
My emotional state
is irrelevant.
Well, l'm a Ferengi
and my emotional state
is very relevant
and right now, l'm miserable
and it's all your fault.
You were well paid
for your assistance.
Not well enough.
Look, l know the Cardassians
can't be trusted.
l know the Central Command
would like nothing better
than to destroy
the Federation colonies
in the Demilitarized Zone.
Then you agree
with our position?
Not for a second.
Why not?
Because your position
is illogical.
Do you propose
to lecture me on logic?
l don't want to,
but you leave me no choice.
lt all comes down
to the Third Rule
of Acquisition.
You don't know that one, do you?
l am not well-versed
in Ferengi philosophy.
Remind me to give you
a copy of the Rules.
You never know
when they'll come in handy.
Now, the Third Rule
clearly states
''Never spend more
for an acquisition
than you have to.''
Logical, but l fail to see
how that applies
to my situation.
You want to acquire peace.
Fine. Peace is good
but how much are you
willing to pay for it?
Whatever it costs.
That's the kind
of irresponsible spending
that causes so many
business ventures to fail.
You're forgetting
the Third Rule.
Right now, peace could be bought
at a bargain price
and you don't even realize it.
l find this very confusing.
Then l'll make it so simple
that even a Vulcan
can understand.
The Central Command has
been caught red-handed
smuggling weapons
to their settlers.
So, every ship that approaches
the Demilitarized Zone
will be searched.
Without the support
of the Central Command
the Cardassian settlers
won't be so eager to fight.
You forget the weapons
they already have.
They have weapons.
You have weapons.
Everyone has weapons
but right now, no one
has a clear advantage.
So, the price of peace
is at an all-time low.
This is the perfect time
to sit down
and hammer out an agreement.
Don't you get it?
Attacking the Cardassians now
will only escalate the conflict
and make peace more expensive
in the long run.
Now, l ask you, is that logical?
A concealed weapons depot
located within
a civilian population center?
According to Sakonna
the Maquis are going
to attack the depot
sometime
within the next 52 hours.
But she didn't tell you
on which colony
the depot is hidden.
She says she doesn't know.
How convenient.
l believe her.
Why?
Because Vulcans don't lie?
As a rule, they don't.
They don't blow up
ships either, as a rule.
But let's assume
she's telling the truth.
l take it you haven't
shared this information
with the Central Command?
No, l haven't.
Good, because they
would never trust you
to handle this matter alone.
But they would be able
to tell me where
the weapons depot is located.
Leave that to me.
l may no longer be a favorite
with Central Command
but l know people who are.
ln the meantime,
l'll go to Volon lll
and try to talk some sense
into the Maquis.
And if you can't?
Don't worry, Dukat.
l said l would stop the Maquis,
and, one way or another, l will.
l've also
been recently informed
that 35 people
had to be hospitalized
on Umoth Vlll after eating
from public food replicators.
Sabotage is suspected.
Then from now on,
guards should be posted
at all public replicators
throughout the colonies.
Thank you.
Now, about the new curfew...
Commander Sisko,
what a pleasant surprise.
lf you'll just wait a moment,
l'll finish up this meeting
and we can talk privately.
That won't be necessary.
l want everyone to hear
what l have to say.
l don't know
how many of you here
actually belong to the Maquis.
Those of you who don't
probably have friends who do.
So, please make sure
you pass along
what l'm about to tell you.
There is a treaty
currently in place
with Cardassia
and the Federation.
lf you make yourself
an enemy of Cardassia
you make yourself an enemy
of the Federation.
That is outrageous.
Agreed.
l know the Maquis
is planning to attack
a Cardassian weapons depot.
My advice to them and to you
is to call it off
because l'll be waiting there,
and l will stop you.
A very rousing speech, Ben.
l suppose my best rebuttal
would be to kill you.
But you won't.
What is this?
Your uniform.
You always were an optimist.
l have every reason to be.
The way l see it,
now that we've stopped
the shipments
of Cardassian weapons
there's no longer any need
for the Maquis.
You and l can work together
to reach a peace agreement
with the Cardassian colonies.
lt's too late for that.
ls it?
We're in a war here,
and l intend to win it.
l could use your help, Ben
and l'm asking you as a friend.
As a friend...
l have to say no.
lf you attack the depot
you'll have
to get through me first.
l hope not.
l truly hope not.
The Bryma colony--
according to my sources
that's the location
of the weapons depot.
Then our objective is simple--
prevent the Maquis ships
from reaching Bryma.
We're going
to have to intercept them
before they're picked up
by the colony's sensors.
Good point.
lf the Cardassian
settlers even suspect
they might come under attack
they'll send a message
to Cardassia
asking for reinforcements.
l don't care how much
the Cardassians
care about the treaty
if the Maquis launch an assault
against a civilian target
the Central Command
will have to respond.
We could wind up with
a full-scale war on our hands.
We have to stop the Maquis.
Our runabouts will take up
a defensive position
just outside the Bryma colony's
sensor range.
The best way
to detect incoming ships
would be to hide
a couple dozen sensor probes
in the system's Oort cloud.
That way,
we could spot the Maquis
no matter what route they take.
How many Maquis ships
are we expecting?
According to Sakonna,
they only have two ships
capable of mounting
the weapons she purchased.
So, we'll have three ships,
and they'll have two.
The odds are in our favor,
anyway.
That's not going to give us
much of an advantage, Julian.
The colonists are used
to being outnumbered.
They'll fight just
that much harder.
How do you propose to stop them?
What's that human expression?
''Shoot to kill.''
We'll try to stop
them with words
if possible;
with force, if necessary.
So, if they fire at us,
we have orders to shoot back.
That's correct.
We'll target their warp engines
and weapons arrays--
try to disable them.
How noble.
l hope the Maquis will be
as obliging to you.
Rio Grande to
Mekong and Orinoco.
How do you read me?
Orinoco here.
You're loud and clear.
Mekong here.
Our communications channel
is fully operational and secure.
The remote sensor
probes l set up
still haven't detected
any sign of the Maquis ships.
Do you really think
they're coming?
They know we're waiting
for them, after all.
lt's possible they changed
the time frame of their attack--
postponed it a day or a week.
They'll be here.
The longer they wait,
the greater the chance
the weapons depot will be
moved to another location.
Commander, l'm picking up
two Federation ships
headed our way.
Sisko to Hudson.
This isn't going to work, Cal.
Turn those ships around
before someone gets hurt.
Please, Ben,
don't make me open fire on you.
He's not going to listen.
lnitiating evasive maneuvers.
Signal Niles to follow my lead.
Right.
Commander, they're
making a run for it.
Lock on tractor beams.
Damn it!
They've got Niles, too.
Let us go, Ben.
You know l can't do that.
Then l suggest you duck.
Fire on their beam emitter.
What are you waiting for?
We're losing tractor lock.
They're breaking away.
Commence firing.
Niles' propulsion system
is down.
He's drifting.
We'll have to even the odds.
They've hit
our navigational array.
l've lost attitude control.
Attempting to compensate
with manual thrusters.
lt's not working.
Thrusters are still locked.
Hang on.
Chief, you go after
the Orinoco.
l'll handle Hudson.
Right. Major.
-Yes, Chief?
-Lower your shields.
We'll beam you out of there.
You got it.
They're coming back around.
lt's just you and me, Ben.
l can't let you start a war.
l'm not turning back.
And you're not going forward.
We're hit.
Our photon torpedo tubes
are out.
Switch to phasers.
Come about,
heading 1 15 mark 326.
Got it.
We've taken a direct hit
on our primary fusion core.
lnitiating emergency
core shutdown.
The port nacelle is flooded
with ionized deuterium.
We've lost both warp
and impulse engines.
We still have
maneuvering thrusters.
They're coming back around.
Use the phasers.
l can't.
They've knocked out
the power couplings
to our weapons array.
What do we do?
The only thing we can do.
We get the hell out of here.
He's turning away.
Now's your chance-- fire.
lt's over, Cal.
For now, anyway.
Next time, tell Starfleet
to send someone else.
lt doesn't feel right,
you and l
shooting at each other.
There won't be a next time.
Stand down!
l don't think so, Ben.
He's getting away!
You run now,
l won't be able to protect you.
Starfleet will track you down.
You won't be safe anywhere--
not even in the colonies.
Don't be so sure.
l have a lot of friends here.
Besides, l've got to help
the Maquis finish this thing.
You'll be an outlaw--
a hunted man.
Maybe.
You're throwing away
your entire life.
And beginning a new one.
What are you waiting for?
He's helpless.
Finish him.
l'm going to miss you, Ben.
You've been a good friend.
So have you.
No!
l thought you were strong,
Commander.
You're not.
You're a fool.
A sentimental fool.
l said l'd stop the Maquis,
and l have
but l will not kill a good man
for defending his home.
You disappoint me.
Don't expect me to lose
any sleep over it.
Mr. O'Brien,
when you get a chance
l could use some help
with these engines.
Yes, sir.
Commander, Gul Dukat
has left the station.
l'm sure he's glad
to be going home.
Chief O'Brien says
that the Orinoco
and the Rio Grande
will be up and running
in a few days.
Thank you, Major.
l just got a communiqué
from Starfleet
congratulating me
on my good work
and thanking me for preserving
the peace with the Cardassians.
You deserve it.
You prevented a war.
Did l?
Or did l just
delay the inevitable?