Station Log, Stardate 46729.1.
The Bajoran government
has asked me
to mediate a disagreement
between two rival factions,
the Paqu and the Navot.
At issue is a land dispute
which could trigger
a civil war.
Commander, the Paqu delegation
has arrived at Docking Port 6.
Let's welcome them aboard.
Dax, any word on the Navot?
They should be here
within the hour.
Excuse me, Commander.
Chief, l thought you'd be
on your way to Bajor by now.
We're due to leave any moment.
But, sir, l was wondering
if, perhaps, Ensign Boyer
might replace me
on this particular mission.
After all, l'd be little more
than a chauffeur
and Boyer can pilot a runabout
just as well as l can.
Has something come up
that requires your presence
on the station, Chief?
No, sir. Everything's
running smoothly for a change.
But around here, you never know.
Ah, Chief, there you are.
All set to go?
Yes, sir.
Commander, did the Magistrate
give any indication
as to the nature
of this medical emergency?
Only that his village
was in danger of extinction.
ln that case,
we'd better be on our way.
l agree.
Yes, sir.
Docking Port 6.
You know, Chief, in a way
l'm really looking forward
to this mission.
And why is that?
Well, l see it
as a wonderful opportunity
for us to get
to know each other.
Oh.
l'd like you to set
a preliminary meeting
with both sides
for later this afternoon.
Make sure they know that this
is an informal session.
l just want to get them
talking to each other.
Just getting them to sit down
at the same table
will be an accomplishment.
Sir, about these negotiations...
You have some advice for me?
There's an old saying on Bajor.
''The land and the people
are one.''
Well, the land inhabited
by the Paqu and the Navot
is some of the harshest
on the planet.
Relax, Major.
This is not my first time
up at the plate.
Sir...
Besides, l'll have you
by my side
to help me avoid
making mistakes.
Tell me what you know
about the Paqu Tetrarch.
Not much.
The Paqu choose to avoid
contact with outsiders.
Commander Sisko?
Yes?
l am Varis Sul,
Tetrarch of the Paqu.
Chief, may l ask you a question?
Of course.
And l'd like an honest answer.
You'll get one.
Do l...
annoy you?
Annoy me?
What sort of a question
is that?
Well, the thing is,
we've just spent
the last two hours alone
together in this runabout
and you've hardly said
a word to me the whole time.
Really?
l hadn't noticed.
Oh, l see.
l suppose it's because
l was too busy thinking.
Thinking?
That's right.
About what?
What?
What were you thinking about?
l'm just curious.
Well, let's see, um...
l was thinking that when
we get back to the station
l'll have to run
a level-1 diagnostic
on the phase coil generators.
Satisfied?
l suppose so.
Glad to hear it.
l mean, the only reason
l bring it up
is because your opinion
means a lot to me
and l'm aware
that l have a tendency
to run off at the mouth
sometimes.
ls that a fact?
l suppose it's just
a nervous habit.
l hope you don't
hold it against me.
Oh, not at all, sir.
And one more thing.
What's that, sir?
l don't think
it's really necessary
to call me ''sir.''
What should l call you?
You're my superior officer.
How about Julian?
ls that an order?
Oh, no, of course not.
lt's just that l'd
simply prefer it
if you called me
by my first name.
All right.
We've achieved
stable orbit around Bajor.
We can beam down any time...
Julian.
No sign
of any airborne infections.
The soil appears to be
free of pollutants
and the groundwater clear
of bacterial contamination.
Gentlemen.
l am Faren Kag,
the village magistrate.
l'm Dr. Bashir.
This is Chief O'Brien.
This village
is in great jeopardy.
l only hope you're not too late.
Has he shown
any sign of improvement?
None.
You must help him.
How many others are sick?
Others?
You said the entire village
was in jeopardy.
lt is.
lf he dies, we all die.
l'll say this
for the Cardassians--
their replicators
make a fine larish pie.
l didn't come here
to eat, Commander.
Then let's talk.
The official negotiations
don't begin until tonight
but l thought it
might be a good idea
that we meet informally
to see where we all stand.
According to the treaty
that has existed between you
for the past 90 years
''the border separating
the Paqu and the Navot
shall forever be
the river Glyrhond.''
That's correct.
Well, at least
we all agree on something.
Now, as l understand it,
during the occupation
the Cardassians
diverted the river
for use
in their mining operations.
As a result,
the Glyrhond now flows
20 kilometers west
of its former position.
20 kilometers
into Navot territory.
That's Paqu territory now.
You read the treaty, Commander.
The river is our common border.
The treaty says nothing
about stealing land.
lf your father was alive
he would give us back
what is ours.
My father would do
no such thing.
Besides, l'm Tetrarch now.
l will not be pressured
into betraying my people.
Let's see...
two Bajoran synthales
a glass of Gamzian wine
and a Trixian bubble juice
for the little lady.
l'm not a little lady.
l'm still charging her
for that drink.
Oh.
Nog, we've been sitting
here over an hour.
Let's go play some ball
in the holosuite.
No!
Why not?
Because baseball
is slow and boring.
And you can't hit
my curve ball.
lt's a stupid game
that even humans stopped playing
hundreds of years ago.
Maybe, but you still
can't hit my curve ball.
Mr. Sisko, Nog,
l thought l told you
no dangling over the Promenade.
We're not going to fall, Odo.
We can see things
better from down here.
And what, may l ask,
is so interesting?
Nothing.
ln that case,
you can see ''nothing''
just as well from up here.
Now, on your feet.
Thank you.
Are you going to come
to the holosuite
with me, or not?
Come on, we could have Buck
Bokai hit a few out to us.
He was the greatest
hitter of all time.
l'll even let you use my glove.
l have never seen anything
so beautiful.
She's all right.
All right?
l have to meet her.
Ah! The Dal'Rok.
Easy now.
Try not to exert yourself.
Huh? Hovath...
l'm here.
l'm right here.
The time...
lt's still two hours
before nightfall.
You should have wakened me.
Help me to get dressed.
l'm afraid you're
in no shape to go anywhere.
The Prophets sent you,
didn't they?
l beg your pardon?
No, there's something wrong.
lt must be your companion.
You mean Chief O'Brien?
Bring him to me.
Why?
Because you are not the one
l have been waiting for.
Chief?
He wants to see you.
Come.
Closer.
Oh, l knew.
l knew the Prophets
would not fail us.
You may leave now.
Both of you.
See that he stays in bed.
What was that all about?
l haven't a clue.
The Sirah, how is he?
l wish l had better news.
He's suffering
from systemic organ failure
brought on by an accelerated
rate of cellular decay.
His body is surrendering
to old age.
ls there anything you can do?
l can keep him comfortable
and relatively free of pain.
Other than that,
it's just a matter of time.
l'm sorry.
But we need him.
The Dal'Rok will be here soon.
What's the Dal'Rok?
lt's a terrible creature
that lives in the woods
just north of the village.
Every year at the end
of harvest, it appears.
And you say
it's coming here tonight?
Yes, it always comes
for five nights.
This will be the fourth--
and only the Sirah is
strong enough to defeat it.
Well, right now
the Sirah isn't strong enough
to get out of bed.
lf what you say is true
this village will be
destroyed tonight.
You're sure this is the place?
You saw the readout.
There's only one female her age
visiting the station
and these are her quarters.
Well, go ahead.
What?
Ring the bell.
Me? You are the one
who wants to meet her.
Are you afraid?
Of a girl?
Then ring.
You ring!
You are afraid.
No, l'm not, you are.
What are you doing?
My name's Jog...
l mean Jake.
l...
He's Nog.
l'm Jake Sisko.
Sisko...
We're kind of
the unofficial welcoming
committee around here.
That's right.
Welcome to DS9.
Thank you.
l'm Varis Sul.
Would you like a tour
of the station?
There's a Klingon freighter
leaving for the Gamma Quadrant
in a little while.
We could watch it
go through the wormhole.
Good-good-good idea.
Thanks.
So, how about it?
You want to go?
l've never seen the wormhole.
Then you're in luck
'cause we know
the best spot on the station
for wormhole-watching.
Unless you're busy or something.
Not at the moment.
Listen to me, Sirah.
You must return to bed.
To be out here,
in your condition...
Your concern touches me, Doctor
but l am now in the hands
of the Prophets.
We believe in you.
Help us, Sirah.
Strange...
l'm not registering
any atmospheric disturbance.
The Dal'Rok wakes...
but we are ready.
ln the shadow of the night,
he hungers.
With a hatred of the ancients,
he rages.
From the twisted pit of chaos,
he approaches.
ls it alive?
The tricorder's still
not picking up anything.
Could it be some kind
of holographic image?
No.
l'm not picking up
any power source.
The Dal'Rok's anger
is like a wave crashing down
upon the village.
The weight of its fury
threatens to crush us all.
The Dal'Rok thinks the village
is powerless to defend itself...
but the Dal'Rok is mistaken.
The village is strong--
much stronger than the Dal'Rok
can ever imagine.
The village is strong!
With our strength, our unity
we shall drive the Dal'Rok...
Bloody hell!
Chief!
Help us get him down from here!
Where is my successor?
Sirah...
No. The one
whom the Prophets sent.
Yes, you.
W-wait a second.
l think you got the wrong guy.
Say what l say.
The village shall
not be destroyed.
What?!
Quickly.
The village
shall not be destroyed.
Louder, so they can all hear.
The village
shall not be destroyed!
Despite our fears
we shall stand our ground
and face the Dal'Rok.
Despite our fears
we shall stand our ground
and face the Dal'Rok.
The village is strong.
More powerful than the Dal'Rok.
Together, we use that power
to drive it away.
Drive it away!
The Dal'Rok is defeated.
The village is safe.
He's dead.
The Sirah has left us
but the Prophets have sent us
his successor.
A new Sirah to tell the story.
Story, the story!
A new Sirah
to protect the village.
So l sold them a whole herd
of Klingon targs.
Major, what a pleasant surprise.
l always look forward
to one
of your infrequent visits.
Spare me the small talk
and get me a stardrifter.
So, uh...
how are the negotiations
coming along?
Better make it a double.
Ah.
You asked to see me?
Please, sit down.
l just spent
the last five hours sitting.
Yes, five long,
unproductive hours.
Woban is an obstinate fool.
Woban is here to talk.
What are you here for?
l would think that was obvious--
to protect the interests
of my people.
How, by starting a war?
l object to your tone,
Commander.
Because if that's
what you're here for--
if you'd rather
fight than talk--
then we're just
wasting our time.
That land belongs to the Paqu.
The Navot don't agree.
Then they'd better be ready
to die for it.
l am.
Or don't you believe me?
l believe in people
working together
to find reasonable solutions
to their problems.
l hope you do as well.
What you hope
is no concern of mine.
Now, anything else
you wish to say to me
can be said tomorrow
across a conference table.
Varis...
are you sure your people
are as ready as you are
to die for that land?
Where do you think she is?
l guess if she's not here,
we'll try again at her quarters.
When we find her,
let me do the talking.
She asked me questions,
l answered them.
What's wrong with that?
Just remember, l saw her first.
She's mine.
Then how come you can barely
say two words to her
without getting tongue-tied?
That's a lie!
l've never seen you so nervous.
You must really like her.
l never said that!
All l said was...
We were just...
Looking for you.
l've been busy.
ls something wrong?
You seem a little depressed.
lt's nothing, really.
lt's just...
there are these people
who want something l have
and l refuse to give it to them.
How badly do they want it?
Very badly.
ls there anything they have
that you want?
That l want.
Maybe this isn't a problem.
Maybe...
it's an opportunity.
Maybe.
When l have a problem
l can't figure out
l ask my dad.
l ask my dad, too.
lt helps, doesn't it?
Yeah.
No.
My dad's
a pretty smart guy.
Mine, too...
in his own way.
My parents are dead.
They were killed
by the Cardassians.
l'm sorry.
My mom was killed
during an attack by the Borg.
lsn't there someone
you can talk to?
Someone you trust?
l don't trust many people.
My dad says...
Could we please talk
about something
besides your father?
You admire him very much,
don't you?
l trust him.
Mr. Sisko...
Odo.
We were just leaving.
l wonder what was controlling
those energy creatures.
One thing's certain--
it wasn't me.
Try telling the villagers that.
They saw the Sirah choose you
as his successor.
Well, he made a mistake.
You saw the way he greeted you
when we arrived.
lt was as if he
was expecting you.
But l'll tell you this, Chief
l'm glad you came along
on this mission
because if it wasn't for you
l'd have done what l could
for the Sirah and left
and look what l
would have missed.
Well, l'm glad you're
enjoying yourself, Julian.
Don't worry, Chief,
l have faith in you.
Oh, do you?!
l mean, for all we know
you really were sent
by the Prophets.
l was sent by Commander Sisko.
This Dal'Rok, or whatever
will be returning this evening
and everybody's counting
on me to be able to stop it.
The only trouble is
l don't have the slightest idea
how l'm supposed to do that.
These gifts are for you, Sirah.
Well, look,
tell them l don't want them.
Oh, bring them in.
Put them wherever you like.
Now, look, Julian...
We're visitors here, Chief.
lt would be impolite
to refuse our hosts.
Thank you, Sirah.
How can l help you, ladies?
l think they're the ones
offering services, Chief.
Now, look, t-there's been
a serious misunderstanding.
ls there a problem, Sirah?
No! They're not...
Well, yes...
l mean, they're quite...
Look, l have a wife
and daughter back on DS9.
Of course.
You must send for them.
Why?
So they can live here with you.
No, you're missing the point.
l'm not staying.
Then, who will tell the story?
Well, you'll just
have to find someone else.
But there is no one else.
The Sirah chose you.
He made a mistake.
But what about the Dal'Rok?
Without your protection,
it will kill us all.
Faren, l would like
to help, really l would
but l don't know how.
You must tell the story.
Simple as that, is it?
May the Prophets
grant you victory, Sirah.
Let's hope so.
Now what are we going to do?
The way l see it,
the only way out of this mess
is to find out exactly
what this Dal'Rok is
and destroy it
before it destroys us.
Station Log, supplemental.
We have completed
a second day of talks
between the Paqu and the Navot.
So far, we're no closer
to finding a solution
than we were
when negotiations began.
Enter.
Hi. You want to do something?
Sorry, not right now.
Okay, we'll stop by later.
ls there anything we can do
to cheer you up?
l don't think so.
You sure?
Let's go before
you embarrass yourself.
Wait.
Yes?
Do you remember
that opportunity
we were discussing yesterday?
Yes.
How can you be sure
that an opportunity
is worth the risk?
Ah. lnstinct.
The Ninth Rule of Acquisition
clearly states
that opportunity plus instinct
equals profit.
lnstinct...
That's not going to help.
l think it does.
Thank you, Nog.
Good!
Let's celebrate.
Celebrate?
l took one
of my uncle's security rods.
What are we going
to do with that?
l don't know.
We could swipe Odo's bucket.
Are you kidding?
A bucket?
Yeah.
We'll give it back.
Yeah, but...
lt'll be funny.
But we can't just walk
into Security.
Watch me.
Wait over there.
l still don't understand
what's so funny about a bucket.
Odo lives in it.
He's a shape-shifter.
Every 16 hours
he has to change back
to his original form.
lnside a bucket?
He turns
into some kind of liquid.
Maybe this isn't
such a good idea.
Watch the front door.
l'll be right back.
Jake, are you sure
this is all right?
Well, it's not like we're
really stealing anything.
Found it.
Oops!
Odo!
lt's oatmeal.
l filled it
from the replicator.
Very funny!
You should have seen your face.
l believe that belongs to me.
What's the rush?
There's some residual
neutrino levels
in the microstructure
of these rocks.
But if the Dal'Rok has
no physical substance
how can it leave
a neutrino trace?
l didn't say it made sense,
but this rock face
didn't just spontaneously
blow itself to pieces.
Lucky for us,
you managed to stop it
before it did any more damage.
All l did was repeat
what the Sirah told me.
ln that case, how did the
Sirah manage to stop it?
Good question.
Maybe there's
a control mechanism
hidden somewhere.
Excuse me, miss.
Please, Sirah, for my daughter.
What about her?
lt looks like she wants you
to bless her child.
Me?!
lt would mean so much.
l'm sure she'll make
you very proud.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
There he is.
You're quite welcome.
Looks like more
of your followers
are requesting an audience.
Oh, no.
This won't do.
Um, you continue
looking around here.
l'm going to check
the Sirah's room.
Please, please.
l'm afraid the Sirah
is busy at the moment.
Perhaps l could be of service.
Sirah, come back!
Please, Sirah, a moment.
Look, l could use some privacy.
There are more gifts
outside for you.
All right, bring them in.
Hold on.
Didn't you work for the Sirah?
Mm-hmm.
l, um...
l was his apprentice.
Oh. Did he ever reveal
any of his secrets?
How he controlled the Dal'Rok
and that sort of thing?
Why ask me?
Surely, the Sirah
must have taught you
all you need to know.
Oh, all right!
Have it your way.
Don't blame me
when that creature
goes rampaging
through your village.
Chief!
Careful.
Don't hurt him.
l'll try not to.
That's enough.
Tell him that.
l said, that's enough!
Now, you mind explaining
why you tried to kill me?
You are not the true Sirah.
You won't get
any argument from me.
lf he isn't, who is?
l am.
For nine years,
l studied with the Sirah
learning the secrets
of the storyteller
only to have you come
along and take my place.
Look, friend,
as far as l'm concerned
the job's yours.
But if you were
supposed to take over
how come the Sirah chose him?
lt was his way of punishing me.
Punishing you?
Three nights ago
the Sirah allowed me
to tell the story
but when the Dal'Rok appeared,
l was unable to control it.
Several people were injured.
Control it, how?
With this.
This stone is said to be
a fragment of an Orb
from the Celestial Temple.
We had one of those Orbs
aboard our station.
We're aware
of how powerful they are.
Many years ago, this village
was deeply divided
by hate and mistrust.
The first Sirah knew
that unless he could find a way
to unite the people, the village
would destroy itself
so he used the Orb fragment
as a catalyst
to give their fears
a physical form.
So the villagers' thoughts
create the Dal'Rok.
Yes, but they don't know that.
lt's a secret which is passed
from Sirah to Sirah.
Why do they need a storyteller?
The story helps to focus
the villagers' thoughts.
And that enables them
to defeat the Dal'Rok
by creating
the shimmering lights.
l know, if l had another chance,
l could control the Dal'Rok.
Well, son
it looks like tonight
you are going
to get that chance.
What is this?
You have no right
to wear those clothes.
l have every right.
You had your chance
to prove yourself.
You failed.
lt won't happen again.
That's right--
because you won't be allowed
to endanger the village
a second time.
Now take off those robes!
Now, hold on.
Sirah...
it's time you were
getting ready.
The people will be assembling
soon to hear the story.
l want you to know, Commander
that l take
complete responsibility
for what happened
in the Security Office.
l think that there's
more than enough blame
to spread around.
Jake should have known better.
l'm afraid he and Nog
were just trying to impress me.
That's not much of an excuse.
Didn't you ever do
anything foolish
to impress a girl?
l may have.
Jake's a nice boy.
So is Nog... in his own way.
l enjoy their company.
l suppose you don't get
much of a chance
to be with people your age.
True, but...
that's not why l wanted
to be with them.
l wanted to learn about you.
And?
Jake speaks very highly of you.
He trusts you.
That's always nice to hear.
Hearing Jake speak of you...
reminded me of how much
l miss my own parents.
My father was a great man.
A great leader.
l'm sure he'd be
very proud of you.
l try to be strong
the way he was strong, but...
it's difficult.
From what l've learned
of your father
he wasn't afraid to compromise.
That's because he knew
the Navot feared him.
lf l were to make concessions,
Woban would think l was weak.
l doubt he would be
that foolish
but he is determined
to get that land back.
l am not afraid
of Woban or the Navot.
l never said you were.
So your answer is still no.
You don't lose by saying no.
Maybe
but a great leader
like your father
is one who's willing
to risk saying yes.
Commander...
l believe l know of...
an opportunity...
that could allow both sides
to say yes.
Sirah, you'll save us.
l thought you wanted this job.
l do.
Then, why don't you
fight for it?
No, Faren is right.
These people will never
accept me as Sirah.
Without their support
l could never control
the Dal'Rok.
You think l can?
You have to.
Oh, Chief.
Good luck.
Tell us the story!
Sirah, the story!
Once upon a time...
there was a Dal'Rok
and it lives there, in the woods
and he hated the village
and all of the villagers
and he wanted
to see them destroyed.
The Dal'Rok is here!
Yes! The Dal'Rok is here
and it's hungry
but the village
is prepared to fight
like it has always fought--
with the lights,
the shimmering lights.
Something's wrong.
What's wrong is that O'Brien
is not the Sirah--
you are.
Come on, you can do it!
The village is strong
and unafraid...
and... powerful
and ready to face the Dal'Rok.
Do you think that maybe
the Sirah planned all this?
He knew the villagers
had lost confidence in you
so he chose O'Brien
as his successor
knowing that you would
have to rescue him.
Don't you see--
this is your chance
to prove once and for all
that you are the true Sirah.
All right now...
let's really focus
and send this one out, okay?
Let's really send
the Dal'Rok a message.
Where the hell are those lights?
Wait!
There is no need to run!
A new voice appears
to challenge the Dal'Rok!
lt's about time.
The Dal'Rok is a fearsome enemy.
The mountains tremble
with its fury
but our prosperity
is its misery
our unity is its vulnerability
and our strength is its doom.
Look-- the Dal'Rok trembles!
lt fears our strength.
lt fears our determination.
lt knows
it cannot stand against us
because the village is united.
We are as one.
You see for yourselves.
The Dal'Rok is defeated.
This village is safe
for another year.
The Sirah! The Sirah!
Let's get out of here
before they change their minds.
Sirah! Sirah!
Sirah!
Hail the Sirah.
Nervous?
Not at all.
Maybe a little.
Do you think Woban
will accept my proposal?
lt's very possible.
lt would give the Navot
back their land.
And free trade access
to both sides of the river
would mean a lot to my people.
lt's a reasonable compromise.
We thought we'd wish you luck
with your meeting.
Thank you...
...for all your help.
All right, let's go.
You two are going
to clean the Security Office
until it shines.
You know, Chief
this is going to make
a fantastic story
to tell around the station.
Not for me.
l've had my fill of storytelling
for the time being.
Well, l hope you don't mind
if l mention it.
Suit yourself... Julian.
Oh, and, Chief,
on second thought...
you don't really have
to call me Julian.
Right you are... sir.