l've never seen
anything like that.
Hmm?
l've never seen
anything like that.
The woman?
She was dead.
The tricorder clearly showed...
Ah, yes, well, tricorders--
very accurate with live people
not so accurate with dead ones.
We learned that first
year medical school.
Well, l was
very impressed, Doctor.
Hmm, and well you
should have been.
l impressed myself
on that one, actually.
l can't imagine
what other doctor
would even consider examining
the scapular nodes
for parasitic infection.
l just seem to have a talent,
l suppose.
A vision that sees past
the obvious, around the mundane
right to the target.
Fate has granted me a gift,
Major.
A gift to be a healer.
l feel privileged to be
in your presence.
Oh, glad to have you along.
Did anyone ever tell you
that you're...?
Priority one
broadband distress signal.
Kobliad Transport Ship Reyab
to any ship.
Our central power linkage
has exploded.
We're losing life-support.
Please respond.
Just picking it up
on long-range sensors.
Bearing 347 mark 08.
l'm reading
massive energy leakage.
lts aft structural integrity
field is failing.
This is the Federation
Ship Rio Grande.
We're on our way.
O2 pressure is dropping rapidly.
Toxic gas levels are rising.
We've got no more
than ten minutes'
breathing time left in here.
Automatic fire suppression
must be off-line.
l'll check
the central power linkage.
Relax.
l'm a doctor.
What happened?
You lost consciousness.
Now listen, is there anyone else
aboard your ship?
We've got to evacuate it.
The pilot is dead.
l'm reading another life-form.
No, don't open that.
lt's sealed.
The prisoner
l was transporting...
he started the fire to escape.
He's dying.
Where is the manual override?
No!
Stop.
Don't!
Wait.
Don't go in there.
He's dangerous.
l assure you, in this condition,
he's of no threat to anyone.
Power linkages
are completely shot.
Maneuvering subsystems
are out.
l've managed to stabilize
the structural integrity field
but l don't know
how long it's going to last.
We'll have to tow it in.
His synaptic field
is dissipating.
l can't get a neural reading.
l have to get him
to the emergency unit
on the runabout.
Computer, four to transport.
Make...
me...
live.
This one, l can't bring back.
Where am l?
You're on Station DS9.
l'm Dr. Julian Bashir.
Ty Kajada.
Kobliad Security.
DS9...
but that's where he was going.
Where is he?
Where is Vantika?
Your prisoner?
He's dead.
You're certain?
Yes.
You were the only survivor.
Where is his body?
l have it in stasis.
l want to see it.
When you're feeling stronger.
Now.
Preliminary examinations
indicated
the subject died
of a massive respiratory failure
brought on
by the pulmonary trauma
suffered during the fire.
Are you sure
it's the same body?
Quite certain.
lt's been sealed in here
ever since our arrival.
Have you run
a retinal imaging scan?
What for?
To confirm that there is
no residual activity
in the visual cortex.
Miss Kajada, l assure
you, he is dead.
He's faked his death
more times than l can tell you.
And the last time
someone thought he was dead
they didn't live
to regret the mistake.
He was a murderer?
That description
doesn't begin to do justice
to the horrors he's
responsible for on my world.
He's quite brilliant,
in his own way.
A man of science,
who killed others
to prolong his own life.
l've tracked him for 20 years.
Please perform an autopsy.
l want his identity confirmed
with a DNA reference scan.
Uh... of course.
And have someone scan my ship.
l want to make sure
there are no anomalous
life-forms on board.
Are you sure that's necessary?
Very sure.
lced raktajino, extra cream.
Thank you, Quark.
At your service, day or night.
Thanks.
Poor woman.
She's obviously
infatuated with me.
You're deluding yourself.
There's nothing wrong
with a good delusion.
l sell them upstairs to
dozens of people every day.
Besides, there
is something in her eyes
when she looks at me.
Mmm.
An allergic reaction, no doubt.
l think she's lonely.
Dax? She has ten lifetimes'
worth of friends to call on
before she calls you.
And every man on the station
would like to be buying her
a raktajino.
Ah, but l'm the one
with the raktajino machine.
She seems to prefer
spending most of her time alone
which l understand perfectly.
Then that must make her
the perfect woman for you.
l wouldn't intrude
on her privacy as some would.
You're pathetic.
You think everyone in the galaxy
should be as lonely
and as miserable as you are.
As hard as it may be
for you to understand,
some of us like company.
The sound
of a friendly voice.
The sight
of a familiar face.
The feel of smooth,
pliant flesh.
Why do you bother?
lt's good to want things.
Even things you can't have?
Especially things l can't have.
Like the deuridium shipment?
Deuridium shipment?
ls there a deuridium shipment
coming here?
l'm watching you, Quark.
And l'm watching you, Jadzia.
lnteresting technique.
Do you always get ready
for an important operation
by leaking word about it
to the local black market?
How l handle my business
is none of your concern.
l'm afraid that it is.
Lieutenant George Primmin,
Starfleet Security.
And if you don't mind,
l would like to talk to you
about the deuridium shipment
from the Gamma Quadrant.
There's nothing to discuss.
Security is already in place.
l would appreciate it
if we could go over it anyhow.
lt took me three weeks
to get here
and l'd hate to think
it was for nothing.
lf you insist.
Meet me in my office
at 1700 hours.
The autopsy revealed
nothing out of the ordinary.
Fingerprints,
cerebral cortex scans
retinal patterns
all matched up perfectly
with the records
Kajada provided.
Vantika may have faked
his death before
but l don't think
he's faking this time.
Why was he coming here?
Well, they're Kobliad.
The deuridium.
l'm sorry...?
The Kobliad are a dying race.
They need deuridium to stabilize
their cell structure.
lt prolongs their life-span.
The Federation's been working
to supply them with deuridium
but even the new deposits
from the Gamma Quadrant
aren't enough to service
the whole population.
lt's so scarce
that some of the Kobliad
have gone underground to get it.
So, he was coming here
to hijack a shipment?
Exactly.
ls Kajada satisfied
with your autopsy?
l don't think anything
is going to convince her
he's dead, Commander.
Vantika has been the focus
of Kajada's attention
for most of her adult life.
ln a way, they were
as intimately connected
as any two beings could be.
Let's do her the courtesy
of granting her requests
as long as they're not
too far out of line.
A quick sweep of her ship
is not too much to ask.
l'm more concerned
that Vantika might have
had help here
waiting to hijack the shipment.
Ah, Mr. Primmin.
Good. ln my office.
l want to brief you
on a security issue
that's arisen.
l'll get Odo up here.
Uh, that's okay, Major.
l'll fill him in later
on anything he needs to know.
How are you getting on with
the Constable, Lieutenant?
l'm sure he's very good
at keeping order
down there on the Promenade.
But...?
Frankly, isn't the security
of a deuridium shipment
a little over his head?
l mean, he was chatting about it
in the bar
with that Ferengi, Quark.
lf l could overhear it,
so could half a dozen others.
lt's hard to keep a secret
in a place like this,
Lieutenant.
lt's not a starship.
l understand that.
l'm sure almost everyone knows
about the shipment by now.
Odo was probably making sure
that Quark knows
we know he knows.
lt's not the way they taught us
at the Academy, is it, sir?
lf you want my opinion...
Actually, l don't.
You and l are guests
of the Bajorans, Lieutenant.
You don't have to forget what
you learned at the Academy
you just don't throw it
in anyone's face here.
lf you're really smart,
you might even learn
a few new things about station
security from our Constable.
Clear?
Very clear, sir.
Now, regarding the shipment.
We've been made aware
of a possible Kobliad plot
to hijack the deuridium.
You and Odo ought to have
a talk with Kajada
the Kobliad Security Officer
who arrived yesterday.
Um, before we get started,
l want to apologize
for us getting off
on the wrong foot.
Think nothing of it.
Listen, l know
this is your bailiwick.
l don't mean to be
throwing my weight around.
No hard feelings.
None at all.
Just because l'm
from Starfleet Security
doesn't mean l don't
respect your opinion.
How about showing me
what you got
and l'll see if there's
anything we can work with?
Lieutenant, you're welcome
to see my plans
but l assure you,
l've taken every precaution
regarding the shipment.
However, if you have
any suggestions
l'd be happy to hear them.
What?!
Odo to Ops.
Go ahead.
Major, are we having
some sort of computer problem?
Everything in active memory
has been accessed and purged.
That's impossible.
Oh, it's possible.
Vantika did the exact
same thing on Rigel Vll.
l know Vantika.
l've learned to think
as he thinks.
Kajada, our best
evidence suggests
Vantika stopped
thinking two days ago.
He's alive
and he's on board this station.
And his first thought
when he came on board
was to plan a way
to access your security files
on the deuridium shipment,
which is exactly what he's done.
Even if he was alive,
it doesn't make sense
that he would purge
an entire computer memory
to go after a single file.
lt makes perfect sense.
Try to access the single file
and you'd be stopped
by a dozen
different lock-outs
that l put in to protect it.
But you would never
consider locking out
the active memory
of your entire system.
lt would make it impossible
to use the computers at all.
So that's where
you're vulnerable.
But how would he gain access?
ln the past, he's used
a subspace shunt.
lt would be attached
to a secondary system
something that runs
throughout the entire facility
but isn't covered by security.
The lighting controls.
Or the replicators.
l'm showing an unauthorized tap
into the computer system.
A temperature control panel,
level 21, section 10.
-Security to level...
-Security...
To L-21, S-10.
We're looking
for a subspace crossover link
to the computer system.
Acknowledged.
Tell them to be careful.
Vantika undoubtedly
equipped the shunt
with an auto-destruct system.
You know that for certain,
without having to check?
l know Vantika.
Miss Kajada, l must admit
l'm having a tough time
with your theory.
Then you're making
a fatal mistake.
Three passengers
were on your ship.
Two bodies are in our morgue.
Unless the ghost
of Vantika is...
Don't patronize me, Commander!
lsn't it more likely
that some accomplice did this?
Rao Vantika is obsessed
with his own survival.
He's prolonged his life
through the use of drugs
cryogenics, transplants.
As a medical supervisor
in a high-security penitentiary
he used prisoners
for his illegal experiments
in cellular longevity.
He's organized raids
on government labs
to steal bio-regenerative
research.
l promise you, when he started
that fire on board my ship
he had a plan to survive.
l'm not sure what that plan was,
but l'm convinced it succeeded.
Doctor, how soon before we get
the results of the DNA trace?
l sent it
to Starfleet Command yesterday.
They'll have to coordinate
with Kobliad Security.
l'd say another 12 hours.
Until then, we will operate
under the assumption
that Vantika is alive.
Commander.
May l have a word with you?
What's on your mind?
My resignation.
You're overreacting.
Oh, so you already
know about this.
Yes. Lieutenant Primmin
mentioned to me...
You asked me to stay
in charge of security
when you took command
of this station.
l did not ask you.
Constable, no one knows
this station like you do.
Oh, yes.
l've noticed that.
''Constable.''
lt's very cute.
lt's an expression of affection.
l believe Major Kira
was the first...
l don't need anyone's affection.
l do need clear jurisdiction
or l am out.
l like you, Odo.
l like to know
where a man stands.
There's never been
any question of that with you.
l need you here.
No Starfleet officer
can do the job you do.
You've got that straight.
But you have to realize
that Starfleet
is not going to take command
of a station in deep space
without assigning some security
to protect its interests.
Understandable.
You're going to have to work
with Primmin.
The two of you have to find
a way to get along.
Tell him that.
l already have.
Who's in charge?
ln joint operations
like this one...
you are.
l can live
with that arrangement.
What have you got, Dax?
l'm not exactly sure yet.
l finished the sweep
of Kajada's ship.
No anomalous readings,
but l did notice one odd thing.
What's that?
Someone tried to break
into the ship's cargo bay.
Since it's been docked?
Kira confirmed
that there was no damage
to the cargo area
when they brought it in.
What do you think
they were after?
This, maybe.
l found it in Vantika's
personal belongings.
What is it?
A map of the humanoid brain.
You call this clean?
l've already found three coins
on the floor up here.
Who knows what else
there might be.
Somebody may have lost
some valuable jewelry
or something.
Fine.
Never mind.
l'll do it myself.
And l'll keep it myself.
Leave!
You just can't find
good help anymore.
Have you made
the preparations?
Preparations?
What preparations?
The deuridium shipment.
You were to hire
mercenaries to help me.
Help you...
but you can't be Vantika.
l told you to expect me
at this hour.
Yes, and l contacted
some very reliable
soldiers of fortune
in anticipation of your arrival.
But l was told you were dead.
Almost...
but not quite.
You wanted to see me?
Kajada.
l'll be right with you.
There.
Now, remember, next time,
lift with your back straight
and use the anti-gravity
generator.
l'm sorry.
Come in.
l have the DNA scan results.
l thought you might
like to see them.
ln fact, l tried
to call you last night.
But you never responded
to the com.
Um, l have a little
trouble sleeping.
Last night was particularly bad
so l used an alpha wave inducer
to help me.
Oh, you should
be careful with those.
They're only meant
for occasional use.
The scan results, Doctor.
Oh, yeah.
There wasn't even a trace
of diploid variation.
lt's definitely not a clone.
Positive identification--
Rao Vantika.
They must have
overlooked something.
Dax to Bashir.
Yes, Jadzia?
l need some medical advice.
Can you come to my lab?
l'll be right there.
Bashir out.
Every conceivable test
has been done, Kajada.
Here's the hypothesis.
The body dies,
the consciousness lives on.
ln another brain?
Possible?
Well, the closest thing
l've encountered
is synaptic pattern
displacement
but that's never been done
by a non-Vulcan.
l'm convinced Vantika
was working on it.
There are over 70 different
computer simulations
in his file.
All involve identifying
neural energy patterns
and storing them
in different areas of the brain.
Well, there's plenty of room.
A humanoid only uses
a small portion of the brain.
What if another entity
shared the unused portion?
Hypothetically...
Vantika's consciousness could be
occupying someone else's brain
while he waits
for the deuridium to arrive.
But whose?
Kajada.
They're both Kobliad.
What better place to hide
than in the mind
of your worst enemy?
lt doesn't make sense.
She's been doing
everything she can
to convince us
that Vantika is alive.
lf Vantika's controlling her
why would he call
attention to himself?
We're not suggesting
he's controlling her.
This is all theoretical
but to extend the logic,
there's no reason to believe
she'd even be aware
of his presence.
Like a stowaway on a ship--
the pilot's at the helm
but someone else
is along for the ride.
Would an examination
of Kajada confirm any of this?
We don't know
what we're looking for yet.
We still have to identify
a method of transfer first.
l could assign some personnel
to maintain continuous
surveillance on Kajada.
We're already stretched
to the limit
preparing for the shipment.
Why don't l just
set the computer
to track her movements
and alert us if she goes
near a secured area?
At the very least
she has to be left out
of our security plans.
She won't like that.
l'm afraid we have no choice.
What do we tell her?
Nothing.
She'll figure it out.
When she does, send her to me.
The computer security
codes have been changed.
l've been denied access.
Why?
Because l ordered it.
What kind of fool are you?
My own special variety.
l'm the only one here
who has experience with Vantika.
l'm sorry.
l believe it's necessary
at this point to restrict access
to the security files
to four people:
myself, Lieutenant Primmin,
Major Kira and Commander Sisko.
When is the shipment
scheduled to arrive?
l can't give you
that information.
What about this Ferengi-- Quark?
What about him?
From what l understand
he has his hands
into everything around here.
ls he under surveillance?
l always keep an eye on him.
l hope so
because he's exactly the kind
that Vantika would
use in his plans.
Everything has been
taken care of.
That's what you said
about the job on Vener Vll.
You should thank me
for Vener Vll.
You got paid, didn't you?
We almost got killed.
A normal risk
in your line of work.
when we work for you.
That's for certain.
So, when do we
meet this Kobliad?
When he decides
it's appropriate.
All right, then,
a better question--
when do we get paid?
When the job is completed,
of course.
Not acceptable.
We'll require an advance payment
of 70%.
Durg, wake up.
This is Quark
you're talking to, remember?
All past debts
have been settled.
They'll never be settled.
You'd still be rotting
in a Cardassian jail
if l hadn't...
Can you speak?
Pushed.
Vantika.
l can't keep her conscious
any longer, Commander.
lf she moves too much
she could suffer
permanent paralysis.
Did you see anybody
behind her?
l just heard the scream
and looked up.
She fell from the balcony.
What was she doing
up there, anyway?
She had an odd feeling
you might be
helping someone hijack
this deuridium shipment.
l resent the inference.
lt's not an inference.
lt's a definite suspicion.
Was anyone else in the bar?
Anyone else?
At the time of the accident.
No, just me.
Just tidying up
which, if you'll excuse me,
l really must finish.
Not so fast, Quark.
l want to take a look
at that third floor
before you get rid
of all the evidence.
Be my guest
but l'm telling you,
she was alone up there.
And she had no business
invading the privacy
of a law-abiding member
of the community.
What do you think, Doctor?
Could this have been
a suicide attempt?
Well, l haven't
noticed any indication
of suicidal behavior,
but then, who knows
what the effect of sharing
one's brain might be.
l'd still like
some confirmation of that.
l'll have to tend
to her injuries
before l conduct
any brain scan.
But until we find
the transfer method
Vantika used
l'm not even sure
what to look for.
Computer, location
of Lieutenant Dax.
Lieutenant Dax
is in the stasis room.
Find something
under his fingernails?
Not yet.
What are you looking for?
Confirmation of a theory,
l hope.
l've been asking myself
why would anyone induct
a bioelectrical charge
into a glial cell?
A question l have
always wondered about.
Well, it might make sense
if you wanted to send
a bio-coded message
along the glial cells
of someone's nervous system
all the way to the brain.
My guess is
that's what Vantika
was trying to do.
Using his fingernails?
Frankly, l can't think
of another way
he could have delivered
the bio-coded message.
He must have used
a very weak electrical charge
or the sensors on Kajada's ship
would have detected it.
ldeally, he would have injected
the bio-coded message directly
into his victim's skin
but there were
no hyposprays or needles
anywhere on the ship.
A microscopic generator.
You're suggesting he
stored his consciousness
in that thing?
His neural patterns encoded
as bioelectrical pulses.
He could have placed that device
under his nail months ago
just in case he needed an escape
route in an emergency--
his last resort before death.
Will this show up
in Kajada?
Now that we know
what we're looking for
we should be able to confirm it
with a glial scan.
Do it as soon as Bashir
stabilizes her.
Nice work.
Confirm that each
distribution amplifier
is at 100% efficiency.
lf there's more
than a .03% fall-off
replace it.
And that won't mean a thing
if the power waveguide
outlets fail.
Double-check them.
You better make this
the last check.
We've only got an hour.
Where's Primmin?
l thought he was with you.
l sent him to help you make
the final security sweep
of the docking area.
He has not been here
all morning.
l won't be going with you.
l'm simply a middleman,
a facilitator.
A profit monger.
And proud of it.
How did you get your hands
on a Federation runabout, Quark?
l can't take credit for that.
Your employer
has somehow managed
to arrange security access.
When do we meet this employer?
His message said he'd be
waiting for us on board.
Uh...
uh, l'm terribly sorry.
We seem to have made
a wrong turn.
We-we didn't mean
to disturb you
Doctor.
Not at all, gentlemen.
l've been expecting you.
Julian?
Computer,
location of Dr. Bashir.
Dr. Bashir is in the lnfirmary.
What the hell are
you doing in there?
l told you to sweep
the docking bay again.
l took a cue from you.
From me?
You understood the logic
of Vantika's MO
when he downloaded
the computer memory--
avoid the single file,
attack the system.
l'm not following.
Vantika has to know
that all of our security efforts
will be focused
on the docking ring.
And...?
l figured,
if he holds true to form
that's not where
he'll try to hurt us.
So l ran a diagnostic
on all the systems
that could shut down
our whole defense array.
l've already done
that twice today.
l know. l didn't find
anything, either.
But then l went
to the backup systems
and l found a glitch there
l couldn't explain.
And l tracked it back
to the waste reclamation system
where nobody would ever
think to look
because it's considered
nonessential.
And l found this.
Another subspace
crossover shunt
just like the one Vantika used
when he tapped
into the computer.
And it's set to feed back
into the primary command
and control functions.
This would have shut us
down for close to an hour.
Long enough for him
to grab that freighter
and warp it to who knows where.
Yes, Major?
The Norkova's just come
through the wormhole.
Requesting permission to dock.
Let's go to
a Security Alert Yellow.
What bay do you
have assigned in the plan?
Number Eight.
Odo...
maintain a visible contingent
of security at Bay Eight.
But l'm sending the Norkova
to the second backup.
Bay 12.
l'll send
additional forces to 12.
Commander, your
Lieutenant Primmin there
just saved us all
a lot of problems.
Another subspace crossover
that would have crippled us
long enough for them to
escape with your deuridium.
Odo, did you deploy
a runabout
to escort the Norkova?
No.
Then how come the Rio Grande's
going out to meet it?
On screen.
Benjamin, Julian's missing.
Missing?
His combadge
was in the infirmary.
l can't find him anywhere.
Computer, who authorized access
to the Runabout Rio Grande?
Authorization:
access code 4-1-2-1.
Dr. Julian Bashir.
lt's safe.
Shields up.
Done.
Secure the rest of the ship.
Be sure to account
for all 12 members of the crew.
lf they resist, kill them.
Enter the new course.
Aye.
The station has locked
a tractor beam on us.
But that's not possible.
They should be shut down by now.
Well, they're not.
They're hailing us.
Hailing... us?
Engage engines, full impulse.
We're not going anywhere
with a tractor beam on us.
Do it!
Full impulse engaged.
The tractor beam is holding.
But they won't be able
to pull us in.
We can't just sit here
and wait.
What do you intend to do?
Open a channel.
l'm Benjamin Sisko,
Commander of DS9.
Rao Vantika is my name.
But l assume you
know that already.
l want to talk to Dr. Bashir.
Unfortunately, he's not
available at the moment.
ls he all right?
His body is--
how do you humans say it?
Fit as a fiddle.
Looks rather good on me,
don't you think?
What have you done
to his mind, Vantika?
lt was necessary to render him
unconscious for the time being.
However, l might consider
leaving his body
and returning him to you.
But first, you must release
your tractor beam.
l can't do that.
lf you don't,
l'll take this vessel to warp.
The tractor beam
would rip apart your ship.
And you and everybody on board
would be killed.
Exactly.
So if you care at all
about the welfare of your doctor
you will release
your hold on us.
You have one minute to decide.
Can we get
a transporter lock on him?
Negative.
Their shields are up.
Suggestions?
A small ship like a runabout
might be able
to get close enough
to overload
their shield generators
with directed phaser fire.
We used to do it to Cardassian
freighters all the time.
But you'd be risking
a hull breach
and with all the deuridium
on board...
He's right.
We can't risk releasing
deuridium into the system.
Every populated area
would have to be evacuated.
Dax, is there
any way to disrupt
Vantika's control over Bashir?
l have an exact model
of Vantika's
neural energy patterns.
lf l can design
an electromagnetic pulse
to disrupt those patterns
Julian might emerge.
We still need a way
to get it there.
Could we run it
along the tractor beam
at the same frequency
as their shields?
The pulse would resonate
off the shields
and create a reflected EM
field inside the ship.
He's hailing us.
l need some time.
l'll give you as much as l can.
On screen.
Have you decided?
lf l permit you to leave
what guarantee do l have
that you'll return Dr. Bashir?
Oh, you're far too ready
to capitulate, Commander.
Would you be planning
a rescue attempt, perhaps?
l'm only interested
in the safety of my doctor.
You insult my intelligence.
Prepare to go to warp.
You've gone to great lengths
to survive, Vantika.
l don't think you're ready
to kill yourself.
And l don't think you are ready
to risk spreading deuridium
all over this system.
Ready to engage warp engines.
You must be crazy!
l want no part of this!
No more middlemen, Sisko.
No more delays.
What's it to be?
All right.
We're prepared to release
the tractor beam.
Dax?
Ready.
Do it!
Dr. Bashir!
Answer me.
Bashir!
Yes?
What?
Doctor, lower the shields!
What... what shields?
Where am l?
l'll explain later.
Lower the shields now!
The shields are down.
Get him out of there!
Energizing.
lt's okay.
lt's...
me.
l've programmed
this transporter
to isolate any glial cells with
Vantika's neural patterns...
and to beam them from Julian
into this
micro-containment field.
Once they're out,
he should be back to normal.
l'm only reading
human neural patterns.
He's clear.
Oh, l have the worst headache.
Dr. Bashir, l'm so sorry
for all of this.
Well, l suppose we should
have listened to you
when you said he was alive.
There was no way
for you to control
what he was doing to you.
l'm afraid l don't remember it.
Actually, l feel
quite humiliated.
No one blames you, Doctor.
lt wasn't you.
lt was that.
What do you intend to do
with it?
May l assume that you've
returned custody
of the prisoner to me,
Commander Sisko?
The prisoner?
What's left of him.
Good.