Ah.
Tarkalean tea again, Doctor?
Yes, and you're drinking
Rokassa juice
aren't you, Garak?
How did you know?
The odor is unmistakable.
So it is.
Rokassa juice soothes my nerves.
l had a very demanding
customer today--
a Bajoran engineer who comes
to the shop constantly
just to plague me.
You know, l've always
wondered about that--
about who your steady
customers really are.
l can't imagine Bajorans
frequenting a shop
run by a Cardassian.
l like to think
that my expertise
and willingness to serve
overcome any general resentment
any of my clientele may have.
Ah... and perhaps
your expertise
and willingness to serve
go so far as to establish
a certain... trust
between you and your customers?
Trust is very important.
And once they trust you,
they're much more open with you
and they tell you things.
Really, Doctor, must we
always play this game?
l'm no more a spy
than you are...
A doctor.
l'm afraid
you really do allow
your imagination
to run away with you.
What else can l say
to finally convince you
that l'm just...
Plain, simple Garak?
Precisely.
Now, there's something
you don't see every day.
There's a table.
Have a seat.
l'll get us all
some refreshment.
Well, that was odd.
Do you know him?
On the contrary.
l've never seen him before
in my life.
l hope l'm not intruding
but l couldn't help
noticing what a...
what a handsome young man
you have here.
l'm sorry l'm late.
The damnedest thing
just happened.
Garak the tailor was attacked.
Attacked where?
At the Replimat.
He was bitten on the hand.
Another unsatisfied customer?
He always cuts
the pants too long.
Actually, it was a boy--
a Cardassian boy.
l wasn't aware we had
any Cardassian children
on the station.
We don't.
He's just arrived
on a Bajoran transport
with an adult Bajoran
who says he's his father.
The boy was probably
one of the orphans left behind
when the Cardassians pulled out.
We had no choice
but to take care of them.
You have an incoming
subspace transmission
from Cardassia, Commander.
lt's Gul Dukat.
ln my office.
Commander, it's been brought
to my attention
that the sole Cardassian
living on your station
has been assaulted.
l'm surprised how quickly
the news reached you, Dukat.
l only heard about it myself
a minute ago.
Well, is it true he was attacked
by a Cardassian boy brought
to the station by a Bajoran?
A Cardassian boy appears
to be involved, yes.
Exactly as l feared.
Exactly as l've been
warning my colleagues.
Warning them?
Cardassian war orphans,
Commander.
Abandoned when we left Bajor.
lt's a disgrace
and obviously, these
children are being raised
to hate their own kind.
This incident is proof.
You're assuming a lot
from one incident.
Am l?
Then why would this boy
attack poor Garak?
An amiable fellow,
if ever there was one.
lf you'd like,
l'll try to find out.
That would be most
appreciated, Commander.
l need to find out everything
l can about this boy
so that l can use his story in
my fight to bring these orphans
back to their homeland.
This is a tragedy
that all of Cardassia is
going to have to address.
We didn't come here
to cause trouble.
Has this Garak
filed a complaint?
No, but the Cardassian officials
asked that we look
into the incident.
l wish they'd shown
as much concern
as when they left my boy
and dozens like him
to fend for themselves.
How did you come to adopt him?
My wife and l felt that Rugal
shouldn't suffer
for crimes committed by others.
But why would he attack
another Cardassian?
That Cardassian should have
minded his own business.
Garak was only trying
to be friendly.
The boy seemed terrified
of him on sight.
The Cardassians are suggesting
that the Bajorans
are raising these orphans
to hate their own people.
To hate Cardassians?
lt shouldn't be too hard,
should it?
We told him the truth,
Commander.
The truth about what Cardassia
did to Bajor.
He needed to know.
And for that,
l make no apologies.
To us... he isn't even
one of them anymore.
He isn't Cardassian.
He's Bajoran.
And we love him
just as if he was
our own flesh and blood.
All right, here we go.
Here we go.
Come on now, baby, come on.
Dabo!
There's nothing quite so
depressing as a winning streak
that won't stop streaking.
Dabo!
Oh...
lt would appear as if
you have this game
all figured out.
Dabo!
Dabo is a passion of mine.
l remember you.
You're Doctor...
Bashir.
Bashir, yes.
How's the Cardassian?
Still has all his fingers,
l presume.
Yes... luckily there
were no broken bones.
l've never seen a boy
take a bite out of a man's hand
like that.
He's a strange boy, Rugal.
Do you know the family well?
Dabo!
Do you?
Look, this is really
none of my business.
Well, you were a witness.
l just want to get my facts
right for the medical report.
l'd really rather
you asked someone else.
Frankly, l don't
understand your attitude.
All l asked
was if you know them well.
Well enough.
l heard the father was
looking for a new job
several months ago,
and l offered to help.
l visited them on Bajor
several times.
Did you find anything troubling?
lt must be torture for that boy,
living like that.
Hated by people he thinks
of as his parents.
Told day after day,
he's worthless Cardassian scum.
Beaten if he even
looks the wrong way.
Rugal is their revenge--
their revenge against
all Cardassians.
lt is not true.
lt is not true!
Rugal will tell you.
We have not mistreated him.
ls this some Cardassian...
There will be ample opportunity
to go over the matter in detail
but during the investigation,
we'd like for Rugal
to stay with our schoolteacher,
Mrs. O'Brien.
She's expecting him now.
What if l refuse?
Then l'll have
to call security
and have them remove him
from your quarters.
l don't think either
of us wants that.
Why?
lt will be all right.
l didn't do anything wrong!
l know, l know.
lt will be all right.
l didn't do anything wrong.
Nobody's accusing you
of a crime, Rugal.
You're not being arrested.
My name is Commander Sisko.
l believe you already
know Dr. Bashir.
Hello, Rugal.
l'm sure all of this
will be straightened out
in a day or two.
lf you want to visit with
your father tomorrow, you can.
Go on, Rugal.
We'll talk tomorrow.
They won't hurt you.
They're humans.
They're not Cardassians.
Actually, something good did
come out of all of this, Garak.
Oh?
lf it hadn't happened
we'd never have discovered
Rugal's situation.
And a bite on the hand
is certainly
worth saving a boy's
life, wouldn't you say?
l suppose it depends
on whose hand.
Just joking, Doctor.
Perhaps it might
even help Gul Dukat
in his efforts to resolve
the entire war orphan
predicament.
l beg your pardon?
Gul Dukat.
He called Commander Sisko
right after this happened.
Apparently, he was quite
concerned with your well-being.
You never mentioned
you were friends.
You said Dukat is doing
something about war orphans?
He wants to bring them
all home from Bajor.
Does he?
Am l missing something?
Tell me, Doctor...
is there a single trait
you would ascribe
to me and my fellow Cardassians?
Would it not be
our attention to detail?
Do you think we simply forgot
about those poor little orphans
when we left Bajor?
Do you think they simply
slipped from our minds?
And who, would you guess
was in charge of the Cardassian
withdrawal from Bajor?
l don't know how to thank you.
Don't thank me too quickly,
Dukat.
The boy could be returned
to his adoptive parents.
After the accusations
this businessman has made...
That's all it is for the moment,
an accusation.
We would not take kindly
to the boy being returned
to the Bajorans.
However, l have
complete confidence
in your ability to be thorough,
Commander.
And if there's
anything l can do...
As a matter of fact, there is.
lf it is decided the boy is
to be returned to Cardassia
to whom would we return him?
lt might help to find out
if he still has
any living relatives.
l was going to suggest
that you forward us
a sample of the boy's DNA
and we'll run it through
our data banks immediately.
We'll send it right away.
Excuse me, Gul Dukat.
l have a question.
Doctor... Bashir, isn't it?
Yes. lsn't it true
that you were in charge
of the evacuation of Bajor?
Yes, l was.
Then it would have been
your responsibility to ensure
that these orphans were,
in fact, part of that evacuation
yet you chose
to leave them behind.
Why?
l did not choose to leave
them behind, Doctor.
l was ordered
to leave them behind.
Ordered.
By whom?
By the civilian leaders...
Excuse me...
but, if l understand
the Cardassian political
system correctly
civilian leaders
have no direct authority
over military officers.
Who's been tutoring you
in Cardassian
social studies, Doctor?
Your old friend, Garak.
Well, then perhaps you should
remind my old friend Garak
the withdrawal of Bajor
was a decision
made by the civilian leaders--
one which l clearly opposed.
And yes, they made the decision
to leave the orphans behind
a decision
l've regretted ever since.
Thank you for your concern,
Doctor.
Good day, Commander.
He's lying.
ls that an opinion, or do you
have evidence to support it?
l have Garak.
Garak?
He seems to think
there's more going on here
than we realize.
What exactly
does he think is going on?
l'm not sure.
He doesn't actually tell me
what he really thinks.
l sort of have to deduce it.
Ah, so, you deduced that Garak
thinks Dukat is lying
about something
you're not sure of
and you proceeded to interrupt
my conversation to confront him
about whatever that might be.
l'm sorry, Commander.
lt just seemed an opportune...
Don't apologize.
lt's been the high point
of my day.
Don't do it again.
Why would Garak
want to undermine Gul Dukat?
l'm not really sure.
l don't think he likes
Gul Dukat very much.
l'd like to ask Garak
about this myself.
Have him in my office
at 2100 hours.
Yes, sir.
Hi.
Here, let me.
Oh, thanks.
Good idea.
What?
Well, three settings.
l assume you sent Molly over
to stay with the Fredericks.
She's asleep.
She and Rugal
played all afternoon.
He wore her out.
You let them play together?
Why not?
The boy almost bit
somebody's hand off.
l was with them all afternoon.
He's not like that.
He's really very gentle.
''Gentle'' was bred out of these
Cardassians a long time ago.
You know...
that was a very ugly thing
you just said.
l only said...
l don't need to hear it twice.
Rugal, dinner's ready.
l hope you like it...
Keiko...
darling, what is it?
l found some Cardassian recipes
in the memory bank
of our food replicator.
lt's a stew
made with Cardassian
zabo meat.
l thought Rugal might enjoy
a dish that's popular
on his own world.
Can't sleep?
What are they going
to do with me?
Oh, l'm not sure.
You might have something
to say about that, you know.
You should be telling
Commander Sisko what you want.
l want to go home.
Well, he'll understand that.
You're a Cardassian
and they should have taken
you home when they left.
No, l mean home.
To Bajor.
lt must be tough for you.
You know, living on Bajor?
Why?
Being Cardassian.
That's not my fault!
l was born that way.
That's not what l meant.
There's nothing wrong
with being a Cardassian.
Yes, there is.
Who taught you that?
lt's the truth.
Everybody knows it.
How do your parents
feel about Cardassians?
They hate them.
Why would you want to live
with someone who hates you?
They hate other Cardassians,
not me.
My parents have never
done anything wrong to me.
Oh, come on,
even l got my bottom
whacked by my dad once or twice.
Not me.
My parents follow
the teachings of the Prophets.
What do you think
of Cardassians?
Me?
Well, l... l can't say, really.
Why not?
Well, you can't judge
a whole race of people.
You can't hate all Cardassians
or all Klingons
or all humans.
l've met some Cardassians
l didn't like.
And l've met some l did.
Like you.
Do you know how many Bajorans
the Cardassians murdered
during the occupation?
Over ten million.
We had a test on it in school.
l wish l wasn't Cardassian.
Come, Doctor, get dressed.
We need to be going.
Going?
Going where?
To Bajor.
l assume this couldn't wait
until morning?
No, sir, l...
l need to use a runabout.
l'm waiting.
lt's Garak, sir.
He wants to go to Bajor.
Bajor? For what?
He wouldn't tell me.
Well, by all means.
Will one runabout be enough?
Ops to Sisko.
Go ahead.
Commander, there's an urgent
communication for you
from Gul Dukat.
l'm sorry to disturb you
at such a late hour, Commander
but thanks to the DNA gene type
you sent us
we've discovered the boy
is actually the son
of one of our most prominent
politicians-- Kotran Pa'Dar.
When was Pa'Dar on Bajor?
Over eight years ago.
He was Exarch for a Cardassian
settlement there
and the boy was believed
to have died
in a Bajoran terrorist attack.
Has he been told
his son is alive?
Of course!
As you can imagine,
he's overwhelmed with joy.
He's already on his way
to the station to reclaim him.
lt's not that simple.
l don't understand.
The boy wants
to go back to Bajor.
Back?
To live
with the same brutal people?
l can't find any evidence
to support that accusation.
l can't even find the man
who made it in the first place.
Well, nevertheless
once the boy finds out
his real father's alive
surely he'll change his mind.
And even if he doesn't, it would
be in the boy's best interests.
We'll just have to see
what happens
when Pa'Dar gets here.
Sisko out.
lt can't be just
a coincidence, sir.
Garak must have heard
about Pa'Dar
before he woke me up.
What could he be
looking for on Bajor?
There's only one way
to find out.
Excuse me, is this the Tozhat
Resettlement Center?
Yes.
l'm Dr. Bashir
from Federation Command
at Deep Space 9.
l've been trying to find
some information
on a Cardassian war orphan
who was apparently placed
for adoption here.
Yes, the Bajorans have
opened their hearts
to many abandoned children.
The boy's name was Rugal
and the Bajoran who adopted him
was named Proka Migdal.
l don't recognize
either of the names.
What was it you were trying
to find out about them?
Yes... exactly what are we
trying to find out about them?
The circumstances surrounding
the young man's adoption.
lt took place
about eight years ago.
The Cardassians were still here.
You'll never find anything
from back then.
Oh, the Cardassians
are quite meticulous
record keepers, madam.
They've taught many worlds,
including this one
how to keep records.
l find it difficult to believe
that none exist
from that period.
Certainly computer entries
were made on a regular basis.
l wouldn't know.
l wasn't a volunteer then.
l was in the underground.
Really?
Perhaps we have met.
Look, can we just
check your computers?
Our computers don't work.
l can't get a technician
to come out.
We're not exactly
a top priority.
Perhaps l can be of service.
You can fix computers?
Oh, l dabble with isolinear
data subprocessors.
lt's... a hobby of mine.
l continue
to underestimate you, Garak.
Oh, it's no more difficult
than sewing on a button,
actually.
Excuse me.
You carry this
everywhere with you, do you?
A simple tailoring tool.
You'd be surprised how often
someone needs
their pants let out.
Oh, it's not there.
What's not there?
Rugal's name, his father's
name-- none of it.
You managed to find eight-
year-old files that quickly?
Oh, it's simply a question
of knowing what you're
looking for, Doctor.
Excuse me.
Now, it's either been misfiled
or under a wrong name
or this is entirely
the wrong resettlement center.
l'm not going to another
district until l know...
That won't be necessary.
We can access the files
to this entire province
from here and download
them into a data clip.
But that'll be
thousands of files.
Tens of thousands, actually.
Excuse me, sir.
Have you come to take us
back to Cardassia?
l'm afraid not, child.
Come, Doctor.
l believe you'll find
your computer system
fully functional now, madam.
Computer, set up a data bank
cross-referencing
age groups, sex
year of adoption...
Computer, disregard that request
and shut down all engines.
l'm sorry you're upset
about the orphans.
Children without parents
have no status
in Cardassian society.
The situation
is most unfortunate
but l don't make the rules.
But you do play the game,
don't you, Garak?
And there is a game being played
right now as we speak,
isn't there?
There are always games, Doctor.
The trouble is,
l don't have the slightest idea
what this game is all about.
So you're going to tell me
what's going on
inside that plain
and simple head of yours
my Cardassian friend
or we're going to sit here
until we rot.
Tell me, Doctor...
why do you think
the Cardassians left Bajor?
Gul Dukat said it was a decision
made by your civilian leaders.
And isn't it interesting
that one of Cardassia's
most notable civilian leaders
has recently entered
this scenario?
Rugal's father?
You're saying Kotran Pa'Dar
was involved in the decision
to evacuate Bajor?
Very good, Doctor!
l'm glad to see
our little get-togethers
haven't gone for naught.
Which makes him a political
enemy of Gul Dukat's
who lost his job as Prefect
when they withdrew.
And seemingly out of nowhere
Dukat takes an interest
in this orphan boy
who recently arrives
on our station
and then soon afterwards,
with Gul Dukat's assistance
we discover that the orphan boy
isn't really an orphan boy
but Pa'Dar's long-lost son.
Another coincidence?
l believe in coincidences.
Coincidences happen every day.
But l don't trust coincidences.
l am Kotran Pa'Dar.
Miles O'Brien.
Come in.
Sit down.
Where is my son?
Oh, he's with my wife.
They'll be back shortly.
l thought it might be
a good idea if we talked first.
Your son, Rugal...
At least they didn't
change his name.
When was the last time
you saw him?
On Bajor-- he had just
had his fourth birthday.
He probably doesn't
even remember me.
Does he?
l think he spent most of his
life trying to forget you.
l don't think l understand.
The boy hates everything he is.
He hates Cardassians,
he hates being a Cardassian.
Yes, l've heard those stories.
Well, l suppose after growing up
among the Bajorans...
but now that l'm back
in his life...
Well, he... may not want you
back in his life.
l am his father.
Mr. O'Brien, l know
very little about human culture.
l don't know
how you view the family.
We'd do almost anything
to protect our families.
l have a daughter myself.
She's four-- the same age
your son was when you lost him.
Then l expect you can imagine
what l'm feeling right now.
On Cardassia,
family is everything.
We care for our parents and
children with equal devotion.
ln some households
four generations
eat at the same table.
Family... is everything.
And l have failed in
my responsibility to my family.
You had no way of knowing
he was still alive.
l should have tried harder!
l should have looked everywhere!
To abandon my son, to allow him
to be raised by a Bajoran...
l have disgraced everything
that a Cardassian believes in.
Hello, Rugal.
Do you remember my face?
Even a little?
No.
Would you like to see
some pictures of you
when you were a child?
No.
Hey.
Rugal...
you have to understand.
There was nothing left of the
house after the attack.
Your mother was dead
and you...
l... cried for you, Rugal.
l missed you so much.
l could not even stay on Bajor.
lt was too close
to the happy memories of you.
lt was your own fault.
You deserved it.
You are a Cardassian.
What the Bajorans did,
they had to do.
l understand why you say that.
You can't understand!
You are a Cardassian
butcher, a butcher!
They killed your son
for your crimes.
Rugal...
You are not my father.
And l will never go
back to Cardassia.
Never.
l have no intention of allowing
a Bajoran court to rule
on the custody of my son.
You gave up custody
when you abandoned him here.
He is my natural-born child.
As Cardassian law clearly...
There is no more
Cardassian law on Bajor.
Gentlemen.
l think you may be in need
of an arbitrator to settle this.
Well, it must be someone
who is neither a Cardassian
nor a Bajoran.
What about you?
l'd be willing.
But wouldn't you have objections
because of the Federation's
relationship with Bajor?
No, Commander.
You are a father, too.
You would be acceptable to me.
Very well then.
l'll schedule a...
Odo to Commander Sisko.
Yes, Odo, what is it?
l thought you might be
interested to know.
Gul Dukat has just arrived
on the station.
Station Log, Stardate 47 177.2.
The arrival of Gul Dukat
only powers my suspicion
that we are being manipulated
in some unseen manner.
Dr. Bashir and Garak
continue to search
for anything of relevance
in the adoption files.
So far they've found nothing.
And the decision
on custody for Rugal
cannot wait much longer.
You've come a long way
just to view a custody hearing.
Pa'Dar is an eminent member
of the Civilian Assembly.
This matter has generated
a great deal of interest
at the highest levels
of our government.
So you're here representing
your government.
Not exactly.
l like to think l'm here
representing the children--
all of the children who
were abandoned on Bajor.
l want to see Rugal
reunited with his father.
Well, l'm sure Pa'Dar is
grateful for your support.
Because l was
under the impression
that you were
political adversaries.
lsn't that so, Pa'Dar?
We have disagreed in the past.
But, Commander, l don't see...
l must object, Commander.
The past is the past--
it has no relevance here.
What is relevant
are the children.
What are we going to do
about the children?
lf you don't mind, l'd like
for you to go over the events
leading up to the disappearance
of Rugal eight years ago.
How perfectly foolish of me.
Don't tell me you've decided
you were wrong.
Not after searching 7,420 files
for a misspelling.
Dukat is much smarter than that.
Than what?
Think about it, Doctor.
He would never have left
a file to be found.
Do you really think he
purged the file on Rugal?
l would have.
There was something in that file
he didn't want anybody to see.
Exactly.
We have one last chance--
to find the person
who wrote that file
in the first place.
How do you ever hope
to find him?
Her.
Her?
How do you know?
Because l've already
found her name-- Jomat Luson.
Do you remember anything
from back then, Rugal?
No.
Do you remember being adopted?
What's the first thing
you do remember?
My father teaching me
how to swim.
l know exactly the one
you're talking about.
You do?
He was the only Cardassian boy
we had at the time.
We had several girls.
Are you sure his name was Rugal?
That's what we were told.
Somebody told you his name?
Yes, that was
the most unusual thing
about his arrival.
Virtually all of the other
Cardassian children
turned in to us were found
on the streets by Bajorans.
Rugal was brought in
by a Cardassian.
A Cardassian military
officer, by any chance?
Yes, as a matter of fact,
she was.
A woman.
l don't remember her name,
but she was attached
to the command post
at Terok Nor.
ls there anything else, Doctor?
The boy accused him
of being a butcher.
He hates Cardassians, sir.
Pa'Dar was heartbroken.
l can only imagine
how l'd feel in his shoes.
Commander...
can l ask a few questions?
Chief, didn't Pa'Dar tell you
about the humiliation
he feels right now?
He said he had disgraced
everything a Cardassian
believes in.
Has news of your son's discovery
become public knowledge
on Cardassia?
The government has not chosen
to reveal it to the people yet.
What happens
when it is revealed?
lt will be the end
of my political career.
That's a shame...
especially
considering the timing.
The timing?
lsn't there an inquiry
about to begin
concerning the Cardassians
who were involved
in the attempted
military coup on Bajor?
Yes.
And isn't Gul Dukat one of
the key witness in that inquiry?
This is irrelevant
and insulting.
Commander,
you've lost control here.
Yes, it seems that l have.
l suggest we return to the issue
of the children.
All right.
Let's talk about children.
Have you ever been
to the Tozhat Resettlement
Center on Bajor
where Rugal was adopted?
Never.
Of course.
Tozhat is the province
where Pa'Dar
was stationed eight years ago.
l'm aware of that.
l've been trying to find records
of Rugal's adoption
but they're missing
from the files.
How unfortunate.
Yes, but we have found someone
who was working at the Center
at the time Rugal
was brought in.
Do you know of a Bajoran
social volunteer
named Jomat Luson?
No.
Well, Jomat Luson remembers
Rugal being brought in
by a Cardassian military officer
a woman who seemed familiar
with him-- even knew his name.
ls there a question?
The question is whether
or not this officer
deliberately left the son
of Kotran Pa'Dar
at the relocation center
with the full knowledge
that he was not an orphan.
Perhaps even with the hopes
of humiliating Pa'Dar someday.
l wouldn't know.
Well, would you happen
to know, then, of a base
known during the occupation
as Terok Nor?
Terok Nor?
lt was here, this space station.
Jomat Luson clearly recalls
that the officer
who brought in Rugal
was attached to Terok Nor.
Gul Dukat!
Who was the commanding officer
of Terok Nor eight years ago?
For the record
the commanding officer
of Terok Nor eight years ago
was Gul Dukat.
Station Log, Stardate 47 178.3.
After long and difficult
deliberations
l have decided to allow Pa'Dar
to take his son
back to Cardassia.
Although l am convinced
his Bajoran foster parents
treated him with love
Rugal has been the clear victim
in this conspiracy.
l believe it's time
for his healing to begin.
Your doctor has given me
the leverage l need, Commander.
Leverage?
Dukat will never
allow these events
to be made public now
and l certainly won't
choose to discuss them.
-A stalemate.
You've helped me salvage
my political career.
l won't forget that.
Perhaps you will
use your influence
to help other Cardassian
orphans on Bajor.
Well, yes, we'll see.
Remember what l said.
lf you ever want to come
back and visit them
just let me know
and l'll arrange it.
Hello, Rugal.
Ready to go?
l suppose it'll take time.
But there's one more question
l haven't figured out, Garak.
Why did you want
to expose Dukat?
What's the truth
about you and him?
Truth, Doctor, is in
the eye of the beholder.
l never tell the truth
because l don't believe
there is such a thing.
That's why l prefer
the straight-line simplicity
of cutting cloth.
So you're not going to tell me.
But you don't need me
to tell you, my friend.
Just notice the details.
They're scattered like crumbs
all over this table
we regularly share.
Until next time.