What a waste of a morning.
That Galipotan freighter
that was scheduled
to be here at 0700
still hasn't arrived.
Oh, well, that's the price
for doing business
with a culture
that refuses to even acknowledge
the concept of time.
Though l must say,
they make magnificent sweaters.
l hope l'm not
boring you, Doctor.
Oh, not at all.
No, l-l was just
up late last night.
Entertaining one
of your lady friends?
Unfortunately not.
No, l was reading
the last few chapters
of The Never-ending Sacrifice.
lsn't it superb?
Without a doubt
the finest Cardassian
novel ever written.
l'll take your word for it.
So, you didn't enjoy it?
Well, l-l thought
it was interesting.
Maybe a little dull in parts.
Oh, wonderful!
At this rate, we'll be
done eating lunch
just in time for dinner.
Well, there's always Quark's.
True, but l'm really
not in the mood
for noisy, crowded
and vulgar today.
l suppose the Klingon restaurant
is out of the question.
l can't believe
that l'm having lunch
with a man who thinks
The Never-ending
Sacrifice is dull.
l just thought the story got a
little redundant after a while.
l mean, the author's
supposed to be chronicling
seven generations
of a single family
but he tells the same story
over and over again.
All of his characters
lead selfless lives
of duty to the state,
grow old and die.
Then, the next generation
comes along
and does it all over again.
But that's exactly the point,
Doctor.
The repetitive epic
is the most elegant form
in Cardassian literature
and The Never-ending Sacrifice
is its greatest achievement.
But none of his characters
ever really come alive.
And there's more to life
than duty to the state.
A Federation viewpoint
if ever l heard one.
This is ridiculous.
Can't you just move
to the front of the line?
Tell them it's a medical
emergency or something.
We'll be there in a minute.
Look, maybe if you
lent me another book
by a different writer...
lt would only be
a waste of time.
When it comes to art,
you're obviously a prisoner
of Federation dogma
and human prejudice.
l'm sorry you feel that way.
l was just trying...
Are you all right?
l'm fine.
You don't look fine.
Your skin is clammy
and your pupils have contracted.
l assure you,
l'm in perfect health.
Now you were asking
about other Cardassian books.
Something maybe
a little more access...
Perfect health.
Then Cardassian standards
must be a little lower
than mine.
Come on.
Doctor, what do you
think you're doing?
l'm taking you to the lnfirmary.
That won't be necessary.
Well, maybe not,
but humor me.
Frankly, Doctor...
l'm a little tired
of humoring you.
Now, there's nothing
wrong with me
that a little peace
and privacy wouldn't cure.
Now, if you'll excuse me
l seem to have lost my appetite.
What was that all about?
l have no idea.
Can you tell
what's wrong with it?
ln my expert medical opinion
l'd say it's... sick.
l know that, but why is it sick?
l'm a doctor, not a botanist.
Did you ask Professor O'Brien?
Keiko's at a hydroponics
conference on Rigel lV.
She won't be back for a week.
And none of your past hosts
have had any experience
with plants?
Daxes have never
been much on gardening.
Tobin was the only one
who ever tried
his hand at it
but he had even less
luck with plants
than he did with women.
Do you even know
where it's from?
l picked it up on Ledonia lll.
May l?
Be my guest.
Oh, that explains it.
Ledonian soil contains
a benevolent mycorrhizal fungus
that helps the native plants
retain water.
The fungus in this potting soil
has almost completely died out.
But if we can salvage
what's left
and cultivate a new batch
in the lab
that should do the trick.
Keiko would be proud of you.
lt's all there on the screen.
l only wish my humanoid patients
were as easy to treat.
Did Chief O'Brien
dislocate his shoulder again?
No, it's Garak.
Today at lunch,
he seemed as though
he was going to have
some kind of seizure.
He was having trouble breathing
and he appeared to be
in a great deal of pain.
But when l tried to get him
to come to the lnfirmary
he outright refused.
Maybe he just doesn't like
going to see the doctor.
Ah, that's not it.
lt's that damned Cardassian
evasiveness of his.
l mean, keeping me guessing
about his past is one thing
but when it comes
to his health...
l don't know.
Why can't he just tell me
what's going on?
lt sounds like you're
taking this personally.
l suppose l am.
lt's just that Garak and l
have been having
lunch together once a week
for more than a year now.
You'd think he'd come
to trust me a little.
Why should he?
lt's not like the two of you
are really friends.
Well, no, of course not.
l suppose
when it comes right down to it
l don't trust him either.
l mean, for all l know,
the man is a Cardassian spy.
Exactly.
And if he doesn't want my help
that's his prerogative.
So, l take it,
we understand each other.
Garak, how long have you
been living on this station?
Too long.
And in all that time,
have l ever let you down?
l have never done business
with you until now.
Which is why this deal
is so important to me.
l want our business relationship
to get off on the right foot.
Now relax.
You'll get your merchandise.
Soon, Quark.
l can't wait much longer.
You and Garak
going into business?
l couldn't help overhearing
your conversation.
Oh, that.
l'm helping Garak
get a new sizing scanner
for his shop.
A sizing scanner.
Not just any sizing scanner.
The best,
straight from Merak ll.
Calibrated to be accurate
down to the micrometer
and l might add,
at a very reasonable price.
Really? l thought Garak
sounded a bit upset.
Upset? Garak?
Oh, l hadn't noticed.
Now, is there anything
l can do for you, hmm?
A little Saurian brandy to go
or maybe a late-night
session in a holosuite?
No, thank you.
l think l'll call it a night.
Suit yourself.
There, how does that feel?
Much better.
Well, try not to yell
at any more admirals for awhile.
l wasn't yelling.
l was just expressing
my feelings, loudly.
Chief.
Commander.
You wanted to see me?
Ah, yes.
l was hoping
you could give me a hand.
l've been trying to access
the old Cardassian medical files
but l haven't been
having much luck.
l'm not surprised.
The Cardassians
did a general systems sweep
before they pulled out.
The medical files
would have been deleted
along with everything else.
ls there any way
to recover them?
Maybe.
These subroutines don't
look anywhere near as bad
as the engineering files did.
l might be able
to reconstruct the data
by micro-scanning
the purge trace.
Well, how long will that take?
Mmm. Two, maybe three weeks.
Ah. Well, that settles that.
Thank you anyway, Chief.
l'm sorry l couldn't
be of any more help.
Quark to Bashir.
This is Bashir.
Doctor, l need you
in my bar right away.
Oh, come on, Garak.
Don't you think
you've had enough?
On the contrary.
Anyone who talks about
the numbing effects
of your liquor
is severely overstating
the case, huh?
What's all this?
He came in complaining
about a headache.
The next thing l knew
he drank up
half my stock of kanar.
Oh, Doctor,
what a pleasant surprise.
l apologize
for my outburst at lunch
but l promise
l'll make it up to you.
Please, join me.
l think l will.
May l?
By all means.
What are you doing?!
l think it's
a little noisy in here.
Um, l'd prefer to drink
somewhere quiet.
Why, an excellent idea.
We'll go to my quarters.
Whatever you want.
But, first, l must make
a stop at the lnfirmary.
The lnfirmary?
Oh, my dear Doctor.
What kind of fool
do you take me for?
Now, give me back my bottle.
Give me my bottle back.
l will...
in the lnfirmary.
l'm not going to the lnfirmary
and l refuse to play
this ridiculous game.
Now, give me...
Give...
Make it stop, make it stop.
Bashir to Ops.
Medical emergency.
Two to beam to the lnfirmary.
Energize.
Some kind of implant?
Apparently.
What's it for?
Well, l was hoping
you could tell me.
After working for
the Cardassians for five years
l'd guess you'd know them
as well as anyone.
Maybe so,
but l never bothered
to look inside their skulls.
No, l don't suppose you did.
Do you think this is the cause
of Garak's condition?
lt's possible.
l mean, whatever this thing is
it's situated
in his postcentral gyrus
and has filaments
that connect it
to his entire
central nervous system.
Maybe it's some kind
of punishment device--
a parting gift from
the Cardassian government.
l thought of that
but, based
on the amount of scarring
in the surrounding tissue
this implant's
been in there for years.
And as far as l can tell,
Garak's only been in pain
for the past few days.
lnteresting.
l wish l had an answer
for you, Doctor.
Well, l was hoping
you could help me get one.
l think Quark knows
what this thing is.
Now, what makes you say that?
l overheard them talking
the other night.
Garak was negotiating to buy
some merchandise from Quark.
He seemed quite desperate.
l tried to ask Quark
what it was about, but...
No need to explain, Doctor.
The direct approach seldom
works with people like him.
But this could answer
some of my own questions.
Quark has sent several coded
messages to Cardassia Prime
in the past few days.
Really?
Mmm. l routinely monitor
all of Quark's
subspace communications.
ls that legal?
lt's in the best interest
of station security.
Doctor, do you want to know
what Quark knows or not?
l see your point.
Then meet me in Security
at 0200 hours.
Quark always makes
his clandestine calls
after the bar closes.
l wouldn't miss it.
Quark, you parasite.
lt's been too long.
ls Hartla still working for you?
The dabo tables wouldn't
be the same without her.
Oh, what l wouldn't
give to see her again.
l'm sure she misses you, too.
l'll bet she does.
Yeah.
She would have bankrupted me
if the occupation would
have lasted much longer.
But l'm sure you didn't
contact me just to reminisce.
What can l do for you?
How would you like to earn
a little extra latinum?
Enough to buy yourself
a promotion?
You have my undivided attention.
l need a piece
of Cardassian biotechnology
and the schematics relating
to its installation.
Hmm, biotechnology, huh?
Why, that shouldn't be
too difficult.
What is it?
You know, l never ask
those kinds of questions
but l've got
the requisition code number.
Well, give it to me.
l'll look for it.
l knew l could count on you.
Here it is.
l hope you don't have
one of these little bugs
hidden in my quarters.
Should l?
Transmission complete.
Hold on.
This won't take long.
Take your time.
Quark, you idiot!
ls something wrong?
ls something wrong?!
l'm ruined!
My career is over!
What did l do?!
You and your damned
requisition code.
lt's for classified
biotechnology, Quark.
Even the cursed number
is classified.
Where did you get it?!
No, don't tell me!
l don't want to know.
lf l'm lucky,
l can still get through this
with my skin intact.
Maybe they won't trace
the request back to me.
Who won't?
The Obsidian Order.
Nice talking to you, Boheeka.
We'll have to do it
again sometime.
The Obsidian Order.
That certainly
complicates things.
Who are they?
They're the ever-vigilant
eyes and ears
of the Cardassian Empire.
lt is said
that a Cardassian citizen
cannot sit down to a meal
without each dish
being duly noted
and recorded by the Order.
What happens
if you eat something
that doesn't meet
with their approval?
People have been known
to disappear for less.
Whether you agree
with their goals or not
you can't help but admire
their efficiency.
Even the Romulan Tal Shiar
can't compete with them
when it comes
to intelligence gathering
and covert operations.
What has all this
to do with Garak?
l wish l knew.
Do you think the Order
put that implant
inside Garak's head?
l have a better question.
lf the implant
is a punishment device
then why is Garak trying
to get his hands on another one?
He did asked for specifications.
Maybe he's trying to find
some way of removing it.
Well, either way,
l'd like to have
a talk with him
when he wakes up.
You'll have to get in line.
Thank you
Constable.
Computer, report on the status
of patient Garak.
Patient Garak is no longer
in the lnfirmary.
What?
When did he leave?
Patient checked out
at 0320 hours.
Garak, are you in there?
Computer, open the door
to Chamber 901,
Habitat Level H-3.
Emergency medical override,
Bashir 1-Alpha.
Ah, Doctor,
what a pleasant surprise.
l'm sorry, l must have
missed the door chime.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?!
Triptacederin?
How much of this did you take?
A mere 30cc's--
not nearly enough, l'm afraid.
30cc's would anesthetize
an Algorian mammoth.
Oh, we Cardassians must
be made of sterner stuff.
l barely feel it.
Listen to me, Garak.
l've had just about enough
of your nonsense.
Now you're coming back
to the lnfirmary with me.
Oh, l don't think so.
Believe me when l tell you
there's nothing
you can do for me.
Oh, and Quark can, is that it?
l thought l was
supposed to be the spy.
Quark's not coming, Garak.
How do you know?
l heard him talking
to his Cardassian contact.
He couldn't get
the item you requested.
Really?
That's most distressing
but l suppose
not all that surprising.
Ah, well,
maybe it's for the best.
My hypospray, if you please.
Another dose of triptacederin
might kill you.
Thank you for your concern,
Doctor
but l'd rather
have the hypospray.
l'm not going to let you
commit suicide.
l'm here to help you.
l doubt you can!
l think you'll find
that l'm experiencing
some slight deterioration
of my cranial nerve cluster.
lt's not so slight, l'm afraid.
We've got to get you
to the lnfirmary.
My dear Doctor
l have no intention
of putting myself on display
for the amusement of the Bajoran
inhabitants of this station.
lt's not your pride
l'm worried about.
lt's that implant
you're carrying around
inside your head.
You know about that, do you?
lt's some sort of punishment
device, isn't it?
Punishment device?
Well, l suppose, in a way,
that's what it's become.
lf it wasn't put there
to punish you
then what's it for?
Garak! l need to know
what we're up against.
lf you tell me what it's for
maybe l could find
some way to remove it.
lt's hopeless, Doctor.
Believe me, it can't be removed.
How do you know?
That's the whole point.
lf it could be easily removed,
it would be useless.
You see, on Cardassia
l was entrusted
with certain information--
information that needed
to be kept safe
regardless of the situation.
My implant was given to me
by Enabran Tain himself--
the head of the Obsidian Order.
lf l was ever tortured
it was designed to stimulate
the pleasure centers of my brain
to trigger the production
of vast amounts
of natural endorphins.
l do hope you appreciate
the irony, Doctor.
The whole purpose of the implant
was to make me immune to pain.
What caused it to malfunction?
lt was never meant
for continuous use.
Continuous use.
What do you mean?
Living on this station
is torture for me, Doctor.
The temperature
is always too cold.
The lights always too bright.
Every Bajoran on the station
looks at me
with loathing and contempt.
So, one day, l decided
l couldn't live with it anymore
and l took the pain away.
You activated the implant.
l created a device
which allowed me
to trigger the implant
whenever l wanted it.
At first, l only used it
a few minutes a day
but then l began relying
on it more and more
until, finally, l just turned
it on and never shut it off.
How long has it been on?
Two years.
And now the implant
is breaking down.
That's correct.
So, why don't you just shut
the damn thing off?
lt's too late now.
My body has become
completely dependent
on the higher endorphin levels
generated by the implant.
So, that's it then.
You're just going to give up
and let them win.
''Them,'' Doctor?
The Central Command,
the Obsidian Order--
whoever it is
who exiled you here.
You're just going
to roll over and die
let them destroy you
give up any hope of ever
seeing Cardassia again.
Doctor, did anyone ever tell you
that you are
an infuriating pest?
Chief O'Brien, all the time
and l don't pay any attention
to him, either.
Has it ever occurred to you
that l might be getting
exactly what l deserve?
No one deserves this.
Oh, please, Doctor,
l'm suffering enough
without having to listen
to your smug
Federation sympathy.
Do you think that,
because we have lunch together
once a week, you know me?
You couldn't even begin
to fathom what l'm capable of.
l'm a doctor.
You're my patient.
That's all l need to know.
Wrong again.
You need to know
who you're trying to save.
During the occupation
l was a Gul in the Cardassian
mechanized infantry.
We were stationed just
outside the Bajoran capital.
Shortly before the withdrawal
a handful of Bajoran prisoners
escaped from my custody.
My aide, a man named Elim
tracked them
to a Cardassian shuttle
about to depart for Terok Nor.
Elim got aboard
but the Captain refused
to let him search the ship
because he claimed he was under
strict orders from Gul Dukat
to depart immediately.
So, l had the shuttle destroyed
killing the escapees, Elim
and 97 Cardassian civilians.
You can't be serious.
l followed my orders.
None of those prisoners
escaped off of Bajor alive.
Unfortunately,
as it turned out
one of the passengers
on the shuttle was the daughter
of a prominent
military official.
l was stripped of my rank
and commission
and exiled from Cardassia.
So, now you know, Doctor.
l hope... l haven't shattered
too many of your illusions.
Listen to me, Garak.
Right now, l'm not concerned
with what you did in the past.
l'm simply not going to walk
out of here and let you die.
We need to turn
that implant off
and whatever withdrawal symptoms
or side effects
you may experience
l promise l'll help
you through them.
l need to know where
that triggering device is.
Where is it?
The desk, second drawer.
Well, that will be all for now.
lf you need to reach me,
l'll be here
for at least the next 26 hours.
Computer, l'm reading
an ongoing erosion
of tissue in the patient's
lymphatic system. Explain.
Unable to determine a cause
due to insufficient data
on Cardassian physiology.
All right.
Continue to monitor the status
of the patient's
cranial implant.
lnform me if it shows
any sign of reactivation.
Yes?
Doctor.
l was hoping l could ask Garak
some questions.
He's asleep.
He has been ever since
l turned off his implant.
Now, come on,
we can talk outside.
Doctor, l need to talk to him
as soon as possible.
l have four cases left
in my homicide files
which l'm almost certain
were committed
by the Obsidian Order.
lf Garak was a member
he may be able
to shed some light on them.
l'm afraid your questions
will have to wait.
How long?
l don't know yet.
Constable, Garak's body
has undergone a severe shock.
l don't know
when he'll recover.
l'm not even sure
if he'll recover.
ln that case,
l want to talk to him now.
Wake him up.
l'll do no such thing.
Doctor, these are murder cases,
and Garak may be a suspect.
That may be so,
but he's still my patient
and l'll not have him disturbed.
So, until further notice,
his quarters are off limits
to everyone except emergency
medical personnel.
So, if you'll excuse me,
l have a patient to attend to.
Garak?
Leave me alone.
l don't think that would be
a good idea right now.
Your blood chemistry
is severely imbalanced.
You need to rest.
Don't touch me.
Just calm down.
l don't want to calm down,
Doctor.
l've been calm long enough.
Look at this place.
lt's pathetic.
To think that this is what
my life has been reduced to.
This sterile shell,
this... prison.
Take it easy, Garak.
Look, you're obviously
experiencing some side effects
from the deactivation
of the implant.
Ridiculous.
l feel more clearheaded
than l have
in the past two years.
Two years-- what a waste
these past two years have been.
There was a time, Doctor.
Oh! There was a time
when l was a power.
The protégé
of Enabran Tain himself.
Do you have any idea
what that means?
l'm afraid l don't.
No, you don't, do you?
You don't know much of anything.
Tain was the Obsidian Order.
Not even the Central Command
dared challenge him
and l was his right hand.
My future was limitless
until l threw it away.
You mean when you had
that shuttle shot down
to stop those prisoners
from escaping?
Stopped them.
l only wish
that l had stopped them.
You didn't?
No, Doctor, my disgrace
is worse than that.
Unimaginably worse.
What could you have
possibly done worse than that?
l let them go.
lt was the eve
of the Cardassian withdrawal.
Elim and l were
interrogating five Bajorans.
They were children, Doctor!
None of them were older
than 14 years old.
They knew nothing.
They lived in bombed-out rooms
scrounged for food
on the streets.
They were filthy and they stank.
The room was freezing cold,
the air was like ice
and suddenly the whole exercise
seemed utterly meaningless.
All l wanted was a hot bath
and a good meal.
And so l let them go.
l gave them whatever latinum
l had in my pockets
and opened the door
and flung them back
into the streets.
Elim couldn't believe his eyes.
He looked at me
as if l were insane.
You took pity on those children.
There's nothing wrong with that.
No! l was a fool!
l should have completed
my interrogation
and turned them over
to the troops for execution
but because l was chilly
and my stomach was growling
l failed in my duty
and destroyed everything
l had worked for.
And so they exiled you.
That's right.
And left me to live out my days
with nothing to look forward to
but having lunch with you.
Well, l'm sorry
you feel that way.
l thought
you enjoyed my company.
Oh, l did,
and that's the worst part.
l can't believe
that l actually enjoyed
eating mediocre food
and staring into your
smug, sanctimonious face.
l hate this place,
and l hate you.
Okay, Garak,
that's your prerogative.
Now, l really think
you should lie down.
Get away from me!
Garak...
Garak, stop this.
l don't want to hurt you.
Bashir to lnfirmary.
l need an emergency medical team
in Garak's quarters now.
Administer another
20cc's of hyperzine.
He's not responding.
Give it a second.
Begin cardio-stimulation.
His heartbeat is stabilizing.
But his lymphatic system
is still critical.
l don't understand it.
l shut down the implant.
lt can't be affecting
his blood chemistry.
Yet toxins are
still accumulating
in his lymphatic tissues.
Computer, display analysis
of all biochemical samples
taken from the patient
in the past 39 hours.
Display them
by chemical composition.
lsolate and display
sample number... 17.
Bring up sample 23.
Sample 27.
Sample 32.
Sample 35.
Sample 40.
Stop.
Bring back sample 35.
Superimpose the molecular
structure of this leukocyte
with an analogous sample
taken from yesterday.
That's it.
The molecular structure
of Garak's leukocytes
has been altered.
That must be what's causing
the accumulation
of toxins in his system.
Can we synthesize
Cardassian leukocytes?
Probably, but that
could take weeks
and we don't have
that much time.
We have three
or four days at most.
lf we turned
the implant back on
we might be able
to keep him alive
another week or two.
No.
What?
l won't allow it.
l never want that thing
turned on again.
l understand how you feel
but l'm not sure what
else l can do for you.
Oh, you've done enough, Doctor,
more than l deserve.
There's something
you have to know.
What's that?
The truth.
l've about given up on learning
the truth from you, Garak.
Oh, don't give up
on me now, Doctor.
Patience has its rewards.
Now listen carefully.
Elim wasn't my aide.
He was... my friend.
We grew up together.
We were closer than brothers.
For some reason Enabran Tain
took a liking to us.
Before long, we were both
very powerful men
in the Obsidian Order.
They called us
''the sons of Tain.''
Even the Guls feared us.
And then there was a scandal.
Someone in the Order was accused
of letting some Bajoran
prisoners escape.
There were constant rumors of
who was going to be implicated.
Fingers were being pointed
at me.
By then, Tain had retired
to the Arawath Colony.
He couldn't protect me,
so l panicked.
l did everything in my power
to make sure that Elim
was accused instead of me.
l altered records,
planted evidence
only to discover
that he'd beaten me to it.
Well, he betrayed you first.
Elim destroyed me.
Before l knew what was going on,
l was sentenced to exile.
And the irony is, l deserved it.
Oh, not for the reasons
they claimed
but because of what l had tried
to do to Elim, my best friend.
Why are you telling me this,
Garak?
So that you can forgive me.
Why else?
l need to know
that someone forgives me.
l forgive you...
for whatever it is you did.
Thank you, Doctor.
That's most kind.
See that he rests comfortably.
l'll be back within 52 hours.
Where are you going?
To find the man
responsible for this.
Dr. Bashir.
Welcome.
Please, make yourself at home.
Well, Doctor, you've come
all this way to see me.
Aren't you going
to say something?
How did you know my name?
lnformation's my business.
You're Enabran Tain.
And you're
Dr. Julian Subatoi Bashir.
l hope you weren't
greeted too rudely
upon entering Cardassian space.
Not nearly as rudely
as l expected.
Good, l alerted them
that you'd be coming.
The military hates surprises.
Still, what you did
was very brave.
l'm impressed.
Can l get you
something to drink?
Tarkalean tea, perhaps?
l always drink Tarkalean... tea.
A good host knows
the needs of his guests.
One Tarkalean tea, extra sweet.
And a glass of kanar.
So, Lieutenant, how's Garak?
Has his condition
improved at all?
That Cardassian Quark
was talking to, Boheeka
l suppose he really did have
a reason to fear
the Obsidian Order.
Everyone has reason
to fear the Order.
l don't understand it.
Garak told me you were retired.
Oh, l am.
Have been for years.
But l try to keep informed
on current events.
l bet you could tell me
all kinds of things
l'd like to know, Doctor.
Oh, l'm sure l could.
l'll tell you anything
you want to know
about medicine,
biology, or tennis.
Do you want to hear my opinion
on the latest nillimite
alloy racket?
l don't think
that would be necessary.
Have it your way.
Are all the Starfleet
Lieutenants
as brash as you are?
l couldn't say.
Though l doubt it.
So do l.
Tell me, Doctor,
how sick is Garak?
He's dying.
And you're trying to save him.
That's right.
Strange.
l thought you were his friend.
l suppose l am.
Then you should let him die.
After all, for Garak, a life
in exile is no life at all.
Say what you will,
my job is to keep him alive
and l need your help.
My help?
What can l do?
The molecular structure
of Garak's leukocytes
has been disrupted.
l need to synthesize
replacements
in order to stabilize
his condition.
Unfortunately, my knowledge
of Cardassian biochemistry
is severely limited.
And you think l have access
to that kind of information?
lnformation is your business.
Besides,
you're the one who ordered him
to put that implant in his head,
aren't you?
l never had to order Garak
to do anything.
That's what made him special.
So you're saying that
if you don't get the
information, Garak dies.
That's it.
Well, we can't
allow that, can we?
l'll see to it
that all the necessary
data is transferred
to your station's computers.
Thank you.
Oh, don't thank me.
l'm not doing Garak any favors.
He doesn't deserve
a quick death.
On the contrary, l want to him
to live a long, miserable life.
l want him to grow old
on that station
surrounded by people
who hate him
knowing that he'll
never come home again.
What a lovely sentiment.
And it's from the heart,
l assure you.
And now, Doctor, l really
think you should be going.
One last thing.
Make it brief.
Garak mentioned an old friend
of his the other day--
a member
of the Obsidian Order.
l was wondering
what happened to him.
Did he give you
the name of this friend?
He said it was Elim.
Elim.
Mind letting me in on the joke?
l can see that Garak
hasn't changed a bit.
Never tell the truth
when a lie will do.
That man has a rare gift
for obfuscation.
Doctor, Elim is
Garak's first name.
Now run along home.
And please, tell Garak
that l miss him.
l'll be sure
to give him the message.
Computer, one to beam up.
Energize.
May l join you?
Garak.
Thank you.
What are you doing up?
You're supposed to be in bed.
Out of the question.
l couldn't stand being cooped up
in that dreadful lnfirmary
for another second.
Besides, l feel perfectly fine.
So, how's the l'danian
spice pudding today?
How's the spice pudding?
ls that all you have
to say for yourself?
How can you just sit there
and pretend that the last
ten days never happened?
l, for one, Doctor,
am perfectly satisfied
with the way things turned out
and l see no need to dwell
on what was, doubtlessly
a difficult time
for both of us.
By the way, l just had the
most interesting conversation
with Constable Odo.
lt seems he's
under the impression
that l was a member
of the Obsidian Order.
What did you tell him?
That he was mistaken, of course.
And he believed you?
Well, he said something
about keeping a closer eye on me
in the future.
l told him, ''Be my guest.
l have nothing to hide.''
Here, l've brought you
something.
What is it?
Meditations on a Crimson Shadow
by Preloc.
More Cardassian literature.
l think you'll find this one
more to your taste.
lt takes place in the future
during a time when Cardassia
and the Klingon Empire
are at war.
Who wins?
Who do you think?
Never mind.
Don't tell me.
l don't want you
to spoil the ending.
You know, l still have
a lot of questions
to ask you about your past.
l've given you all the answers
l'm capable of.
You've given me answers,
all right.
But they were all different.
What l want to know is, out of
all the stories you've told me
which ones were true
and which ones weren't?
My dear Doctor,
they're all true.
Even the lies?
Especially the lies.