Personal Log, Stardate 47329.4.
l finally realized
why l've had trouble sleeping
the last few nights.
Yesterday was
the fourth anniversary
of the massacre at Wolf 359...
of Jennifer's death.
l'm not sure
what bothers me more--
the date itself
or the fact that it almost
passed unnoticed.
Dad, what are you doing up?
l was about to ask you
the same thing.
l-l had a weird dream.
Get some hot chocolate
and tell me about it.
Nah, it's nothing.
Ah, come on.
Tell me about this weird dream.
lt's stupid.
Maybe so.
But the thing about dreams is
if you talk about them,
they kind of go away faster.
Okay, but don't laugh.
l promise.
l don't know, l was...
l was on the station somewhere--
l'm not sure where--
and l was trying
to get back here
but l couldn't...
l couldn't find my way.
l mean, every time l saw
a familiar corridor
it kind of led
into some other direction.
See, l told you it was stupid.
You got me interested.
Well, then...
l guess l got a little scared
and started looking for you.
But l couldn't find you.
Some... Somehow
l ended up in Ops
but you weren't in your...
you weren't in your office.
And... and then it was like...
like the floor started sloping
and... and l couldn't
keep my balance.
And all l wanted to do
was find you.
And here l am.
Dad, l... l love you.
l love you, too.
Oh, l have a calculus test
in the morning.
Then you better get some sleep.
Yeah.
Dad?
Hmm?
l miss her.
Me, too.
Beautiful, aren't they?
l don't think l've seen
the stars shine so brightly.
The Bajorans call
that constellation
''the Runners.''
l can never figure out
if they're running
toward something
or away from something.
Does that matter?
Sometimes it just
feels good to run.
l never thought about it
that way.
l'm Benjamin Sisko,
Commander of this station.
l'm...
Fenna.
l'm sorry,
you must be very busy.
l didn't mean to bother you.
You're not bothering me
at all.
Good.
Commander of the station.
That must be very exciting--
all those ships
coming and going.
Every day must bring
something new.
lt has its moments.
ln some ways, though,
l prefer this time the best
when everything is quiet and...
And you can feel a kind
of anticipation in the air
like something wonderful
is going to happen
but you just don't know
what it is.
l guess that sounds
kind of silly, doesn't it?
Not at all.
That's one of the great things
about this station.
You never know
what's going to happen next.
Or who you're going to meet.
l like it here.
l wish l could stay longer.
Where are you going?
l'm not really sure.
l guess l'll just keep going,
like the Runners.
l tell you what.
Before you run any farther
why don't l show you
around the station
if you have the time...?
Fenna?
Good morning, Chief.
Morning, Commander.
ls this maintenance or repair?
Right now, it's maintenance.
Five'll get you ten, it'll be a
repair by the time l'm through.
Admit it, Chief.
lf you were on a station
where everything worked
you'd be miserable.
Well, you may be right, sir.
But l'd be willing
to give it a try.
Good morning, Major.
Computer, one Chiraltan tea
with a double twist of lemon.
Something wrong?
No, nothing.
lf something's
bothering you, Major
l want to hear it.
lt's just that...
Every morning
for the last year
l've seen you walk in here
and start your day
with a raktajino.
l love raktajino.
l know.
You never even talk
to anyone until you've had
your first cup.
Because l'm not awake
until l've had my first cup.
So...
how come you're drinking
Chiraltan tea?
l, uh...
l just felt like
having something different.
That is all right with you,
isn't it, Major?
Of course.
You can drink whatever you like.
Thank you, Major.
l appreciate your support.
Dax to Sisko.
Go ahead, Lieutenant.
Professor Seyetik
and l are in the Science Lab
if you'd like to meet him.
On my way.
Lieutenant, where's our guest?
lnside the flux generator.
What?
What's he doing in there?
He could be killed.
Well, that's what
l tried to tell him.
And he went in anyway.
Benjamin, have you ever
met a terraformer?
No, what's that
got to do with it?
You can't tell
a terraformer anything.
lt's an amazing talent--
bringing dead worlds to life
but humility and common sense
aren't part
of the job description.
Oh.
There you go, Lieutenant.
That should increase
your generator output
by at least five percent.
Ah, you must be Commander Sisko.
Gideon Seyetik.
Great pleasure to meet you, sir.
Professor.
l'm a great admirer
of your work.
Good, a man
of intelligence and taste.
l can see we're going
to get along famously.
My son and l visited
Blue Horizon
on the way to Deep Space 9.
l must say, l was impressed.
Of course you were.
l created the place,
and even l'm impressed.
How did you like DaVinci Falls?
We didn't get to see them.
We were on the surface
only for a few hours.
Oh, Commander, you missed
Blue Horizon's crowning glory.
lmagine water cascading
off cliffs the height
of Mount Everest
thundering through
continuous rainbows
straight into an ocean
the color of sapphire wine.
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho!
l'm going to have
to take you there one day.
By God, l wouldn't mind
seeing it again myself.
l may take you up on that.
Good, good.
But first, Epsilon 1 19, huh?
Yes, l understand the initial
surveys look promising.
Promising?
Why, they look magnificent!
lmagine, reigniting a dead sun
bringing new life
to an entire solar system.
Next to that,
terraforming planets
will seem like child's play.
Let's hope it works.
Right now,
it's a promising theory.
Of course it'll work.
l never fail.
Well, l did once.
But l found it didn't
agree with me, so l swore
never to do it again,
and l never break my word.
Oh, you should be glad you're
coming with me, Lieutenant.
This'll be
my crowning achievement.
Giving birth to a star.
Even l would have a hard time
topping that one.
You're not going to let
that last piece
of Andorian tuber root
go to waste, are you?
Why do you ask?
Because it's delicious.
May l?
Be my guest.
l'm going to need
the extra calories
to keep up with Seyetik.
The man works almost
as much as he talks.
Benjamin?
What?
Are you looking for someone?
l'm sorry, what were you saying?
Uh, nothing important.
l have to meet
with Chief O'Brien.
We are boosting
the maximum speed
of Seyetik's ship to warp 9.5.
lf his experiment fails
and that sun goes supernova
we're going to need
to get out of there fast.
l'll see you in Ops.
Benjamin...
l was hoping l'd see you again.
l was just thinking about you.
Were you really?
l've been thinking about you,
too.
Where did you
disappear to last night?
l had to go, l'm sorry.
l didn't mean
to rush away like that.
Does your invitation
still stand?
To show me around the station?
What would you like to see?
Everything.
Everything?
That's going to take some time.
l don't mind if you don't.
What do you think?
lt's wonderful.
l'm glad you like it.
You must come here all the time.
Not really, but when l do
a ship is usually
blocking the view.
We should have brought
a picnic basket.
Here?
What better place?
Well, l guess there is tomorrow.
ls that an invitation?
Sounded like one to me.
Then l accept.
Good.
There's plenty left to see.
ln fact, l doubt that we can
see it all in one evening.
Then you can show me the rest
after our picnic tomorrow.
Do you always do that?
Do what?
Say exactly the right thing.
Well, no one's ever
told me that before.
There you go again.
So...
tell me all about yourself.
There's not much to tell.
Whatever there is,
l want to hear it.
l can't.
Can't what?
l can't tell you.
Why not?
l'm sorry, Benjamin,
but l have to go.
Fenna, wait.
So, then Tiet looked
down at Altrina's lunch
and said, ''Klingon food?
Those are worms!''
And Altrina vomited
all over the table!
lt was pretty disgusting.
That's nice, Jake.
Nice?
She threw up!
Hmm?
Oh, l'm sorry.
l guess l must have been
thinking about something else.
Dad...
are you in love?
What?
You know, with a woman?
You're showing
all three of the signs.
Signs?
The ones that Nog
told me about:
Loss of appetite, daydreaming,
smiling all the time.
You've been talking to Nog
about women again?
Look, l just want you to know
that if you're in love
it's all right with me.
Thanks, Jake.
What's she like?
She's, uh... really interesting.
lnteresting, huh?
So, when do l get to meet her?
l think it might be
a little early to do that.
Why? She likes you, too,
doesn't she?
l think so.
So, then what's the problem?
Well, um...
it's just that, uh...
she keeps disappearing.
Above all, stay alert.
lf the subspace transmission
l've received is correct
and Villus Thed is
en route to the station
l want to be notified
the moment he arrives.
Keep him under
constant surveillance
but remember,
he's a short-range telepath
so stay at least five meters
away from him at all times.
That's all.
Yes, sir.
Commander,
what can l do for you?
l need to ask
a favor, Constable.
Of a personal nature.
Go on.
l'm looking for someone--
a woman.
Name?
Fenna.
First name or last?
l don't know.
Species?
Humanoid.
What ship did she arrive on?
l... don't know.
Well...
what can you tell me about her?
Let's see...
l'd say she's
about 1.6 meters tall...
brown skin...
dark hair.
The last time l saw her,
she was wearing a...
She was wearing red.
Well, that's something, anyway.
Do you think you can help me?
l don't know.
l need to find her, Constable.
l think she may be
in some kind of trouble.
What kind of trouble?
Oh... let me guess.
You don't know.
Well, it's not much to go on,
but l'll do what l can.
l appreciate your help, Odo.
Benjamin, do you have a minute?
ln my office.
What's on your mind, Dax?
l was hoping you had
something to say to me.
l don't follow you.
You really have no intention
of telling me, do you?
Telling you what?
Come on, Benjamin!
l saw you with her last night
on the Promenade.
What's her name?
Fenna.
But believe me, Dax,
there is nothing to talk about.
You used to tell Curzon
everything.
Not everything.
You know what l mean.
lt's because l'm
a woman now, isn't it?
Don't be ridiculous!
No, l understand.
lt's hard to talk
man-to-man with a woman.
That has nothing to do with it.
Then tell me what's going on.
l will.
As soon as there is
something to tell.
Personal Log, supplemental.
Odo continues to search for
new information about Fenna.
ln the meantime, Professor
Seyetik has invited me
and the senior staff to dinner
aboard the Prometheus.
A great terraformer needs
the green thumb of a gardener
the eye of a painter
and the soul of a poet.
And of course, it doesn't hurt
to be a raging egomaniac.
Which makes you
eminently qualified.
Of course!
Terraforming is amazing enough,
but l don't understand
how you intend
to reignite a dead sun.
Basically, l'll use
a remote piloted shuttlepod
to deliver protomatter
into the dead star.
This will cause a cascade effect
which will transform
the star's carbon and oxygen
into elemental hydrogen.
And then we just stand back
and watch the fireworks.
Of course, if it doesn't work
it might be the last thing
we ever see.
Oh, come now, Lieutenant.
Nothing of worth
was ever created by a pessimist.
l don't know about that.
Van Gogh, Beckett, Y'Raka--
l wouldn't exactly
call them optimists.
Precisely,
and look at their work--
dark and dreary and dismal.
Art should be
an affirmation of life.
For example, take my own work
in the field.
l once saw an exhibit
of your paintings
at the Central Gallery
on Ligobis X.
They certainly were memorable.
l don't think l've ever
seen such huge canvases.
Doctor, nobody ever accused me
of understatement.
Certainly not anyone
who's ever read
your autobiography.
Nine volumes and counting.
You know, l always said
l wanted to write as many books
as l've had marriages.
Ah... which reminds me.
Wait till you taste the food
my wife has created for you.
None of that replicated nonsense
you're used to.
No, no, no.
Every dish was prepared entirely
by Nidell's own sweet hands.
l can't wait to meet her.
And so you shall.
She should be just about ready.
l'll go and get her.
Commander, do you think
he'd notice
if we weren't here
when he got back?
Don't even think
about it, Major.
l've had dinner with about
two dozen Bajoran ministers.
l think you owe me this one.
Besides, Seyetik is one of
the Federation's greatest minds.
l know, he told me.
Well, l, for one, find him
remarkably entertaining.
Ladies and gentlemen
l'd like you to meet my wife
and my inspiration... Nidell.
Now we have something
to talk about.
l can't eat another bite.
That was delicious.
Do you think
l could have the recipe?
You'll have to ask Gideon.
lt's his creation.
Well, it took me years
to perfect it.
The secret, you see, is to sear
the Kalo roots slightly
before layering them
over the slices
of roasted Waroon.
But the most important...
She acts like
she doesn't recognize me.
...one liter
of clear Rumall stock...
lt is the same woman, isn't it?
She looks the same.
...of Vulcan redspice
half a dozen Humat pods
and a dash of ice salt.
And then you reduce it
in an Andorian boiler
cook it exactly
500 degrees Kelvin
and then you just
pepper to taste.
Any questions?
Ah, maybe you should
write that down.
Of course.
No trouble at all.
Well... l think we should
continue this conversation
in the other room.
We shall be
more comfortable there.
Commander, can l help
you with something?
l hope so.
lt would have been a lot easier
if you'd told me
you were married.
l don't understand.
Yesterday...
on the Promenade...
you had plenty of opportunity.
Commander, l don't know
what you're talking about.
l've never met you
before tonight.
l suppose you never told me
that your name was Fenna.
Would you like
to talk about this?
Commander, obviously
you have mistaken me
for someone else.
Seems that way...
doesn't it?
l'm telling you, Dax,
it was the same woman.
The face, the voice--
it was Fenna.
Maybe you have to talk to her
when her husband isn't around.
Dax, she's a married woman.
That would have never
stopped Curzon.
lt's just that this
was the first time
since Jennifer's death that
l felt... drawn to someone.
Commander, may l have
a word with you?
l thought you should know
l've checked this week's
docking and transporter logs
and there is no record
of anyone matching
the description you gave me.
Thanks, Odo.
But you can call off
your search.
l've already found
the woman l was looking for.
You did?
And where was she,
if you don't mind my asking?
Aboard the Prometheus.
The Prometheus?
Are you sure?
Yes, we just left there
a few minutes ago.
That's impossible.
What do you mean?
l checked the de-embarkation
logs as part of my search.
With the exception
of Professor Seyetik
no one has left the Prometheus
during the entire time
it's been at the station.
Commander...
l thought you could use this.
No thanks, l was just leaving.
Stood you up, didn't she?
When you've worked
in a bar as long as l have
you get to recognize that look.
l've even seen it
in the mirror once or twice.
l'd better be getting home.
lf you like
we could go down to the bar
and talk...
you know, about women.
l don't think so.
Don't forget...
the holosuites are always open.
Benjamin!
l missed you.
ls there something wrong?
l just had dinner
with someone who looks
exactly like you.
Like me?
How strange.
You're telling me that your name
isn't really Nidell
and you're not the wife
of Gideon Seyetik?
Of course not.
l'm Fenna.
You know that.
Right now, l'm not
sure what l know.
l don't suppose you have
a twin sister, do you?
Not that l know of.
Fenna...
l need to know
where you came from
and what you're doing
on this station.
Does that matter?
Of course it matters.
l need to know who you are.
You do know me, Benjamin.
When l came here,
l thought l was looking
for a place--
somewhere l belonged--
but l was wrong.
l wasn't looking for a place;
l was looking for a person.
l was looking for you.
Benjamin...
All right, Lieutenant.
l've got the warp drive
on the Prometheus
purring like a kitten.
lt'll do 9.6 in a pinch
but l wouldn't take it
any faster.
l thought
the theoretical maximum
for those engines was warp 9.5.
Well, it was.
Must l remind you, Lieutenant
some of us have
only one lifetime?
l'll be right there.
Good luck, Lieutenant.
Commander.
Come to see us off, Benjamin?
Not exactly--
l'm going with you.
How often do you get a chance
to see a star reborn?
Do you really think
this is a good idea?
l need answers, Dax.
And the key
to Fenna's disappearance
may be on that ship.
Have you finished loading
the protomatter device
into the shuttle pod?
All set.
The containment fields
are holding fine.
Remote guidance systems
are fully operational.
l'm telling you, Commander
by the time l was through
with New Halana
it was a veritable paradise.
How are we doing, Mr. Piersall?
We'll be initiating preliminary
scans in a few hours.
Well, let me know
when we get there.
Well, Professor, you must
be eager to get started.
What did you call this?
Your crowning achievement.
Ah, don't remind me.
Commander, my entire life
has been a series
of escalating triumphs.
lt's what l live for...
knowing that no matter
what l achieve
there's always another
triumph waiting for me.
And now?
Well...
Are you familiar
with the Klingon poet G'Trok?
A little.
The Fall of Kang is required
reading at the Academy.
Ah...
''So honor the valiant
who die 'neath
your sword...''
''But pity the warrior
who slays all his foes.''
Well...
yes, well...
a bit obvious perhaps,
but true nonetheless.
So, what were we talking about?
You.
Hah! Of course.
My favorite subject.
Where was l?
You had just finished
terraforming New Halana.
Ah, of course.
Well, you can imagine
how grateful
the New Halanans were.
Endless parades
and receptions and...
Got to be a bit of a bore,
actually.
But then l... l met Nidell.
She was the daughter
of a local dignitary
and she was utterly infatuated
with me from the very start.
Well, l-l can't say
l blame her, actually.
The first time she saw me
l was surrounded
by crowds of people
unveiling a statue
they'd commissioned
in my, in my honor.
Well, l could...
l could tell from the start
she was something special.
You know,
she'd never been off-world
before she met me.
l promised to show her
the galaxy.
l would have given it to her
if l could have.
She must love you very much.
She does, Commander.
Don't ask me why, but...
she does.
Fenna?
Benjamin, l'm so glad
to see you.
Dax, report to my quarters
immediately.
On my way.
Benjamin, what's wrong?
The last time l saw you...
you vanished.
l'm with you now, and l'm never
going to leave you again.
l wish l could believe that.
You have to, Benjamin.
Dax, this is Fenna.
What is she doing?
lt's all right.
She's not going to hurt you.
l'm not reading
any cellular structure.
No DNA patterns.
Just pure energy.
Benjamin, what is
she talking about?
l think it's time we find out.
Help her.
She won't wake up.
She's in shock.
Her respiration is shallow.
Her heartbeat
is irregular and falling.
Her blood pressure's dropping.
Benjamin, she's dying.
But you've got to do something!
l don't know that l can.
Fenna!
l should have known.
But you can't be here!
Nidell promised me
you'd never come back.
l don't know
what you're talking about.
Just look at her!
She looks like me.
Of course she looks like you!
She is you-- the real you.
Professor,
what the hell is going on here?
That thing over there
isn't real.
She's an illusion
created by my wife's
unconscious mind.
That's not true!
Benjamin, you know
that he's lying.
Nidell is
a psychoprojective telepath.
Fenna's just another one
of her projections.
Lieutenant?
l've never seen readings
like these.
Her occipital lobe is giving off
enormous amounts of energy.
l don't see
how she could survive
more than an hour or two
like this.
But she's dying!
You've got to do something!
There's nothing l can do.
Get Fenna to my quarters, Dax.
And notify Lieutenant...
No!
Get her out of here, Dax.
Benjamin, l want
to stay with you.
lt will be all right, Fenna.
l just need to talk
to Professor Seyetik, here.
All right, Professor,
if what you're saying is true
Nidell's psychoprojective
abilities are killing her
and l need to know why.
Nidell doesn't even
know this is happening.
ln times of deep
emotional distress
Halanans sometimes...
lose control of these abilities.
My wife is very...
emotionally distraught.
Oh, this happened once before,
three years ago on Terosa Prime.
lt nearly killed her then.
She swore to me
it would never happen again.
Obviously...
it has.
You may have noticed, Commander,
that l tend to evoke
strong emotions from people,
particularly my wives.
Oh, they all start out
loving me, but...
a few years of togetherness
soon cure them of that.
The others all had
the good sense to leave me.
But why can't Nidell?
What keeps her with you?
Halanans mate for life.
She can never leave me
no matter how much
she might want to.
Benjamin, l've never seen
Seyetik or that woman before.
l don't know why he's saying
those things about me,
but they're lies.
l'm as real as you are.
Oh, how l want to believe that.
But can you tell me
where you came from?
How you got to this station?
Can you tell me
a single memory of your life
before we met on the Promenade?
Benjamin, l'm so frightened.
Nidell's dying, Fenna.
She only has a few hours.
What happens to me if she dies?
You no longer exist without her.
But you can save her.
Give her back the life
she gave to you.
l don't know how.
You can go back to her.
l've seen you do it,
three times.
But even if she lives,
then l die
and everything that you
and l have dies with me.
Fenna...
what we have is a dream.
l wouldn't trade it
for anything
but it's still just a dream--
Nidell's dream.
And she won't remember
any of it, will she?
There's no way to be sure.
l love you, Benjamin
and l always will.
Commander, you'd better come
to the Bridge right away.
What is it?
lt's Seyetik.
He's launched the shuttlepod
toward Epsilon 1 19
and he's onboard.
On my way.
He's opening a channel.
On screen.
l hope this transmitter
is working.
l'd hate to go to all this
trouble without an audience.
Professor, you'll be killed.
What do you think you're doing?
Making history.
You might want to record this
for posterity and all that.
He's about 60 seconds
from impact.
Gideon, you don't
have to do this.
We found a way to save Nidell.
l had a feeling you would,
Commander.
But this is the only way
l can really set her free
and l owe her that.
Besides, this'll be
my crowning achievement.
Remember The Fall of Kang?
Well, this is one warrior
who refuses to be pitied.
What's he talking about?
Klingon poetry.
30 seconds from impact.
Gideon, l want you to turn
the shuttlepod around now.
That's an order.
Too late, Commander.
l've already entered
the gravity well of the star.
Engage the tractor beam.
He disabled it before he left.
Commander, when all this is over
you'll find a case
among my personal belongings.
There's something in there
l want you to find.
What is it?
My obituary.
l wrote it myself.
After all, l couldn't leave
such an important document
to some stranger.
Do me a favor,
and see that it's sent
to the Daystrom lnstitute
for publication, huh?
You have my word.
Oh, which reminds me
l didn't get a chance
to update it before l left.
Let the record state
that he sacrificed himself
on the altar of science.
Ten seconds.
l'll be sure they get it.
l'm sure l can count on you.
Five seconds.
Keep your eye
on the viewscreen, Commander.
You'll never see
anything like this again.
Let there be light!
Station Log, supplemental.
Epsilon 1 19 continues
to burn brightly--
a fitting memorial
to a brilliant man.
Meanwhile, l'm happy to report
Nidell has made
a complete recovery.
Unfortunately, she has no memory
of Fenna's experiences.
Commander.
Nidell.
How did you know l was here?
Lieutenant Dax told me.
So...
when does the Prometheus leave?
Soon.
l just wanted to say
good-bye and thank you.
lt'll be good to get home.
How long do you plan
on staying on New Halana?
For the rest of my life.
l've been gone
too long as it is.
l wish that l could
remember Fenna.
What she did...
how she felt.
But l can't.
l'm sorry.
lt's all right.
l can remember for both of us.
Tell me one thing.
lf l can.
What was she like?
Fenna?
She was just like you.