Look, save your energy.
We'll have you out of there
as soon as possible.
l hope.
Try rerouting
the power coupling.
Mr. O'Brien.
See if you can activate
the interlock servos.
Mr. O'Brien.
Captain Jaheel, those people
have been stuck in that air lock
for over an hour.
Now, if you can wait
till we get that door opened
l'll be happy to listen
to any problems you might have.
But l've already
been waiting two days
for your people to readjust
my ship's antimatter
flow converter.
l'm afraid we've
gotten a little behind
in our maintenance schedule.
l'm not interested
in hearing excuses.
l have a shipment
of Tamen Sahsheer
waiting to be
delivered to Largo V
and l'll need to do
better than warp 1
to get there
before it spoils.
l'll try to get a repair crew
to you by the end of the day.
Now, that's
the best l can do.
Your best, Mr. O'Brien,
hardly seems good enough.
Dax to O'Brien.
O'Brien here.
Can you spare a minute, Chief?
l have a little problem
here at the lab.
On my way.
Thanks for coming, Chief.
What are you doing out here?
Have you checked
the EPS converter?
Yes-- first thing.
How about the intensity grid?
lt's fine.
Then it's probably the secondary
phase modulator.
We had trouble
with them last week
in the main power core.
That should do it.
Anything else
l can do for you?
The navigational computer
hasn't worked reliably
for three days.
l ask for the star charts
for the Argosian sector
Glessene sector
comes up instead.
That's when l can coax
this system on line.
Uh-huh.
Try it now.
Ah! That's more like it.
You look like you
could use some sleep.
Who has time for sleep?
l'd settle for five minutes
peace and quiet.
Chief, l thought you were going
to fix the replicators.
You're absolutely right, sir.
l knew l'd
forgotten something.
Can't have the
Operations Chief
sitting around daydreaming
when there's work
to be done, can we?
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
l'll get right on it.
''Fix the replicators, Chief.''
''My console's off-line, Chief.''
l should have transferred
to a cargo drone--
no people, no complaints.
Hot coffee--
black, double sweet.
Tell me, Quark.
Am l mistaken, or is business
a little slow today?
Slow? lt's been
almost nonexistent
for the past three days.
Mmm. Who knows?
lf things don't improve
you may be forced
to close down.
Oh, you'd like that,
wouldn't you?
Well, let's just say,
without you around
my job would be
considerably easier.
Without me around,
you'd be forced
to find some other poor
innocent to persecute.
Think about that
while you sit here
gloating at my misfortune.
Quark!
You call this Kohlanese stew?
lf your meal
isn't satisfactory
l'm sure we could,
uh, exchange it
for something
more to your liking.
Aren't you the
least bit curious
as to how it tastes?
Ugh! Ugh!
Now...
you served it.
You're going to eat it.
All right, that's enough.
l said, eat it!
l said...
that's enough.
Leave him alone.
Well,
another satisfied customer.
lt's these replicators.
lf l don't get them fixed soon,
they'll destroy my business.
Why not get O'Brien
to fix them?
He has the replicators on the
command level working perfectly.
l'm on his waiting list.
He assures me he'll get to them
as soon as he can.
Mmm...
No telling when that will be.
The Chief's a very busy man.
Computer...
display a station layout.
Highlight locations
of all repaired replicators
on command level.
lnformation restricted
to security clearance 5
and above.
Please enter
security verification.
Clearance verified.
There you go, sir.
l think you'll find that
more to your liking.
Very much appreciated,
Mr. O'Brien.
Don't mention it, sir.
Unfortunately, there
are plenty of replicators
around the station
that still need looking after.
You all right, Chief?
l'm just a bit hot.
The environmental controls
must be acting up again.
Send my regards
to Mrs. O'Brien.
Jake tells me
she's a wonderful teacher.
Oh, that's nice to hear, sir.
She's flower units
about the lad herself.
Excuse me?
Sir?
What was that
you just said?
She's... quite fond
of the lad herself.
Oh.
l'm glad to hear it.
Very good, sir.
Ladies.
Hello, Lieutenant.
Oh, l forgot
how different it was.
How different what was?
Being female.
l haven't been one
for over 80 years.
All this attention.
lmagine it must take
some getting used to.
Actually,
l find it quite enjoyable.
Major Kira.
Lieutenant Dax.
l'd be honored to have you
join my little party--
as my guests, of course.
What's all this, Quark?
You cheat your
1,000th customer?
Who says Bajorans
don't have a sense of humor?
Actually, uh, we're
celebrating the repair
of the bar's
replicator system.
Perhaps l could interest you
in a nice, double-whipped,
l'danian spice pudding.
Oh, what do you think?
l think l'm due back at Ops
but, uh, go on.
Enjoy yourself.
Chief?
How can l help you, Major?
Looks like you're the one
who could use a little help.
Oh, no, l'm fine, really.
l suppose this isn't
a good time to tell you
that number three turbolift
has broken down again.
Joking, Chief.
Major, lark's true pepper.
What?
Let birds go
further loose maybe.
Shout easy play.
Chief, you're not
making any sense.
Round the turbulent quick.
Well, close
the reverse harbor.
A-Ankle try sound.
Reset gleaming.
Dinner to bug.
Chief, wait.
When?
Chief.
Computer,
continue neural imaging scan
and stimulate visual cortex.
All visual responses normal.
Begin auditory stimuli.
No physiological damage.
All brain functions
within normal parameters.
Nurse.
Yes?
Will you pull up Mr. O'Brien's
neurophysiological
history, please?
Yes, Doctor.
What is that?
What's he written?
l wish l knew.
Strike limits
flame the dark true salt.
Please, Chief, take a seat.
Way link complete.
Way link!
What's wrong with him?
He appears to suffering
from a form of aphasia.
lt's a perceptual
dysfunction
in which aural
and visual stimuli
are incorrectly processed
by the brain.
His actual thinking
hasn't been affected
but he's incapable
of expressing himself
or understanding others.
Victory strike
limits frosted wake.
Simple hesitation.
l'm not sure l follow you,
Doctor.
You say Mr. O'Brien is aphasiac
but all of his tests
have come up negative.
lsn't aphasia
typically associated
with some kind
of cranial trauma?
Yes. lt can occur
as a result of a stroke
or a blow to the head
but there's no evidence
of that here.
Did you check
the medical library
for any precedents?
And rechecked--
nothing, so far.
You have any theories?
Not yet.
Find one.
Major Kira, get ahold of
the Chief's personal duty log.
l want to know where he's been
and what he's done
for the past 52 hours.
l've already examined it,
Commander.
He's been
all over this station.
Retrace his steps
and see what you come up with.
Dax, you will temporarily assume
Mr. O'Brien's duties.
Yes, uh... um...
ls there a problem, Lieutenant?
Lieutenant?
l'm sorry, Benjamin.
l'm unable to...
foolish assembled regal...
control weather.
Spontaneous development
of aphasia
is virtually impossible.
Yet we saw Lieutenant Dax
become aphasiac before our eyes.
This told me we were
dealing with a disease
which only mimics aphasia,
so l ran a full
neural synaptic comparison
between Dax and O'Brien
and l found this in the
temporal lobes of both patients.
A virus.
lt imposes itself
within the established
synaptic pathways
and then randomly
reroutes them.
For example, when l look at this
a process occurs within my brain
which connects the stimulus
to the word ''tricorder.''
This virus
disrupts that process.
l'd see a tricorder
but l'd say something
ridiculous, like ''window.''
Exactly.
Doctor, l think
you should get over here.
Night the flow trade again.
You lost pile luck.
Away tunnel back the garden.
Doctor, l want this station
put under emergency
quarantine immediately.
Yes, sir.
Dabo!
Quark,
what is going on here?
What does it look like?
lt looks like
business as usual
but that's impossible
because all shops
and businesses
have been closed
until further notice.
Except, of course, for
essential station operations.
For which this place
hardly qualifies.
l don't think they'd agree.
This quarantine has everybody
on edge, Constable.
Would you deprive them
of a little harmless diversion?
They'd be safer
in their quarters.
Quark, this Kohlian stew--
magnificent.
Fortunately, my assistant, Rom,
was able to fix the replicators.
Yes, very fortunate.
Jake...
l expected you
home an hour ago.
Sorry. l was at Nog's.
Dad, about this quarantine--
it's going
to be okay, isn't it?
lt's just a precaution,
nothing more.
l wish l shared your
confidence, Commander.
Go straight home, son.
l'll see you at dinner.
Captain Jaheel, all visitors
have been confined
to their ships.
Believe me, there is
no place l'd rather be.
Then what
are you doing here?
Commander, l officially
request permission
to leave this station.
Request denied.
But none of my crew
has been affected
by this virus of yours.
And, unless l depart at once
my whole cargo will be ruined.
Captain, l suggest
you return to your ship now.
Please. l don't want
to get sick.
l'm sorry, but until we can
find a cure for this... thing
no one's going anywhere.
Computer, let's start with
one Ferengi starduster, please.
Extra strong.
Perfect.
Uh...
l thought the front wheels
were sticking a bit.
Unauthorized access
to crew quarters
is a crime, Quark.
You could have just asked
to use the replicators.
There's an old Ferengi saying--
''Never ask when you can take.''
Uh, how did you figure it out?
You claimed Rom
fixed your replicators.
-So?
-Rom's an idiot.
He couldn't fix a straw
if it was bent.
You're right.
Rom is an idiot.
Remind me to get rid
of him tomorrow.
Based on the levels of the virus
found in the patients' blood
l believe it's being
absorbed through ingestion.
You're saying
it's in our food?
Well, that's not possible.
All the food on this station
is replicated
and all the replicators
use biofilters.
They automatically
screen out contaminants
including viruses.
Major, l've analyzed
samples from replicators
all over the station.
Food on the command level
is contaminated.
But all of us here have
eaten from those replicators.
How come we're not aphasic?
This virus
is highly adaptable.
lts incubation period
seems to vary
within each individual.
According to O'Brien's duty log
the last thing he did
before becoming aphasic
was fix
the command level replicators.
Get a repair crew over there
to inspect the site.
Let's shut down
those replicators.
Maybe we'll be able
to limit further contamination.
l'm afraid that's
not going to do it, sir.
l've been getting
aphasic patients
from all over the station.
How is that possible?
You can thank Quark.
l caught him
using a replicator
in one of the vacant
crew quarters.
He was producing
his entire menu out of there.
lf this virus is present
within a large enough segment
of the population
it could mean...
What is it,
Doctor?
l just took an air sample.
The virus...
lt's mutated
into an airborne variety.
Which means...?
Which means the whole station
is infected.
Station Log, Stardate 46423.7.
Nearly 60% of DS9's population
has now contracted
the aphasia virus.
We've initiated standard
quarantine procedures
and are advising
all incoming ships
to maintain their distance
from the station
until further notice.
l found it in the replicator's
pattern generator.
O'Brien must have accidentally
triggered it
when he repaired the system.
According to Bashir,
it introduced
an anomalous programming
sequence
into the materialization
subroutine.
ln effect, it built the virus
directly into
the replicated food
at a molecular level.
So what we have here
is sabotage.
Cardassian sabotage.
How can you be sure?
Has a diboridium core
for a power source.
That is Cardassian
technology.
Bashir to Sisko.
Sisko here.
Commander, l think you'd better
get down here to the infirmary
as soon as possible.
On my way.
You wanted to see me, Doctor?
Jake?
Left... become better...
control... entire hope.
We've converted
some empty crew quarters
into a hospital ward.
He'll be well looked after.
l'll take him there myself.
Come on, Jake.
You're going to be all right.
Commander, when
you've got a moment
l've found something
l'd like to show you.
lt'll be all right.
Just lay back.
l know, but just
lay back and relax.
Food... dabo... drinks...
money... hand... mine... give!
Well, Quark, l see even you
couldn't weasel your
way clear of this one.
You underestimate the Ferengi
immune system, Commander.
l'm merely here visiting
my less fortunate customers
to make sure they're
not faking the illness
to avoid paying their bills.
No one could
be that devious.
l am.
You... gold... owe... me!
l... now... give!
Up.
We're doing
everything possible.
l'll be back
as soon as l can.
The virus is synthetic,
Commander.
lts nucleotide sequence
is too perfect.
lt's clearly not natural.
You're saying the Cardassians
genetically engineered
this thing?
Well, that's what
l thought at first
but l've studied Cardassian
genetic engineering.
They always
build distinctive
monoclonial links
into their DNA.
This virus has none
of those features.
All right,
then who made it?
Well, that's what
l wanted to find out.
So l referenced all known
DNA construction techniques
in the Federation records
and this protein
series was the key.
lt indicates...
Doctor!
Who created this virus?
The Bajorans, sir.
l believe it must have
been a terrorist plot
to sabotage the Cardassians
while they were here.
The energy decay
of the power core
indicates it dates back
to the building of the station.
That's 18 years ago.
l suppose
the Bajoran underground
could have smuggled it aboard
during construction...
before l took over
as Head of Security.
But why would the underground
go to all the trouble
of planting a booby trap
and not set it off?
Maybe they forgot.
No. More likely,
they were captured
or killed before
they could release it.
We need to find out
who created this virus.
You're our best hope.
18 years is a long time.
Besides, even if she
finds who did this, that's
no guarantee they can help us.
We just have to hope
they remember the antidote.
That's assuming they ever
bothered to create one.
lt had to be someone
in the underground
familiar
with genetic engineering.
18 years ago?
Sounds like something
Dekon Elig
might have thought up.
How can l find him?
The last l heard
he was in a Cardassian prison.
Where was he being held?
The Velos Vll lnternment Camp
but that was nine years ago.
And you have no idea
where he is now?
Think, Galis.
This is important.
l'm sorry, Kira,
but it was all so long ago.
What is it, Jake?
Roll linger when life...
roll linger when...
What?
Other support, strong courage...
He's running a high fever.
Open way long.
Open way.
Doctor, we have
an emergency in crew quarters.
How is he, Doctor?
Not good, l'm afraid.
The virus has attacked
his autonomic nervous system.
Can he be stabilized?
He hasn't responded
to neural stimulation.
l've given him 30cc's
of corophizine
to avoid secondary infection
but so far, l've been unable
to lower his fever.
What are his chances?
Unless l find some way
to counteract the virus
he'll be dead in 12 hours.
Have you made any progress?
No.
l've tried
base pair destabilizers
sequential disruption--
nothing seems to affect it.
Sir, l've got seven
other aphasic patients
displaying the same symptoms
as O'Brien here
and l'm afraid
this is only the beginning.
Keep searching, Doctor.
l hope Major Kira finds
whoever's responsible
for creating this virus.
l'd like to meet
that person myself.
This virus
is a work of genius.
l'll try to
arrange it for you.
Link established with
the Bajoran Archival Records.
Locate files on Velos Vll
lnternment Camp.
Ready.
Do you show a record
of an inmate named Dekon Elig?
Affirmative.
Biographical data.
Dekon Elig, geneticist.
Former member
of the Higa Metar sect
of the Bajoran underground.
Killed while attempting escape,
Stardate 39355.
Certificate of Death on file.
No need to ask
how you're doing.
Chasing after ghosts.
You have 12 hours
to catch one.
And then?
People start dying.
Computer...
display Dekon Elig's
Certificate of Death.
ldentify signature of witness.
Certificate of Death
was witnessed by Surmak Ren
Bajoran medical assistant.
Show me biographical data
on Surmak Ren.
Dr. Surmak Ren.
Former member
of the Higa Metar sect
of the Bajoran underground.
Repatriated to Bajor
upon closing
of the Velos Vll lnternment
Camp, Stardate 46302.
Current status unknown.
Dabo.
Any luck?
l haven't won a spin in hours.
Uh, care to place
a friendly wager?
lf it's your reputation
you're thinking about
no one need ever know.
lt has nothing to do
with my reputation.
The truth is, l never...
learned the game.
You mean, you've sat here
for all these years
and you don't even
know how to gamble?
That's correct.
No wonder you
always look so bored.
The rules are quite
simple, actually.
l'd be happy to
show them to you.
Some other time, perhaps.
Sisko needs me in Ops.
And, since
the entire security force
has been stricken
with aphasia
the Promenade is in
a very vulnerable position.
How unfortunate.
Consider it a warning, Quark.
Because l'm holding you
personally responsible
if anything turns up missing.
ls that understood?
Perfectly.
Hmm.
Dabo.
Computer,
analyze test sample 37 delta.
Detail effects
on viral containment.
Working. Analysis complete.
Sample 37 delta ineffective.
Viral protein sheath
is unaffected.
Nucleotide sequence
remains intact.
Computer, replay morning.
Command unclear.
Please repeat.
Glass lunch judge a bin
to let it.
Command unclear.
Please repeat.
Computer, establish a link
with the Bajoran Medical lndex
for the, uh,
Northwestern District.
Link established.
Access all information
on Dr. Surmak Ren.
There are no records
matching that name.
Try the Northeastern District--
same search.
Dr. Surmak Ren,
currently serving
as Chief Administrator
of the llvian Medical Complex.
Computer, open a channel
to the llvian Medical Complex
Administrator's office.
This is Dr. Surmak.
And you are...?
Major Kira Nerys
Bajoran liaison to Deep Space 9.
Ah, yes, the old Cardassian
mining station.
How can l help you?
lt depends.
On what?
On whether or not
you helped Dekon Elig
plant an aphasia virus here
18 years ago.
l have no idea
what you're talking about.
Look, Sisko, l'm a security
officer-- a good one--
but that doesn't
make me qualified
to help you run
station operations.
You're probably right,
Constable.
But, as you can see,
you're all l've got.
Commander...
Commander, l think
l found our scientist.
Does he have an antidote?
l don't know.
He broke the connection
the minute
l mentioned the virus.
Major, you mind telling me
where you're going?
To continue my conversation
with Dr. Surmak, in person.
Major, l can't allow you
to break quarantine.
We can't risk
spreading the virus to Bajor.
l am well aware
of that, Commander.
As a matter of fact
l don't intend
to step foot on the planet.
Better let her go, Sisko.
She's all we've got.
Let's just hope
there's someone left
to greet her when she returns.
Jake.
How's it going?
l've missed you.
l know things don't look
too good right now
but they'll get better.
You have to believe that
because l'm not going
to lose you, Jake.
You hear me?
l'm not going to lose you.
You better take a look at this.
We have activity
on Docking Port 5.
l think a ship
is about to depart.
Docking Port 5?
That's Jaheel's ship.
Put him on screen.
Captain, your ship
has not been cleared
for departure.
The mooring clamps are locked
and l don't intend
to release them.
l suggest you change your mind.
l'm taking aft thrusters
to one half.
Captain, cut your engines
before you rip
your ship apart.
He's not reducing power.
Jaheel, l'm ordering
you to stand down.
Your orders
are no concern of mine.
My entire crew has been
confined to your hospital.
l must leave now,
while l can still function.
Look, l understand
that you're frightened
but, believe me,
you're better off here.
You don't want
to be out there alone
and get hit by the virus.
Don't worry about me,
l'm fine.
And l plan to stay that way.
And if you think you're go...
We'll have to
retract the clamps.
Once he's clear
of the station
we can grab him
with a tractor beam.
Damn.
What's wrong?
There's too much stress
on the mooring clamps.
They're not retracting.
His aft isolation
plate buckled.
His main power core's
been ruptured.
lf the internal
fuel cells collapse
the whole ship will explode.
And take half
the docking ring with it.
Computer, isolate a com line
to the llvian Medical Complex
Administrator's office.
Line isolated.
Scan office for life-forms.
One life-form present.
Lock on
and stand by to transport.
This is Dr. Surmak.
Hello again, Doctor.
Just checking
to see you're in your office.
l have nothing to say to...
Hello again, Doctor.
This is outrageous.
l demand you return me
to my office immediately.
Relax, Doctor.
You won't be gone long.
Try to reestablish
visual contact
with Jaheel's ship.
No response.
His com lines are down.
Bypass communications
through a secondary grid.
See if you can switch
to external pickups.
Got it.
His fire control systems
don't appear to be working.
We have about 15 minutes
before the fuel cells collapse.
l hope you feel better
than you look.
Must be that damn virus.
This is Sisko.
Any station personnel
who can understand
what l'm saying, come
to Ops immediately.
We need help up here.
We have to get that ship
away from the station.
Why don't we explode
the mooring clamps?
The blast should push the ship
away from the docking ring.
We'll have to get down there
and blow it manually.
l'll do it.
All right.
You can cross barrels.
All job appalled.
What was that?
Bread...
the arrive...
seen earlier.
Oh, l see.
Major, this is kidnapping.
Turn this ship around or,
l swear, you will spend
the rest of your life
in Kran-Tobol Prison.
Fine. But first,
we need your help.
The aphasia virus is spreading
through the station.
Why come to me?
You helped create the virus,
didn't you?
No, l had practically
nothing to do with it.
Dekon Elig created the virus.
l was merely
his medical assistant.
That seems
like a lifetime ago now.
l was only in the underground
for six months
before we were captured.
l am not responsible for this.
l am not looking to place blame!
All l want is the antidote.
l don't know of any antidote.
lf Dekon created one,
he never told me.
Listen, Surmak.
l have a station
full of dying people
and you are
the closest thing there is
to an expert on this virus.
l sympathize, Major
but l don't think
l can help you.
All right.
Then how about helping yourself?
Meaning what?
Meaning...
l've been infected
with your virus, Doctor
so now you're infected, too.
To anyone who can hear me,
this is Odo.
Sisko's infected.
l could really use
some help here in Ops.
Do l detect a note
of panic in your voice?
Quark.
Am l to believe that you're
volunteering to help?
Who said anything
about volunteering?
We can haggle over price later.
Now, um...
how may l be of use?
l need to get
to Docking Port 5 now.
That ship's going to explode
in five minutes.
l'll beam you over.
You?
Relax.
l served on a
Ferengi freighter
for eight years.
All right.
l must have witnessed
the procedure
hundreds of times.
Witnessed?
You mean to say you never
handled the controls yourself?
Energizing.
Kira to Ops.
Approaching Landing Pad 7.
Request clearance
to initiate docking procedure.
Welcome back.
l could use some help up here.
Quark, what are you
doing in Ops?
First thing l need to see
is your doctor's viral
characterization research.
He was beginning to develop
an antidote series.
Let's take a look at that.
Listen, Doctor, um
l'll be in Ops.
lf you need me,
use this string impact.
Lot show red intense.
l think you'd better
sit down, Major.
Dog fellow distance.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Odo, you'd better hurry up.
That ship's going to explode
in one minute.
Virum protein sheath.
Nucleotide sequence.
Yes.
That's right.
lt's an adaptive,
synaptic inhibitor.
Dekon was brilliant.
No doubt of that.
l think we've found
your antidote, Major.
40 seconds.
30 seconds. Hurry!
l know, l know.
20 seconds!
Ten seconds!
Odo? Quark to Odo.
You still with us?
Try not to sound
too disappointed.
Now, about that little matter
of my hazard pay...
Why, you...
Come on. Come on.
Station Log, Stardate 46425.8.
With the help
of Dr. Bashir's notes
Dr. Surmak was able to find an
antidote for the aphasia virus.
We are continuing to administer
it throughout the station
and things are slowly
returning to normal.
Good to have you back, Chief.
Thank you, sir.
Coffee, black.
O'Brien!