What's funny is where
the files were located--
right there in Ops protocols.
The encryption system
was extremely easy to break.
So, they wanted us
to find these?
Or they didn't care.
Well, there's nothing
of strategic value here--
just some personal logs
and some files
on Bajoran terrorists
but it is a glimpse
into the Cardassian mind.
You might want to warn Kira
before she sees her file.
Warn me?
About what?
Oh, uh...
Dax and Mr. O'Brien
discovered some of the last
Prefect's personal files.
There's a file on you
but you may find it
disappointing.
l'm a big girl, Commander.
Bashir to Sisko.
Sisko here.
l'm at Airlock 14, Commander.
l think you better
get down here.
What's the problem, Doctor?
Well, l was about to begin
off-loading
some medical specimens
from the Bajoran transport
and, well...
the Kai is here.
Kai... Opaka.
Why would she be here?
She said you once offered her
a tour of the station.
''A minor operative
''whose activities are limited
to running errands
for the terrorist leaders''?!
Major, when you're through
feeling underappreciated
perhaps you'd join me
in welcoming the Kai aboard.
You say she's never
been here before?
She's never even left
Bajor before.
Well, excuse me
for saying so, Commander
but she looks... preoccupied.
ls something wrong, Opaka?
Contemplating prophecy.
lt's interesting you
chose this viewport.
The wormhole is just out there.
lt's a spectacular sight to see.
Unfortunately,
it can only be seen
when a ship enters it or exits
but there's nothing
scheduled for today.
A shame.
Sisko to O'Brien.
Go ahead, Commander.
Prepare the Yangtzee Kiang
for launch, Chief.
Kira and l are taking
the Kai through the wormhole.
Right away, sir.
Thank you.
l didn't want to keep you
from your duties, Doctor.
Oh, it's a slow day.
All right.
This way.
ls the ship ready, Chief?
All prepped
and ready for departure
Commander.
Ma'am.
After you.
You have a child, don't you?
l do.
l have a little girl, ma'am.
Yes.
Would you give this
to her for me?
We'll be entering the wormhole
in about a minute.
Thank you again
for indulging me.
Not at all, Opaka.
You honor us with your presence.
Yangtzee Kiang to DS9.
Estimated time of return,
1400 hours.
Logged in.
We'll expect you then.
Flight stabilization at maximum.
Here we go.
Spectacular, isn't it?
More than l imagined.
My smoothest ride yet, Major.
There's ldran,
the closest system.
lt's a ternary star.
A doorway into the unknown.
The other side
of the galaxy, to be precise.
The Gamma Quadrant is 70,000
light years from Bajor.
lt would take
our fastest starship
over 67 years to get here.
l'm glad l got the chance
to see it.
You'll be seeing
what this wormhole
is worth to Bajor
in a few years.
lf that is to be my fate,
Commander.
Should l reverse course?
So soon?
There's not much else
to show you yet.
Prophecy can often be vague,
Commander.
That's why we must test it.
l don't understand, Opaka.
You may return.
Take us back
to the wormhole, Major.
Coming about.
Sensors are picking up
a narrow band subspace signal.
What do you make of it?
Just a long stream
of statistical data
followed by a request
for a reply.
Uh, l'm not reading
any response.
Launch a class-2 probe.
We'll follow it up later.
You're not going
to investigate it now?
l'm not sure that's a good idea.
Because of my presence?
Well, there's no telling
what it may be.
Please, Commander.
l don't get out often.
Can you get a fix
on the source, Major?
.35 light years,
bearing 229, mark 41.
l guess we'd better take a look.
Well, this is definitely
the origin of the signal.
l'm having trouble
pinpointing the source.
lt's not coming
from the surface.
There's your answer.
A network
of artificial satellites.
One of them looks like
it's malfunctioning.
lts orbit is unstable.
l'd bet the signals we picked up
were from the system
trying to repair it.
Commander,
sensors indicate life-forms
localized
in 12 square kilometers
on the moon's surface.
They may be humanoid, sir.
Humanoid?
Can you verify that?
l can't resolve
the bio-patterns.
There's too much interference.
Take us in a little closer.
We're being scanned
by one of the satellites.
l don't like this.
lt's heading toward us.
Shields up.
Reading a massive energy buildup
in the satellite.
600 megawatts... 900.
lt's firing.
Shields are down.
Forward thrusters are gone.
We're losing power.
Attempting to compensate
with secondary boosters.
lmpulse generator's failing.
Hold on, we're going down.
Check contingency
fuel cell output.
Holding at 65%.
Doctor...
-watch the hull temperature.
-Aye, sir.
Stabilizing attitude
control response.
Pitching up to 20 degrees.
Hull temperature 900 C.
950, 1,100.
We're holding profile.
1,200 C, 13...
Ejecting antimatter pod.
Pitching up to 60 degrees.
Prepare for final
braking maneuvers.
Brace for impact.
Commander...
Pulmonary collapse.
Her upper thoracic vertebrae
have been crushed.
Stay with us, Opaka.
Stay with us.
l'm sorry.
Ahn-kay ya...
ay-ya vasu.
Coh-ma-ra...
di-nay-ya.
Ahn-kay ya...
ay-ya vasu.
We've got company.
Still no contact with Sisko?
Not yet.
They're nearly
three hours overdue.
Three and a half.
Opaka's people are on subspace
to me every five minutes.
Tell them
one of our runabouts
found a trace
of a warp eddy current.
lt's got to be
from their ship.
With any luck, we should
be able to determine
which direction
they were headed.
That's not going
to satisfy them on Bajor.
You have no idea
what the Kai means to them.
When they heard Sisko had
taken her into the wormhole...
Constable, tell them we're
doing the best we can, okay?
Runabout Pad C.
Have the Bajorans station
a ship on the Gamma side.
We'll stay in close touch
by subspace.
Move.
Our first visitors.
You're not all the same race.
l'm a Bajoran.
l'm Commander Benjamin Sisko.
Major Kira Nerys
and Doctor Julian Bashir.
A doctor?
How ironic.
l'm Golin Shel-la,
leader of the Ennis.
Why are you here?
We were attacked
by one of your satellites
Our ship was damaged,
and we crashed.
Of course, Commander,
but why did you come here?
We were exploring.
We recently discovered
a permanent wormhole
linking our quadrant
of the galaxy with yours.
l command a space station at
the mouth of that wormhole.
You know nothing
of our home planet?
of the punishment?
We're just beginning
to explore this sector.
As l said, our home is on
the other side of the gal...
Major.
l'm all right.
The hell you are.
She needs treatment.
l'd like my medical case
if you don't mind.
For God's sake!
l apologize
for our cautious nature.
lf you haven't realized,
we're at war.
Who are you fighting?
A brutal enemy
that attacks at whim.
We maintain a constant vigil.
This is an energy weapon.
Yes.
The Ennis stopped using
directed-energy weapons
centuries ago--
not damaging enough.
Your arrival
complicates matters.
We don't plan to be here long.
Oh, you expect
to repair your ship?
No, but a rescue team is
probably on its way right now.
Well, like you
they'll have to deal
with the defense-net
and that is beyond my influence.
You don't control
the satellites?
We're all prisoners
on this moon.
Then, this is a penal colony.
My immediate concern
is your partisanship.
By your very presence here
you'll be considered
our allies.
All your lives are in danger.
The latest victims
of our enemy--
the Nol-Ennis.
Where are your doctors?
We have none.
You have no medical personnel?
How do you survive without...?
We were thrust
into this situation
with few resources.
Since you're here
under similar circumstances
l was hoping we'd be
of some help to each other.
This should make you
feel better.
Major...
l'm so sorry.
l would have done anything.
lt's all so senseless.
Opaka's always been
a symbol of hope to me.
Her words gave
our struggle meaning.
And now she's dead.
Her life ends
on some unknown moon...
and for what?
Dr. Bashir will give you
any medical assistance he can
but understand, we can't
take sides in your battle.
lt doesn't matter
what l understand
if the Nol capture you.
We're in the middle
of a pretty ugly war.
l gathered that.
Shel-la says his people
will protect us from the enemy
in exchange for your services.
Well, perhaps l can
train some of them
in the basics of field triage.
Do whatever you can.
How's the shoulder, Major?
l'll live.
l still have to run
a neuromuscular scan
on her when we get back.
Don't count on a quick rescue.
This moon is some kind
of high-security prison colony.
Over here!
Major!
Let's go!
Leave him!
Run!
Commander!
Put your phaser down, Kira.
Her vital signs
appear to be normal
but l could have sworn
she was...
l... l was there, Doctor.
Opaka...
are you aware of what happened?
The surface was approaching
so quickly.
l must admit, l...
l closed my eyes, Commander.
There was a deafening whine.
l felt the impact.
A wall of heat seemed to...
pass through me.
And... and then...
nothing.
After we crashed,
we pulled you from the wreckage
but you were...
Dead.
How do you explain this, Doctor?
Although she appears
to be normal
her physiology
has been radically altered.
How?
l'm not sure.
The tricorder indicates
some kind
of biomechanical presence
at a cellular level.
Biomechanical?
You mean something artificial?
l wish l could tell you.
Whatever it is, it seems to be
directly controlling
her metabolic processes.
ls she in any danger?
l'm sorry to keep saying it,
Commander
but l really don't know.
lf the runabout's computer
were functional
l might be able to run
a full analysis.
Commander.
Over here.
lt's okay.
lt's all right.
There's still no sign of them
on any
of the long-range scanners.
Not even a transponder signal.
lf they went down,
we should at least
be getting something
from their transponder.
The warp eddy has traces
of meson particle emissions.
That makes it
a Starfleet power reactor.
The current shows
that their heading
was approximately 230 mark 4.
Anything interesting
in that direction?
An uncharted binary star system.
Well,
l guess it's time to chart it.
Setting a new course.
His readings are
the same as Opaka's.
Virtually every cell
in his body
shows signs
of this biomechanical presence.
Now, somehow, it has literally
brought him back to life.
You died before?
Many times, too many to count.
Sir, l'd like to return
to the runabout
and try and get the computer
up and running.
Doctor, we're in the middle
of a war.
Sir, this could be
a breakthrough
of unprecedented magnitude.
lt's too dangerous.
l'll see to his protection.
l would like to know more about
this ''breakthrough'' myself.
Your doctor acts as though
he's seen a miracle.
He's not alone.
Well, if you'd lived
with it as we have
you'd see it as a curse.
How long have you been here?
lt feels like an eternity.
lt's all part of the punishment.
What is this punishment,
Shel-la?
Everything here is designed
to prolong our suffering.
What was your crime?
The Ennis and the Nol-Ennis
are ancient enemies.
Generation after generation,
we fought the same war.
The leaders of our planet
were unable to mediate a peace.
Finally, they sent us all here
and told us that we would serve
as an example
for the rest of civilization.
How did your fight begin?
Some say it was water.
Some say it was land.
lt's not really
very relevant now.
Then what do you hope to gain
by continuing?
Vengeance.
All of us have seen
our families suffer incredibly
at the hands of the Nol.
The Nol can say
the very same thing.
And probably do.
lf you must fight your war,
the least you can do
is learn to fight it
more effectively.
Major, this is not our...
What do you mean?
There were no guards
at the entrance when we arrived.
You have no system to alert
your forces of an attack.
Your people are obviously
unprepared
for fighting close-quartered.
That's enough, Major.
We're trapped on this moon
with only his forces
between us and damnation.
We have to defend
ourselves to stay alive.
Now, when the Nol
attack again, we...
l said that's enough!
We have to be ready!
This is not your war, Kira.
We used to defend
ourselves better, Major.
Safety perimeters,
counterattacks
preemptive strikes.
And then we realized...
that it was all pointless.
When you cease to fear death,
the rules of war change.
You'll understand as the years
begin to pass, Major.
Listen to me, Shel-la.
Our rescue is not going
to take years.
Days, weeks, maybe,
but they will find us
and then they'll penetrate
the defense-net
and transport us out of here.
Then you will be luckier
than we have been.
We'd be willing to transport
all of you away from here
if that's what you want.
Away from here?
To live one life
to die in peace...
to us, this is
an ancient prayer
that has never been
answered, Commander.
You would do this for us?
For both sides--
the Ennis and the Nol-Ennis.
After you leave
you can go wherever you want,
but end this nightmare.
Stop fighting long enough
for all of us
to get off this moon.
Zlangco, the leader of the Nol
would never agree
to a cease-fire.
Ask him.
You don't know them!
All they care about is...
What do you care about?
lf you want to end
the suffering of your people
then at least try.
Set a meeting with this Zlangco.
Talk about this.
This is hopeless.
But l will talk...
if he will.
l'm not reading a single
M-Class planet in the system.
lf they went down
anywhere around here
they couldn't have survived.
l'm not sure we can believe
the scans, Chief.
The star is putting out abnormal
levels of delta radiation.
That would foul up
our long-range scanners.
We'll have to survey each planet
one at a time.
Not to mention...
two dozen or so moons
and an asteroid belt.
Bloody needle in a haystack.
A needle in a haystack.
What we need is a magnet.
A magnet?
Yeah. You want to pick
your piece of metal
out of straw, you use a magnet.
l don't think
l'm following you, Chief.
Runabout hulls are made
of metallic composites
that interact
with magnetic fields.
We could send out a few probes
to scan the system
for those specific
magnetic resonance patterns.
lf Sisko's runabout
is in the system
we might pick up a fluctuation
in the hysteresis curve.
The magnetic deflection
of a runabout's hull
is extremely weak.
The probes will never be
able to detect it.
They will if l can outfit them
with a differential magnetomer.
A differential magnetomer?
Mm-hmm.
l've never heard
of a differential magnetomer.
How does it work?
l'll let you know
as soon as l finish making one.
Nice work, Julian.
l'm surprised.
Zlangco has agreed
to listen to your proposals.
Good. When?
Right away.
We'll meet at a neutral site
near your vessel.
We've both agreed
to carry no firearms.
What if they use the opportunity
to set a trap?
We've taken the appropriate
precautions, Major
but if you personally
would care
to check the security,
l'm sure your Commander
would allow you
to accompany us...
Major Kira will be staying here
with the Kai.
What a shame.
You can't bury it, Kira.
What?
Do you recognize yourself
in these people?
Me?
Oh, not...
not at all, l...
They're content to die.
l've always fought
to stay alive.
Oh...
l don't want you to have
the wrong impression
of me, Opaka.
Just what impression
do you think l have?
That, that...
that l enjoy any of this.
l...
l don't enjoy fighting.
Yes, l've...
l've fought my entire life,
but for a good cause.
For our freedom,
our independence.
And it was... it was brutal
and ugly, and...
but that's over for me now.
That's... that's not who l am.
l-l don't want you to think
that l am this...
violent person without a soul,
without a conscience.
That is not who l am.
Oh!
Don't deny the violence
inside of you, Kira.
Only when you accept it
can you move beyond it.
l've known nothing but violence
since l was a child.
ln the eyes of the Prophets
we're all children.
Bajor has much to learn
from peace.
l'm afraid the Prophets
won't forgive me.
They're just waiting
for you to forgive yourself.
22 minutes into launch.
All readings
within normal parameters.
Probe ''B'' approaching
planet six.
Three moons.
No change
in the hysteresis curve.
Probe ''C'' approaching
planet seven.
No change.
What the hell would they
be doing here anyway?
lt's a waste of time.
They could be
20 light-years from here
and we wouldn't have
the first clue.
Probe ''A'' approaching
planet three. One moon.
Chief...
Probe ''A'' measuring
a .0012 fluctuation
in the hysteresis curve.
lt's the third planet.
No, look, it isn't.
We're picking up something
from its moon.
Laying in a new course,
full impulse.
Any progress, Doctor?
Yes, sir.
l've got the computer
up... more or less.
lt's processing the data now.
l can already confirm that
these microbes are artificial.
Rather like nanites, in a way.
l should have
a complete analysis
from the computer
in a few minutes.
What's going on?
Talks about a cease-fire.
No kidding?
How did you arrange that?
l told them we'd transport them
off this moon.
lsn't that a bit like
assisting a jailbreak?
l don't need you to interpret
the Prime Directive
for me, Doctor.
Yes, sir, of course.
l only meant...
Whatever crimes
they've committed
they've paid for
a hundred times over.
They've been altered somehow
and been abandoned
by their world.
l believe the Federation
would recognize them
as separate and unique.
Yes, sir.
Well, l should be checking
on that analysis.
So...
you are the leader
of the aliens.
Benjamin Sisko, Commander
of a Federation space station.
Federation?
What does it matter to us,
Zlangco?
lt matters to me.
The Federation is made up
of over a hundred planets
who have allied themselves
for mutual scientific, cultural
and defensive benefits.
The mission my people and l
are on is to explore the galaxy.
Such a noble purpose.
There'll be no reward
for our release, you know.
You are being a fool, as usual.
A fool who always manages
to outwit you, Shel-la
as l have proven,
over and over again.
You care to die once again,
all you need to do is ask.
lf you've had enough of this
then make your leaders
stop and listen.
Your only reason to live is
to make each other suffer.
lf you've had enough
of suffering
then make them stop.
l'm not here to be a mediator
but if you ask
for an alternative
l'll give you one.
We're listening.
ln a matter of days,
when our rescue party arrives
l can arrange
to transport you and your people
off this moon,
if both sides can only cooperate
until then.
Zlangco, they will resettle us
on different planets.
lf that's what you wish.
The two of you seem to have
discussed this plan in detail.
Of course.
His crew has been with us
for two days.
Explain why you chose to ally
yourself with the Ennis.
We have allied ourselves
with no one.
One of your people
fired a weapon at us.
We were defending ourselves.
l think you're lying.
l don't know the alien
but l know Shel-la.
l know how his mind works.
l promise you,
this is an Ennis trick
to lure our entire
population out of hiding
so they can be slaughtered.
That's not true...!
Then the Ennis
are surely willing
to make the first
gesture of peace.
Let them bring all of their
people out of hiding first
to prove their
honorable intentions.
Do you think
that l would allow
a single Nol to escape
this planet alive?!
No more than l would
let an Ennis go free.
Ah!
l'm sorry, Commander
but l've discovered
we can't afford to die here--
not even once.
lt's some kind
of artificial satellite system.
That's what our probe
must have picked up.
Our sensors are reading
life-forms on the surface,
Chief.
l think some of them
are human.
lf the ship's down there
why wouldn't the transponder
be sending out a...?
We're being scanned.
lncreasing orbital altitude.
What are you thinking?
Well, the only thing that could
block out a transponder signal
is a broadband damping field.
That requires a low-level
satellite system, like this one.
Suddenly, we're being scanned
by those satellites, so...
Maybe they had something to do
with our missing runabout.
Exactly. See?
They're putting out
a mutual induction field
that would block out 99%
of all transmissions
to and from the surface.
ls there any way for us to get
a com line through the field?
Well, l've got one percent
to work with, don't l?
The analysis is very clear.
Once the microbes
have restored a body after death
that body then becomes
permanently dependent on them
for all cellular functions.
Permanently?
lt gets worse.
The designers made them
environment specific.
lf the microbes are removed
from this ecosystem
they'll stop functioning.
So, if we transport
anyone off this planet
we kill them.
l'm afraid so.
The Kai?
Rio Grande to Sisko.
Do you read me?
This is O'Brien.
Come in.
Go ahead, Chief.
l can barely read you.
ls everyone all right?
We're alive, but the Yangtzee
Kiang was destroyed.
Will you be able to beam us up?
Not quite yet, Commander.
We've got to find
a way to penetrate
this network of satellites.
They're making it impossible
for us
to lock on to anything
down there.
Understood.
But those satellites
will come after you
if you get too close.
They're armed.
One of them cut us down
without any trouble at all.
Yeah, we figured as much.
Let me know before you're
ready to make an attempt.
Acknowledged. Rio Grande out.
We have to talk to the Kai.
ls there a cease-fire?
Neither side took it seriously.
l'm not at all surprised.
You were right, Kira.
They don't know how to do
anything else but die.
They've forgotten how to live.
The Rio Grande has made contact.
Dax and O'Brien are in orbit.
They're working on a way
to penetrate the defense system.
l'll be staying, Commander.
What?
This is the answer
to all the prophecies
of my life.
lt's the wrong answer, Opaka.
You can't stay here.
l didn't know how or why,
but when we came
through the wormhole,
l knew l wouldn't be returning.
You must tell our people, Kira
that l have answered the call
of the Prophets.
l was brought here
because it is time
for these people
to begin their healing process
just as you were brought here
to begin yours.
You know, all we really
need to do is find a way
to create a gap in the net.
Maybe a photon would destroy
one of the satellites.
Maybe, but you think they'd
build a defense network
with that in mind.
You shoot one,
the rest might swarm up
like Vayan horn flies.
We need to go
for something simpler.
All l need is
about a 15% increase
in the opening in the net.
Rio Grande to Sisko.
Go ahead, Chief.
We're going to try
to poke a hole up here, sir.
if you're about ready
to end your stay.
Only three of us
are coming back.
Kai Opaka is remaining.
Benjamin, please confirm.
Did you say we're not
transporting the Kai?
That's correct.
l'll explain later.
We need a few minutes,
Commander.
Rio Grande out.
Leaving without us?
My analysis of these microbes
that keep you alive
showed that if you were
to leave this moon
you would die.
Then there is no end.
Commander...
l find myself caught
in a moral dilemma.
As much as l am dedicated
to the preservation of life
l wonder if we shouldn't
help these people
put an end to this torture.
How could you do that?
Anything that can be programmed
can be reprogrammed.
lf l could disable
the mechanism
in these microbes
they should no longer function
when someone is killed
and these people would
finally be able to die.
You've seen our life here.
Please, it's
the only solution left.
You give us a way
to reprogram these microbes
and we'll put an end
to this war.
You really think the fear of
death will end the fighting?
Never has in any other war.
No.
But it will allow us
to finally win
to wipe out the Nol for good.
On this world, Doctor
your disabled microbes
would be the ultimate weapon.
We could finally
and truly destroy our enemies!
Rio Grande to Sisko.
Stand by for transport.
Ready.
Coordinates set.
Launching probe.
12 seconds to intercept.
Go on, go on, go for it.
One of the satellites
is breaking orbit
moving toward the probe.
That's it.
The satellite is showing
a power buildup--
about 800 megawatts.
Probe destroyed.
Rio Grande to Sisko.
Trying to lock on, Commander.
Establishing pattern lock.
You can't leave
without giving us...
Energize when ready, Chief.
Opaka, if we can
ever find a way...
My work is here now, Commander.
But your power and mine...
will cross again.
Energizing.