Station Log, Stardate 46910.1.
Chief O'Brien
has escorted his wife
back to Earth to celebrate
her mother's 100th birthday.
ln the meantime,
the rest of us are trying
to keep the station
up and running.
lt's almost as if the
refiltration processors
were waiting for
Chief O'Brien to leave
before breaking down.
This technology looks like
something the Cardassians
must have taken
from the Romulans.
ls that an RCL type-1
matrix field?
Perhaps we should call in
a Romulan repair service.
Or an RCL type-2?
Another raktajino?
lt'll keep me up all night.
l can think of better
ways of keeping you up
and they're more fun
than drinking Klingon coffee.
Definitely type-1.
Dax.
l really should be
getting to bed.
May l escort you
to your quarters?
That's not necessary, Julian.
Oh.
Well, good night, then.
''Not necessary, Julian.''
But not forbidden, either.
Dax.
Yes.
You are Dax?
What do you want?
Dax!
Yes, Major?
l'm just not sure, Commander.
What does it look like to you?
lt looks like a residual charge
in the graviton generator.
lf that's what it is,
it will bleed off.
Let's run a quick level-3
diagnostic, just to be sure.
Bashir to Ops.
Ops.
Three people...
l think they just took Jadzia.
She tried to struggle with them,
and l tried to help, but...
Full station security alert.
Secure all turbolifts.
Seal off airlocks
on levels four through 12.
Computer, locate Lieutenant Dax.
Lieutenant Dax is on level six,
corridor one.
No, that's where l am.
They just left her combadge.
How long ago, Doctor?
Oh, l'm not sure, really.
What are you doing?
We turn right
at the next corridor.
They're managing to avoid
the security tracking grid.
They seem to know a lot
about the station.
Then they may know
the speed of our runabouts.
lf they do, they probably have
a faster ship
to make their escape.
Major, survey all ships in dock
with a high warp capability.
Damn!
What?
That's why we've got
a residual charge
in the graviton generator.
They've disabled
the tractor beam.
We've got eight ships in dock
capable of warp five or more.
Three on docking pylons,
five smaller ones in the ports.
Seal off
all docking ring airlocks.
Security, all duty squads
to the docking ring.
Commence immediate inward
sweep, levels 16 through 21.
l've got them-- Airlock 5.
l'm on my way.
Security, report to airlock,
corridor five.
We have a hostage situation.
lsolating with
cadderon force fields.
Will you just tell me
what you want?
Move.
Force field is down.
They know
the security override codes.
They're boarding a ship.
l'm trying to speed up
the bleed-off process
in the graviton generator.
We lost them.
lt's working.
l'm increasing the flow
to the EPS wave guides.
The excess charge
is neutralizing.
Engage tractor beam.
Gotcha.
Bring it in
to Docking Port 6, Major.
Slowly!
Extremities
where l can see them.
You're the Chief of Security?
Are you all right?
My name is llon Tandro
special envoy from Klaestron lV
in charge of this
extradition procedure.
Extradition? l call this
kidnapping and assault.
You'll find that to be
a valid warrant for her arrest.
The relevant treaty
between Klaestron lV
and your Federation
allows for unilateral
extradition.
And the charge?
The fugitive Dax
is charged with treason...
and the murder of my father.
The warrant says
Dax was responsible
for the death
of General Ardelon Tandro
30 years ago.
30 years ago?
That would have been Curzon Dax.
Mmm, when he was on Klaestron lV
as a Federation mediator
during their civil war.
He never mentioned
he'd even been to Klaestron lV.
Strange.
Not so strange,
considering these charges.
Odo, let me tell you something.
Curzon Dax tended to be
a little cavalier about life
even about his personal
responsibilities
from time to time.
l think that was
part of the reason
l liked him so much.
He had more faults
than the usual
socially acceptable Trill.
He was not a murderer.
How about a traitor?
lt says Dax betrayed
the Klaestron government
to the rebels.
lt's all nonsense, Constable.
l'm telling you l knew the man.
But did you know
the symbiont inside the man?
Come in.
l've sent a subspace message
to Klaestron lV
requesting confirmation
of the warrant.
That's the only stall
l could think of.
Now, what the hell's going on,
Dax?
Dax.
lf l'm going to help you,
you've got to help me.
l don't expect any help,
Benjamin.
Thank you, though.
Are you crazy?!
Treason and murder--
on Klaestron lV
either of those gets you
the death penalty.
What's the matter with you?
Talk to me, before l have
to let these people take you.
No. l'm sorry, Benjamin,
but no.
We've got 18, 20 years
of friendship behind us.
l'm Jadzia Dax now.
That was Curzon Dax
you knew for 20 years.
So when the Dax part
of you survived
from one host to the next
it really didn't take
our friendship along.
Benjamin, you know
you're still
my very dear friend.
l'm sorry.
You've received
your confirmation, Commander.
Now we'd like to be
on our way with the prisoner.
You know, Mr. Tandro,
l kept wondering
why you tried to kidnap
Lieutenant Dax
rather than just present
your warrant to me
in the proper way.
l couldn't figure
that out at first.
l trust you have figured out,
Commander
that our extradition treaty
with your Federation
is current and valid.
This station is
technically Bajoran.
What does that mean to us?
You don't have an extradition
treaty with Bajor.
l think that's why you tried
to abduct
Lieutenant Dax.
You were afraid the Bajorans
would refuse extradition.
That's absurd.
No Bajoran interests
are even involved here.
How did you know your way
around this station so well?
My conversation
is with the Commander.
No, your conversation
is with my First Officer now.
You Klaestrons are allies
of the Cardassians.
Your knowledge of this station
confirms that.
They must have
given you the layout
which not only compromises
Bajoran security
but also... annoys us.
l'm afraid Bajoran interests
are involved
and Bajor is adamant that--
at least, l believe
it's adamant.
Oh. Oh, yes.
You see, there will have
to be an extradition hearing
before l can lawfully
release Lieutenant Dax.
For how long?
As long as it takes.
That could be for days.
Well, there's nowhere else
on the station that's suitable.
That's too bad.
l'm not shutting down
for any Bajoran hearing.
l'm sure Lieutenant Dax
would appreciate it.
Business is business.
Ah.
You know, that wall's
going to have to come in
about five meters.
What are you talking about?
Of course, after you move
the wall, that'll mean
your second-level holosuites
will have to come down.
Come down? Why?
New restrictions.
Restrictions?
Building codes.
Since the provisional
government took over
they've got their hands
into everything
and, of course,
l'm the one who's expected
to enforce their rules here.
Ha.
You know, l think this bar
is just a little
too near the exit.
This is blackmail.
No, it's just business.
And business is business.
l was just coming to see you.
We still haven't found
a place for the hearing.
Holding it on Bajor
would involve
Dax leaving the station
and l don't want to risk that.
Well, now that's a coincidence.
Our good friend Quark
just donated the use
of his facility
for the hearing.
Nice gesture.
l thought so.
You know, l haven't been able
to get a word out of Dax
about any of this.
So l thought someone
might go do some investigating
on Klaestron lV itself.
What do you think?
This case has 30 years
of dust covering it.
The extradition hearing
will take about 30 minutes.
l was hoping to make it
a little longer than that.
Good luck.
This will be an informal hearing
so l'm going to start
with some informal advice.
l am 100 years old.
l do not have time
to squander listening
to superfluous language.
ln short, l intend
being here until supper
not senility.
Understood?
Understood, Madam Arbiter.
You seek the extradition.
Make your case.
The accused Trill, whatever
its present appearance may be
was and is a Federation officer
who committed capital
crimes on our planet.
Since there is no time limit
on the prosecution
of such crimes...
Thank you, l have already read
the warrant and the charges.
The crimes described
are 30 years old.
What took you so long?
The evidence was contained
in military files
which were officially sealed
until recently.
Fine. Sit.
Commander, the warrant
is in order.
On what grounds do you ask
that l deny extradition?
You say the warrant's in order
but the name
on the warrant is Dax.
Certainly that doesn't refer
to Jadzia Dax, a female
but to the now deceased
Curzon Dax, a male.
This young woman wasn't
even born 30 years ago.
You are arguing semantics.
This creature is a Trill.
The symbiont known as Dax
has progressed
from one host to the next.
Exactly. From one host
to the next.
A different host,
a different person.
So l submit that the person
he wants to extradite
no longer exists
and l challenge him
to prove otherwise.
That's ridiculous.
lt would have been easier
on me, Commander, had you not
raised that particular point
but the penalty for these crimes
on your planet is death
and that is rather permanent
so before l grant extradition
you will convince me, please
that the person
named in your warrant
is the person
who is standing here now.
She doesn't seem to care
whether she gets
out of this or not.
l care.
Doctor, we've given
the opposition
access to our computers
and station library
so let's utilize them ourselves.
l want you to find
all the medical evidence you can
to support the theory
that Jadzia Dax
and Curzon Dax are two
entirely separate people.
Major...
Excuse me, sir.
l don't know that there is
any medical evidence on that.
Assume there is, then find it.
Major, l'm not asking you
to be an attorney here
but if you could check
the Federation computers
for any precedents...
legal decisions
involving Trills.
ls a Trill responsible
for the conduct--
for the acts--
of its antecedent selves?
Right, that kind of thing.
What if l find
the answer is ''yes''?
Then that answer is wrong.
From this minute on,
our answer is ''no.''
But if you do find
a wrong answer...
l want to see it.
l can't fight
what l don't know about.
Commander Sisko, there's
a subspace communication
from Odo on Klaestron lV.
We only have a few hours,
people.
What have you got for us,
Constable?
Well, l know two things so far--
whoever did murder
that General Ardelon Tandro
it got his troops so mad
they went out
and won their civil war.
They made the general
a national hero.
There are statues of him
all over the place.
The second-- everyone
that's old enough to remember
says the General and Curzon Dax
were the closest of friends.
Comrades, inseparable.
Now that sounds
like the Curzon Dax l knew.
But treason...
plus the murder
of his own best friend?
Strange business.
lf those charges are true
l'd want to hang Curzon Dax
up by his heels myself.
Thanks for the confidence.
Don't worry.
l'll do my job.
The General left a widow.
lf the two men were that close
she has to remember something
about Curzon Dax
that's not in the record.
You'll hear from me.
Curzon Dax was not responsible
for the death of my husband.
You're certain of that?
Without a doubt.
But your own son...?
My son is obsessed
with the death of a father
he never knew.
Oh, l tried to persuade him
not to reopen the case.
He won't listen to anyone,
least of all to me.
You have to understand
Curzon Dax was closer
to the General
than any other man
on this planet.
He was a dear friend
to this family.
Curzon would have died himself
sooner than conspire
against my husband.
ls that a personal opinion
or are there any facts
that would support this?
The only facts l have
are in my son's hands
and he intends to use
them against Dax.
lt might help my people
to know what they are.
There is proof
of a secret transmission
that was made
from our military headquarters
to the enemy camp.
lt identifies exactly the route
my husband was taking
on his way back
from the capital to the front.
lt was at that time that he
was ambushed and kidnapped.
A short time later,
he was killed.
Then your son must believe
that Dax made the transmission.
There were only five people,
including my husband
who knew that route.
My son has established the
whereabouts of all of them
at the time of the transmission.
All of them except Curzon.
So Dax has no alibi.
That cannot possibly be
enough to convict him.
Can it?
l don't know.
Thank you.
You've been helpful.
How is he?
Ma'am?
Curzon Dax.
He's gone.
The Dax your son is
trying to extradite
is Jadzia Dax
a 28-year-old woman.
Curzon Dax died two years ago.
Jadzia is the new host.
Wha...?
l'm sorry.
l didn't know.
Madam Arbiter, l call
on the expert knowledge
of another Trill, Selin Peers.
Minister Peers
we're fortunate
to have you with us.
Excuse me, it also seems
rather convenient
to have you with us.
How do you come here?
Because another Trill
is involved
the Trillian government
requested that l be present
during the extradition.
And do you know
the accused personally?
l do not.
We accept you
as an expert on Trills.
Proceed.
Minister
through how many hosts
have you survived?
The symbiont within me
has survived
through the adult lifetimes
of seven hosts.
Do you remember
your very first host?
Of course.
lt was a woman,
as a matter of fact.
Do you remember
what you thought and felt
when you were joined
with your first host?
Yes. The symbiont
does carry memories
of time shared
with previous hosts.
So, if a crime
is committed by a Trill
then the symbiont's next host
would remain aware of it--
would recall that crime.
Yes. Absolutely.
Would recall the details of it.
Yes, absolutely.
And would still
feel the guilt of it.
Oh, yes.
Madam Arbiter,
this is not a trial
and Mr. Tandro is
not the prosecutor.
Mr. Tandro,
you have made your point.
l don't believe that l have,
Madam Arbiter.
The real point is
that Commander Sisko
would have you endorse his idea
of a perfect Trill crime.
To commit it, all one has to do
is elude capture long
enough to change hosts
and then he or she can go free.
Minister Peers, you've said
you were with your first host
throughout her adult life.
Yes.
So, before a symbiont
is joined with any host
that host has lived
a significant portion
of his or her life
from birth to what age, sir?
Early to mid-20s.
Why not younger?
To give the prospective host
a chance to develop, mature.
They have to be old enough
to make an informed judgment
as to whether or not
they really want to be joined.
And once they are joined,
this host's personality
is completely suppressed
by the symbiont.
Oh, no.
No, it's a joining.
lt's a total sharing--
a blending
of both symbiont and host.
Neither is suppressed
by the other.
So with each new host
there does come, in fact,
a new personality--
a new combined person...
a different person.
From that standpoint, yes.
Well, l, for one, don't know
from what other standpoint
we could be talking about.
Thank you, Minister.
Just to return us
to what's important here,
Madam Arbiter
the accused can remember
any crimes he committed
as Curzon Dax
and nothing can be
truthfully asserted
in this hearing
that can alter that fact.
Yes. The memories were passed
to an entirely new host--
to an entirely
different person.
This is outrageous!
You-You can't let Dax
get away with murder!
Gentlemen, l said this would be
an informal hearing
not riotous.
We will take a two-hour recess.
The answer seems
simple enough to me--
split her down the middle.
Send the symbiont
back to stand trial
and keep the host here.
l'm afraid it's a bit more
complicated than that.
Oh, what a surprise.
Please enlighten me.
The symbiont and the host
are biologically interdependent.
93 hours after they've joined
neither can survive
without the other.
l see.
Proceed, Commander.
Doctor, you've heard
the arguments.
From a medical point of view
are Curzon Dax and Jadzia Dax
the same person?
Certainly not.
Aside from the gender change,
there's a marked difference
in blood types, metabolism,
nervous system
height, weight.
This is not at all relevant.
What is relevant, sir...
is my analysis
of the brain waves
of Curzon and Jadzia Dax.
Madam Arbiter.
As you can see, they are
distinctly different
which clearly illustrates
that Curzon and Jadzia
are two unique individuals.
Thank you, Doctor.
Doctor...
l've looked through
your research myself.
lt's quite impressive
for such a young man.
Thank you.
As a layman,
there are obviously things
l don't fully understand.
l'd be happy
to explain anything you wish.
Yes?
Well, exactly how does
the Trill brain work?
lt's quite complicated,
actually.
First of all, there are
two cerebral nuclei...
Two?
One in the symbiont
and one in the host.
Two brains.
And these two brains
talk to each other?
Like two computers
linked together.
That's very clear, Doctor.
Thank you.
Now, in your investigations
were you able to analyze the...
separate wave patterns
from each of these brains?
They don't function separately.
l didn't ask you
how they function, Dr. Bashir.
l asked if you could analyze
the two distinct patterns.
l don't see the relevance...
Could you?
Yes.
And have the brain wave patterns
of the symbiont changed
since it joined
with its new host?
With the available evidence,
there's no way of telling.
What's your best guess?
l wouldn't care to guess.
ln fact, is there evidence
of any change at all
in the symbiont since it joined
with its new host?
Yes or no.
No.
Thank you, Dr. Bashir.
You've been very helpful.
Any more witnesses,
Commander Sisko?
Yes, Madam Arbiter.
l'd like to call
the one person in this courtroom
who knew Curzon Dax.
Me.
You know where
the witness stand is.
With your permission
l'd like Major Kira
to direct the questions.
Tell us a little
about Curzon Dax, Commander.
He probably wasn't
the ideal Trill.
He drank a little too much.
He could be more interested
in women
than maybe he should have been.
l thought he was your friend.
l'm simply pointing out
that he was not at all
like the young woman
in this courtroom.
What was, exactly,
your relationship
with Curzon Dax?
He took a raw, young ensign
under his wing
and taught me to appreciate life
in ways
l'd never thought about before.
He taught me about art
and science and diplomacy.
Whatever sense of honor
l might have today
he nurtured.
Treason, murder-- he was
not capable of those things.
As you've already said
Commander,
this is not a trial.
l'm describing my friend,
Curzon Dax--
a man l knew very well.
On the other hand,
l can't tell you too much
about my new friend there.
We're really just getting
to know each other.
Commander, Starfleet officers
do have the reputation
of being honorable
and l judge you to be
an honorable man.
As an honorable man,
do you think this crime
should go unpunished?
l prefer no crime
to go unpunished.
Then, if it were possible,
even you would not argue
with punishing
the symbiont part of Dax.
How can you be so sure
that the symbiont
was the criminal influence?
What if it were the Curzon host
that was responsible?
Then the surviving symbiont
would be completely innocent.
No. They'd both be guilty.
You yourself have argued
that the two personalities
once joined, function as one.
Your own Dr. Bashir
confirmed it.
When you put salt in water
the two become indistinguishable
and inseparable.
l think you've just made
my point for me.
When the water boils off
the salt returns
to its original state.
Pour that same salt
into another liquid
and you have something
completely different.
Jadzia Dax
is an entirely new entity.
Following a one-hour recess
Lieutenant Dax will take
the witness stand.
One hour.
lf you won't defend yourself,
you're not going to testify.
lt's a hearing, not a trial.
She has no choice.
Sir.
Odo's on subspace.
lt's urgent.
l've made some progress.
Good.
Not good.
Since the transmission to
the enemy is the key evidence
l thought it might be
a good idea
to go through
all the communications logs
from headquarters
during that period.
l even found
Curzon Dax's records.
You can't tell me Curzon
would log in a communiqué
to the enemy.
No, nothing like that
but the log does show
a number of conversations
between Dax's office
and General Tandro's home.
They were close friends.
A number of the conversations
took place while the General
was away at the front.
-The wife.
Curzon Dax and Enina Tandro.
Maybe it was innocent.
Maybe he was just providing
a little emotional support
during tough times.
Or maybe they were
taking advantage
of the General's absence
to get a little closer.
lf they were having an affair
that translates into a pretty
solid motive for murder.
The conversations
were just the beginning.
l've also found records of gifts
of holidays spent at an inn
outside the capital.
Oh. What purpose
does this serve?
lt serves the truth.
Oh, the truth.
lf there's more to this
than meets the eye
l hope you'll explain,
because as it stands
this will severely hurt
Dax's defense.
My husband was not the hero
in life
that he was in death, Mr. Odo.
ln death, he became a legend
and l became a legend's wife.
There are people who did not
even know my husband
who still contact me.
Decades after his death,
they still mourn him.
But you don't.
No
because l knew the man
before he became a legend.
But l also know
my place in history.
My place is to carry on
bravely, never to remarry--
to represent my husband
at the banquets
given in his name.
But never, never to talk
about who he really was.
Because nobody
wants to hear that.
They may have to hear it now.
No matter what is said
they will still embrace
his memory...
for he was and always will be
the hero
who died for his people.
But perhaps it's time
for my place in history
to change.
You've been protecting
her reputation.
That's it, isn't it?
That's why you won't
even defend yourself.
There are worse things
than an illicit love affair.
Curzon didn't murder anybody.
He didn't commit treason.
Are you really willing
to commit suicide
over something done
in another lifetime?
That is what you're doing,
you know.
My God, Dax.
Young Tandro--
that wouldn't be your son?
You have an overactive
imagination, Benjamin.
Then what is it
that's holding you back?
Help me.
Damn it, if you were
still a man...
l see your temper
hasn't improved.
Don't talk to me
about my temper.
Curzon always
warned you about it.
You're not going
to get me off track here.
Do you remember
that Argosian Lieutenant
who threw a drink in your face?
And you knocked me down
with a right cross
before l could kill him.
l still have a little scar here
from your ring finger.
l tried on that ring
after Curzon died.
lt just slipped off my finger.
lf you don't help me, old man,
they're going to take you
because l don't know
any more arguments.
Then allow it to happen.
lt is my obligation
to protect the lives
of those in my command.
You ought to know that,
you taught it to me.
That was Curzon.
l'll stop trying to protect you
the minute you tell me
Curzon was guilty
of these charges.
l won't discuss it with you.
As for Enina Tandro
yes, l feel the shame
of Curzon's indiscretion.
When one of my kind
stumbles, Benjamin
it is a mistake
that's there forever.
l can't tell you
which part of Curzon Dax
couldn't stop himself
from acting shamefully
with another man's wife.
l can tell you...
that he did love her
for whatever that's worth.
Enough to kill her husband?
So you are questioning?
What else can l do?
Nothing, Benjamin.
Nothing at all.
Lieutenant Dax, you are either
200 years older than l am
or you're about the same age
as my great-granddaughter.
At first, l wondered
which of those you were.
Now, l am bothered
by the likelihood
that you may be both.
Let's finish this, Commander.
At what age did the host,
Jadzia
first want to be joined
as a Trill?
l wanted it since l was a child.
l worked very hard for it.
The competition to become
a Trill is very strong, then
among potential hosts?
Yes. lt's considered
a great honor.
How did the young Jadzia finally
become a host candidate?
By winning scholarships
competing against
other young people.
You're tested in countless ways.
lncluding psychological tests
to determine strength
of character
of the prospective host,
is that true?
Yes.
And the young Jadzia
excelled in those tests
of academics and character--
of psychological stability.
Yes.
lf you can remember other
things, remember that as well.
What academic degrees
do you hold, Lieutenant?
l hold Premier Distinctions
in exobiology, zoology
astrophysics and exoarchaeology.
How many of those degrees
did you earn
before being joined
with the symbiont Dax?
All of them.
As Jadzia.
Alone.
This brilliant and independent
young woman
has done nothing in her life
but contribute to her society.
Madam Arbiter
how can anyone justify
trying her for a crime
allegedly committed
by another entity
before she was even born?
This will only take a minute.
Lieutenant...
as a Trill candidate
did Jadzia fully understand
the responsibilities
to be assumed
upon becoming a Trill
and did you willingly
accept those responsibilities
and whatever consequences
they might entail?
Yes.
And would that not obviously
include the consequences
of criminal acts
committed by Curzon Dax?
May l speak?
And you are?
l am Enina Tandro
widow of General Ardelon Tandro.
This hearing is unnecessary.
The accusations are erroneous.
Mother, what are you
talking about?
Madam Arbiter,
Curzon Dax is accused
of sending a transmission
to the enemy
that betrayed my husband.
But l know where Curzon was
at the exact time
that transmission was sent.
He was... in my bed.
Mr. Tandro
you will want to reexamine
your extradition request.
Until then,
this hearing is adjourned.
lt was kind of you
to try and protect me...
someone you'd never even met.
There's much of Curzon
that's still a part of me--
that still remembers
what you had together.
But it was Curzon Dax
who swore himself to silence
to preserve the memory
of General Tandro, not Jadzia.
l felt it was important
to keep that promise.
The General's memory
is cherished by your people.
And it will continue to be.
Oh, no one will ever know
that he was the one
who tried to betray us
and that the rebels
killed him for the favor.
As for you, there is
one favor l would ask.
Of course.
Live, Jadzia Dax.
Live a long,
fresh and wonderful life.