Hey, Jake.
What's all this?
My science project.
l'm growing Bajoran
katterpods to find out
which hybrid yields
the biggest root.
That's it? You're just
going to watch it grow?
Yeah. Pretty neat, huh?
Hmm. Not bad.
But don't you think
it's a little low-tech?
l'm a low-tech kind of guy, Dad.
l still think
you can do something
a little more challenging.
lf you could do any
science project you wanted to
anything at all,
what would it be?
Learn how to pilot a runabout?
Well, that's not exactly
a science project, is it?
Second choice.
Visit the Gamma Quadrant?
And what would you do
when you got there?
l don't know. l...
l could do a planetary survey.
Not bad.
All right, let's do it.
Really?
lt'll be like a vacation,
a working vacation.
That's great!
Thanks, Dad.
l'll bet we'll have
a great time.
l know we will.
Let's see.
We have a Bolian freighter
due in day after tomorrow.
We'll be outfitting
another group of settlers
leaving for New Bajor.
You know, l heard
their new irrigation system
is really something to see.
When you get
to the Gamma Quadrant
you ought to take a look.
Not this trip.
l really want to spend
some time alone with Jake.
When's the Odyssey due back
from the Cardassian border?
Three days.
lt's a shame l'll have to miss
your reunion with Captain Keogh.
Don't you find him
just a little arrogant?
Funny... he said
the same thing about you.
Did he?
Commander, your son's
here to see you.
Send him in.
He's really looking
forward to this trip.
Dad, guess what?
l was talking to Nog
and it turns out
he's having trouble
coming up
with a science project
so l told him
he could be my partner.
We can finish this up later.
Partner?
We asked Mrs. O'Brien,
and she said it would be okay
so l invited Nog to come
with us to the Gamma Quadrant.
Now, hold on a second, Jake-o.
Dad, if Nog doesn't get
a good grade
on this science project
he's going to drop out
of school.
And l can't let that happen.
Maybe he can help you analyze
the survey information
when we get back.
That's not enough.
Mrs. O'Brien said he'd have
to be an equal partner.
Come on, Dad.
He's my friend.
l have to help him.
Morn, you've been
sitting here all day
staring at the same drink.
Talk to me.
l want to help.
l'm not just your bartender,
l'm your friend.
Whatever's wrong,
l'm here for you.
Hold that thought.
Well, uh, what did he say?
What did who say?
Commander Sisko--
about my idea.
You mean using the monitors
throughout the station
to sell merchandise?
Stop torturing me, Odo.
Tell me what he said.
Guess.
He said yes.
Guess again.
lt would triple my profits.
How could he refuse?
Maybe it's because
he doesn't like you.
Don't be ridiculous.
Major Kira is the one
that doesn't like me.
Sisko...
Doesn't like you either.
What'd l ever do to him?
Oh, l could think
of one or two things.
Oh, one or two things,
that's nothing.
So, do you think there's any way
l can change his mind?
Uncle Quark?
Not now.
l just wanted to tell you
l'm not going to be able
to work my shift
for the next couple of days.
Why not?
l-l'm going
to the Gamma Quadrant
with Jake and his father.
You're going
to the Gamma Quadrant
with Commander Sisko.
How lucky for you.
Oh, l always wanted to see
what the cockpit
of a runabout looked like.
Hey, how do you fire
the phasers?
Nog, you promised.
Oh, l wasn't going
to touch anything.
Why don't the two of you
stow our gear away in the back
while l go through prelaunch?
l'll do it.
l'll be right there.
''Fire the phasers''?
He was just kidding.
Look, Dad, l know
this isn't exactly
the trip you planned on
but you'll see--
Nog's a great guy.
l'm sure he is.
l was just hoping that you and l
could spend this time together.
We will. Don't worry.
You won't even
know Nog's along.
This'll be a great
trip, you'll see.
Ah, there you are.
Where do l put my bags?
Uncle Quark,
what are you doing here?
What does it look like?
l'm going with you.
Since when?
Really, Commander,
you don't expect my nephew
to go all the way
to the Gamma Quadrant
without proper supervision?
No offense--
some of my best friends
are humans--
but my brother, Rom,
isn't as liberal as l am.
Let's face it--
he's never been comfortable
about Nog's friendship
with your son.
You can tell Rom not to worry.
l'll take good care of the boy
and l promise l won't try
to corrupt him
with my human values.
l know that
but Rom is convinced all humans
look down upon Ferengi
and by allowing me
to come on this trip
you can help prove him wrong.
He is wrong, isn't he?
Dad, please.
All right.
Let's get going
before anyone else shows up.
Thanks, Dad, thanks.
Whoo-hoo.
This place is great.
Our preliminary surveys suggest
it's a lot like Earth
during the early
Devonian period--
a lot of plant life,
fish, some insects
but no predators
or large animals.
Pretty, isn't it?
l don't see
what's so pretty about it.
l think they mean
the trees and stuff.
Quark, this is
as close to paradise
as you're going to get.
All you need to do is to allow
yourself to see it.
l'll tell you what l see.
ln two words--
exploitable resources.
l suppose you want
to cut down all these trees
and start strip mining
the entire planet.
As a wise man once wrote
''Nature decays,
but latinum lasts forever.''
Rule of Acquisition
Number 102.
Good lad.
Nog, l have some ointment
in one of my bags. Get it.
What's the problem?
Oh, l get a mild reaction
now and then.
To what?
Nature.
Perhaps you'd be
more comfortable
sleeping on the runabout.
And miss all the fun?
Never.
Besides, l'm really
looking forward
to our getting to
know each other better.
Ah, that's much better.
Now, if it only wasn't so hot.
l hadn't noticed.
lt isn't the heat so much
as the humidity and the insects
the stench of these flowers.
l'm glad we could
talk like this.
There's nothing like
facing the wilderness
to bring people closer.
The answer is still no, Quark.
No? No to what?
l'm not going to allow you
to sell merchandise
over the station's monitors.
Why not?
lt's a brilliant idea.
With my connections
l could offer
a whole range of merchandise
which normally couldn't
be acquired in this sector.
Such as?
Collectibles...
Andorian jewelry
Vulcan lDlC pins
Bolian crystalsteel...
And with my low overhead
l could offer these items
at a significant discount.
Quark, you're wasting
your time and mine.
Ah, ah, ah...
Did l mention
l was going to donate
two percent of my net profits
to the Bajoran Fund for Orphans?
Three percent?
So, how's it going?
The atmosphere
is 77% nitrogen
21% oxygen
and 2% carbon dioxide.
The water contains
traces of copper, nickel
and a little birythium.
You're showing
a little lead there, too.
That's from
the surrounding soil
but we think it's localized.
We're going to check
other water sources,
just to be sure.
Why not wait until tomorrow?
l was just about
to start dinner.
Jambalaya?
How did you know?
Great!
Jambawhat?
You're going to love it.
The two of you
did good work today.
Yes!
Anyone want some more?
Not me.
Oh, me neither, Commander,
but it was very good.
You know, l think
l'm developing a taste
for human food.
Quark?
l still say there's
some dirt in the sauce.
And these bugs.
Look at this.
They get into everything.
lt's disgusting.
l thought the Ferengis
liked eating bugs.
Only certain bugs--
Ferengi bugs.
Nog, get some more ointment
for the back of my neck.
Yes, Uncle.
Better get a good night's sleep.
You have another
big day tomorrow.
Yeah, l want to start
cataloging the plant life
first thing in the morning.
You know what this reminds of?
Hmm.
The camping trip we took
on ltamish lll.
l don't think
l remember you, me and Mom
ever having more fun together.
Hmm.
lsn't that where l taught
you how to water ski?
Mom taught me
how to water ski.
Yes. She always was
the graceful one.
You know, Jake...
we really need to get away
more often.
l'm ready whenever you are.
l'm sure Nog is, too.
l'm joking.
l'm on fire!
Quark!
Cover it up!
Are you all right?
No!
l am not all right.
My ears itch,
my nose is running
l'm eating foreign bugs!
Now look at me!
One minute l'm trying
to pick a couple of bugs
out of that jumba-what's-a-pot
the next thing l know--
whoosh!
Quark, calm down.
Look, do us all a favor.
Sit down and try
to stay out of trouble.
What did l do?
l'd better go see if he's okay.
Now, see what you've done.
What l've done?
The boy couldn't stand seeing
his favorite uncle insulted.
l guess Rom was right after all.
You don't like Ferengi, do you?
That is not true.
All right.
Name me one Ferengi
you do like.
Aha! You see?
l was right.
You Federation types
are all alike.
You talk about tolerance
and understanding
but you only practice it
towards people who remind
you of yourselves.
Because you disapprove
of Ferengi values
you scorn us, distrust us
insult us
every chance you get.
Quark, l don't have to stand
here and defend myself.
Tell me, Commander.
Would you allow your son
to marry a Ferengi female?
l never thought about it!
Exactly my point.
Don't hurt me.
How many of them are there?
There's just the two of us.
Not you, the Jem'Hadar.
We don't know
who you're talking about.
We are not your enemies.
Then you'd better run.
lt's too late.
You're done running.
This has not been a good day.
Dad, this is Jake.
Where are you?
Dad, answer me.
l'm telling you, Jake,
something's happened to them.
Maybe they were attacked
by a wild animal.
You heard my dad.
There aren't any wild animals
just insects and plants.
Maybe they were attacked
by a vicious tree.
Hmm... take a look at this.
l don't know any trees
that wear boots.
We'd better beam up
to the runabout.
Listen, we can't run away
just 'cause we're scared.
Hey, who said anything
about being scared?
l just thought the runabout
would be a good place
to, uh, to plan our next move.
There's nothing to plan.
My dad never would
have left here
without telling me first.
Not unless he was in
some sort of trouble.
We can track him
with the tricorder.
Hmm...
Hey! Wait for me!
Hey!
ls anybody there?
Hello?
We're humanoids.
We require food and water.
Hello?
Quark, shut up.
This is your fault.
They were after you, not us.
Why don't you say
something to them?
Tell them you'd
never seen us before.
We have nothing
to do with her.
This is a misunderstanding.
Quark...
l have the right
to express my opinion.
l'm about to put my fist
in your opinion.
You don't scare me.
And you want to know why
you don't scare me?
Because l'm already
more scared
than l've ever been
in my life.
You're not helping anything.
l'm not helping anything?
l don't see you coming up
with any ideas, or her.
lf she wants to help us,
she will.
Right now, l'd say she's even
more scared than you are.
Believe me, she's not.
She's obviously been running
from these people for a while.
She's probably
been through a lot.
She doesn't know who we are
or what we're about.
l just hope that Jake and Nog
are smart enough
to stay out of sight
until help gets here.
Trust me, l didn't raise
my nephew to be a fool.
He'll find the nearest dark
hole and climb into it.
l'm not so sure about Jake.
lf l know him,
he'll be looking for us.
Don't they teach you
how to neutralize
security fields
in Starfleet?
l've never seen anything
like this before.
lt seems to be generated by...
Don't.
The security barrier
will kill you.
Thanks for the warning.
l have no wish
to see you hurt.
A lovely sentiment.
How did you know
that the security
barrier is lethal?
Because everything about
the Jem'Hadar is lethal.
Anything you could tell me
about them might be helpful.
Are you saying you've never
heard of the Jem'Hadar?
Oh, we're not
from around here.
My name is Benjamin Sisko.
l'm from the United Federation
of Planets.
We came through
a wormhole to get here.
Our home is thousands
of light years away.
My name is Eris.
l'm glad to meet you...
Eris.
That's Quark.
Tell me about the Jem'Hadar.
They are the most feared
soldiers in the Dominion.
The Dominion?
The Ferengi have been trying
to open up trade negotiations
with the Dominion
for almost a year now.
We've never heard
of the Jem'Hadar.
Then you've been fortunate.
Negotiations with the Dominion
can be a dangerous thing.
lf it's so dangerous, why would
anyone do business with them?
The Dominion decides that you
have something that they want
and then they come and take it
by negotiation or by force.
Believe me, l know.
l've seen it happen
on my own world.
Kurill Prime was offered entry
into the Dominion.
They thought
our telekinetic powers would be
useful to them.
Back there in the camp--
that's what you used
to knock me down.
When Kurill refused
the Dominion's offer
they sent in the Jem'Hadar.
They destroyed
our communication center
they executed our leaders
and before we realized it
they had seized control
of the entire planet.
How did you manage to escape?
l was on a freighter
going home
when the attack occurred.
We fled, but they came after us.
Why?
My mother was an outspoken
opponent of the Dominion.
l guess they wanted to make
an example of my family.
That thing they put
around your neck...
lt suppresses
my telekinetic abilities.
Without it, l might be able
to break though
the security barrier.
Then we'll just have to find
a way to get this collar off.
Well, even if we get past
the barrier
no one ever escapes
from the Jem'Hadar.
Luckily for us, they seem
as sure about that as you do.
Look around you.
They placed the three of us
in the same containment field.
l've never seen more than four
guards on duty at any one time.
As far as l can tell
there's only this single
containment field
between us and freedom.
They're overconfident
and that's what's going
to help us get out of here.
Maybe if l can pry off
that casing
l can get at
the locking mechanism.
May l?
Of course.
You sure you know
how to read that thing?
Pretty sure.
Pretty sure?
We've been walking for hours,
and you're only pretty sure?
Would you be quiet?
l'm picking up some kind
of humanoid life-forms.
l don't know who they are
but they don't look friendly.
l wish we could get closer.
l don't think they'll look
any friendlier close up.
Hello?
l know someone must be
listening to me out there.
lf we escape, do we have
to take him with us?
He's not so bad.
Whoever's in charge
you're missing a very
lucrative opportunity...
Doesn't he realize he's not
accomplishing anything?
Don't be so sure.
We need to know
what the Jem'Hadar
plan to do with us
which means we need
to get their attention.
And if there's
one thing l know...
That's enough.
...it's that Quark
is hard to ignore.
l'm Commander Benjamin Sisko
of the United Federation
of Planets.
l want to know why we
are being held here.
That's not my concern.
Then why won't you let us go?
Because the Founders
don't want you released.
And who are the Founders?
That's not your concern.
This isn't getting
us anywhere.
Commander, allow me.
How would you like
a thousand cases
of tulaberry wine?
Don't bother, Commander.
l'm not going to do
any permanent damage.
lf the Founders are the ones
who give the orders
l want to meet them.
Those aren't my orders.
He can't take you
to the Founders
because they don't exist.
They're a myth.
The Founders exist.
They created the Dominion.
And the Jem'Hadar
are their servants?
A Ferengi and a human.
l was hoping
the first race l'd meet
from the other side
of the anomaly
would be the Klingons.
l'm sorry to disappoint you.
lt's too late for apologies.
The Dominion will
no longer stand by
and allow ships from your side
to violate our territory.
l hear the Klingons
are effective warriors.
What's that weapon they're
so fond of... the bat'leth?
l am not interested
in discussing the Klingons.
All right.
Then what about the Cardassians?
Are you satisfied
with the treaty
your Federation made with them?
lt seems a tactical error.
How do you know so much
about our side of the galaxy?
We gain more knowledge every day
and now we have you
to help us learn more.
l don't plan
on telling you anything.
l won't be the one asking
the questions.
Who will?
l was really hoping
to meet a Klingon.
Well, now that
we're all friends
l feel so much better.
l hope this works.
You wanted a plan,
l came up with a plan.
Now let me concentrate.
Computer, scan the region
around our base camp
for human and
Ferengi life-signs.
One human
and one Ferengi located.
That's them.
l told you this would work.
Computer, lock onto
the two life-forms
and beam them up.
Unable to comply.
Subjects are located inside
a spatial distortion field.
l knew it couldn't be
that easy.
Maybe we'd better go back
to the station for help.
Good idea.
Computer, fly us back
to the station.
Please restate command.
Computer, disengage autopilot
and lay in a course
back to the wormhole.
Enter authorization code.
Go ahead.
What are you waiting for?
l don't know
the authorization code!
Vessel approaching
from the planet's surface
bearing 173 mark 281.
Computer, evasive maneuvers!
Fire phasers!
Launch torpedoes...
and escape pods!
Computer, display
the approaching ship
on the monitor.
Computer, where did the ship go?
The vessel has entered warp
bearing 17 1 mark 259.
Oh, maybe they didn't see us.
Maybe we're not
what they're after.
So, what do we do now?
We'll have to shut down
the autopilot.
How do we do that?
l guess we'll find out
how much l learned
working for Chief O'Brien.
Lieutenant, what's the ETA
on the Odyssey?.
They're due in eight hours.
l'm reading
elevated neutrino levels
from the wormhole.
On screen.
Hail them, Lieutenant.
They're not answering.
Shields up.
Go to Yellow Alert.
Computer, intruder in Ops.
Activate a level-3
containment field.
l'm Major Kira Nerys,
First Officer of this station.
You'll have to excuse
the containment field
but, around here, it's customary
to identify yourself
before transporting
into someone else's
command center.
l'm Third Talak'talan
of the Jem'Hadar.
l'm here to inform you
that your Commander
has been detained
for questioning by the Dominion.
Detained?
For how long?
lndefinitely.
Commander Sisko will serve
as an example
of what happens to anyone who
interferes with the Dominion.
What kind of interference
are you talking about?
Coming through the anomaly
is interference enough.
Unless you wish to continue
to offend the Dominion
l suggest you stay
on your side of the galaxy.
You're making a mistake
if you think
that detaining Commander Sisko
will stop us
from exploring
the Gamma Quadrant.
We anticipated that response.
Security team to Ops.
Here's a list of vessels
we've destroyed
for violating our territory.
Where'd you get this datapadd?
From the Bajoran colony
on our side of the anomaly.
You should be proud.
l hear they fought well
for a spiritual people.
l hope we won't have to repeat
this lesson.
Chief, lock a tractor beam
onto his ship.
Acknowledged.
l can't establish a lock, Major.
They must have
some kind of deflectors
we haven't seen before.
They've entered the wormhole.
We've lost them.
Got it.
lt looks like some kind
of multiple-locking system.
Even if l can break through
the security barrier
how do you plan
to get off the planet?
We'll try to find my son.
We'll use his communicator
to signal my ship and transport
us off the surface.
And then what?
You're welcome to come back
to the station with us.
l'm sure Starfleet would
like to hear anything
you have to tell them
about the Dominion.
l'd be glad to tell them
all l know.
Quark
maybe you'd better
take a look at this.
Sure.
''Quark, be quiet.
Quark, stand watch.
Quark, pick a lock.''
All you ever do
is order me around.
You know, Commander,
l think l've figured out
why humans don't like Ferengi.
Not now, Quark.
The way l see it
humans used to be a lot
like Ferengi-- greedy
acquisitive, interested
only in profit.
We're a constant reminder
of a part of your past
you'd like to forget.
Quark, we don't
have time for this.
But you're overlooking
something.
Humans used to be a lot
worse than the Ferengi--
slavery...
concentration camps
interstellar wars.
We have nothing in our past
that approaches
that kind of barbarism.
You see?
We're nothing like you.
We're better.
Now... if you'll excuse me...
l have a lock to pick.
This shouldn't be so hard.
l just watched Chief O'Brien
run a maintenance check
on the Mekong's navigational
array a couple of weeks ago.
Well, from the looks of things
you haven't been
watching very closely.
Try that one.
l don't think that's it.
Try it.
l have a hunch.
All right.
Let's see.
Warning. Warp core collapse
in ten seconds.
Nine, eight...
Put it back,
put it back!
...seven, six...
Warp core containment field
stabilized.
Sorry.
Wait a second...
the ''G and N'' relay.
What about it?
l think O'Brien said something
about the autopilot
being connected
to the guidance
and navigational relay.
lf l could just find it...
lt was this round thing,
with this square part
on the bottom.
l think l got it.
ls that it?
l hope so.
Computer, what's the status
on the autopilot?
The automatic pilot system
is not functional.
All right!
Yes!
Lay in a course for the wormhole
at warp eight.
Unable to comply.
The automatic pilot system
is not functional.
Now what?
l guess we'll have to try
and fly it ourselves.
Starfleet's orders are simple.
Traffic through the wormhole
will be suspended
until the Odyssey
can investigate
the Jem'Hadar's threat.
What about Benjamin
and the others?
Don't worry, Lieutenant.
Commander Sisko's return
is a top priority.
lf you're going to try
to rescue them
then we're coming with you.
Are you sure that's wise?
With the exception
of Major Kira and Mr. O'Brien
none of you have had
much combat experience.
We fought the Maquis.
All the Maquis had were a pair
of lightly-armed shuttlecraft.
l expect the Dominion
to have sharper teeth.
Well, then you're
going to need
all the help you can get.
Mr. O'Brien, can you equip
the two remaining runabouts
with extra banks
of photon torpedoes?
l already started retrofitting
their weapons systems.
They should be ready
in a few hours.
lt should take
at least that long
to off-load all the nonessential
personnel from the Odyssey.
You were planning on doing that,
weren't you?
Lieutenant,
have you ever thought
of serving on a starship?
l'm happy where l am.
Good.
Major, be prepared
to leave at 1300 hours.
l'll be aboard the Odyssey
if you need me.
Yes, sir.
l thought you said
Keogh didn't like you.
Did l say that?
Come on, you heard him.
We've got three hours.
Station security is
to be on maximum alert.
l want random patrols
of all corridors
and periodic sensor sweeps
of every level.
Now, the provisional government
has agreed to send us
a detachment
of extra security personnel.
This outlines
how l want them deployed.
Odo.
Major.
That will be all.
Captain Keogh has moved up
our departure time.
We have to be ready
in 15 minutes.
l am on my way
to meet Chief O'Brien
and Lieutenant Dax
at the Mekong right now.
Are you sure that you
don't want to stay
and oversee things
here on the station?
l don't know what we're
going to come up against
once we're there.
Your duties do not
require you to come with us.
l realize that, but l figure
while you and the others
are trying to rescue
Sisko and the boys
someone ought to be there
to look out for Quark.
Quark?
Huh.
You're joking.
l thought you hated Quark.
l do, but l'd rather
see him in jail
than in the hands
of the Dominion.
Believe me, Major
if anything happened to him
you'd miss him, too.
l'd be willing to take
that chance...
but not today.
l'd better get to the Orinoco.
Odo...
keep your head down.
Make sure you do the same.
Where's the welcoming
committee?
Maybe the Jem'Hadar
were bluffing.
Or maybe it's a trap.
Odyssey to runabouts.
Go ahead, Captain.
Preliminary tachyon
scans are negative.
We're not detecting anything
on long-range scanners
but, for all we know
the Dominion could have
cloaking technology.
We'll keep our eyes open.
l'm telling you, Jake,
we should go to warp.
First, let me get the hang
of flying at impulse.
How hard can it be?
Are you kidding?
You think making course
corrections manually is easy?
But, at this speed, it'll
take weeks to get home.
Actually, it'll
take about five years.
Can't we reassemble
the autopilot?
lf Chief O'Brien
taught me anything
it's that it's a lot easier
taking things apart
than putting them
back together.
Warning. Three ships
coming out of warp.
Where? Where?
Right there!
Mekong to Rio Grande.
Hey, Chief, it's me, Jake.
Jake, are we glad to find you.
Where's your father?
He and Quark
were taken prisoner.
Jake, come to a full stop.
l'll beam aboard.
Having trouble
getting it out of orbit?
How'd you know?
Chief, we have to go back
and save my dad.
Don't worry, son.
That's exactly
what we're going to do.
This is a very
sophisticated device.
Most telepathic
suppressers l've seen
have been much bulkier.
You know, there might
be a market for this
on the Alpha Quadrant.
You're hurting me.
l'm sorry, but l don't
have much to work with.
You've been at it for hours.
lf you would just stay
still, l'd be... done.
All right,
let's get out of here.
Stand back.
Quark, move it!
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Let's go.
Major, l'm picking up something
on forward scanners.
Odyssey to runabouts.
Go ahead, Odyssey.
We're detecting
three incoming ships
in attack formation.
Shields up.
Going to Red Alert.
Odo, take the helm.
l'll handle
the targeting controls.
Very good.
Captain, this is the Rio Grande.
Go ahead.
Half the systems in this ship
are disabled.
l'm going to have
to break formation.
Understood.
Return to the wormhole.
We'll try to screen you
from enemy fire.
Well, what about my dad?
Captain, l'd like to see
if l can get
close enough to the planet
to locate Commander Sisko.
All right,
but you have ten minutes.
Then l want you out of there.
Enemy ships within range.
Ready to fire at your command.
Runabouts, break formation,
attack pattern delta.
Here they come.
l'm getting casualty reports
from decks 4, 5, 8 and 17.
We also have a plasma leak
in our port nacelle.
Deploy damage-control teams.
Aye, sir!
Keogh to runabouts.
Go ahead.
They're using some kind
of phased polaron beam
to penetrate our shields.
Have you tried altering
your harmonics to compensate?
We've run through
the entire spectrum
but none of the frequencies
were effective.
Divert shield power to weapons.
We'll give O'Brien
five more minutes.
Then we're getting out of here!
Understood.
Dax, let's see if we can take
some pressure off the Odyssey.
We're with you.
Hang on.
Wait... stop.
l've got to start using
one of those holosuite
exercise programs.
He's slowing us down.
He can hide in the underbrush.
We'll transport him to safety
once we get to your ship.
No, l'm not leaving
him behind.
We never would have
gotten away
from the Jem'Hadar
without him.
Thank you, Commander.
l'm glad someone around here
appreciates me.
Dad!
This has turned into some
science project, huh, Jake?
Uncle Quark!
Nog, you're never going
on a field trip again.
Take Eris back
to the passenger compartment
and wait there.
Jake...
well done.
My controls are dead.
We've lost our sensors!
Break off, Mekong.
lnitiate evasive maneuvers.
We'll lay down covering fire.
Acknowledged!
Rio Grande to Odyssey.
We've got Sisko.
Well done, Chief.
Damage control team
to level 7.
Our tactical control
system is down.
We've lost all power to phasers.
Bridge to Engineering!
Get that port nacelle
back on line.
Aye, sir.
Keogh to runabouts,
we've got what we came for.
We'd better fall back
before we...
Their communications array
must have been hit.
Kira, Dax, you heard him.
Let's get out of here.
Major, one
of the Jem'Hadar ships
is making a direct run
at the Odyssey.
Move to intercept.
We were retreating.
There was no need
for a suicide run.
They're showing us how far
they're willing to go.
Set a course for the wormhole.
Commander, wait.
We need to talk.
l can't believe
l'm on the other side
of the galaxy.
You'll get used to it.
Move away from her.
l don't understand.
l've been looking over
this collar of yours.
l thought if l replicated it
l might be able
to turn a tidy profit.
lmagine my surprise
when l discovered
there's nothing in here.
lt's just a complicated
locking device.
Which means you could have used
your telekinetic abilities
at any time.
So the question is,
why didn't you?
You seem to already
know the answer.
The Jem'Hadar wanted us
to escape, didn't they?
That was the plan all along--
for us to bring you back here
so you could spy
on the Federation.
Well done, Commander.
You're one of the Founders,
aren't you?
You think the Founders
would waste their time with you?
Constable.
Madam, if you'll come with us.
You have no idea
what's begun here.
Chief!
l'm picking up
a transporter signature
but l can't trace it.
She didn't rematerialize
anywhere on the station
and there are no ships nearby.
Then where is she?
She'll be back.
The question is
who she'll bring with her.
lf the Dominion
comes through the wormhole
the first battle
will be fought here
and l intend
to be ready for them.