lt's Dr. Bashir, isn't it?
Of course it is.
May l introduce myself?
Uh... yes.
Yes, of course.
My name is Garak.
A Cardassian by birth,
obviously.
The only one of us left
on this station
as a matter of fact.
So l do appreciate making
new friends whenever l can.
You are new to the station,
l believe.
l am, yes.
Though...
though l understand
you've been here quite a while.
Ah. You know of me then.
Would you care
for some of this Tarkalean tea?
lt's very good.
What a thoughtful young man.
How nice that we've met.
You know...
some people say
that you remained on DS9
as the eyes and ears
of your fellow Cardassians.
You don't say.
Doctor-- you're not intimating
that l'm some sort of spy,
are you?
l wouldn't know, sir.
Ah. An open mind--
the essence of intellect.
As you may also know
l have a clothing shop nearby
so if you should
require any apparel
or simply wish, as l do
for a bit of enjoyable
company now and then
l'm at your disposal, Doctor.
You're very kind, Mr. Garak.
Oh, it's just Garak--
plain, simple...
-Garak.
Now, good day to you, Doctor.
l'm so glad to have made
such an interesting
new friend today.
You won't believe
who just sat down
next to me in the Replimat.
Major, Upper Pylon 3
will be shut down for
maintenance for 48 hours.
The spy.
Garak, the Cardassian.
We don't know for a fact
Garak's a spy, Doctor.
He is.
You should have heard him.
He-He introduced himself
and, and, and he struck up
conversation just like that.
He was making contact with me.
With me, of
all people.
What do you think
he might want from you, Julian?
l don't know...
Federation medical secrets.
Rest assured, they're safe
with me, Commander.
l'm sure they are, Dr. Bashir.
ln fact, Chief O'Brien
l think you should place
a monitoring device on me.
Well, just in case...
he...
he's up to something?
l don't think that will be
necessary, Doctor.
Just be very cautious when...
Commander, we have a small craft
taking evasive action.
Cardassian war vessel
in pursuit.
On screen.
That's Bajoran.
That damned Cardassian's
firing at a Bajoran scout ship
in Bajoran space.
Mr. O'Brien?
Confirmed, sir.
They've crossed
into Bajoran space.
Open a hailing frequency
to the Cardassians.
Channel open.
Cardassian vessel,
you are violating Bajoran space.
Break off your pursuit.
Repeat: break off now.
No reply from the Cardassians.
Bajoran vessel is hailing us.
Open the channel.
Space station, do you read?
Space station...
We can only get audio,
Commander.
This is Benjamin Sisko
Starfleet Commander
of the station.
Who are you?
Why are they pursuing?
Please! Repeating request
for emergency docking. Please!
The Bajoran scout ship
is badly damaged.
Structural integrity is failing.
He's breaking up.
Get him out, Mr. O'Brien.
Aye, sir.
Medical assistance to Ops.
My name is Tahna Los.
Request political asylum.
Kira?
His name is Tahna Los.
We fought together
in the underground.
Commander, the Cardassians
are hailing us.
Now they want to talk.
They're hopping mad.
Open the channel, Mr. O'Brien.
Federation Commander
you have taken aboard
a known criminal.
You will turn him over to us.
He has requested asylum.
You have not granted it?
To be honest,
l haven't decided yet.
He is Kohn-Ma.
Not even the Bajorans
would grant his kind asylum.
He has committed heinous crimes
against the Cardassian people
and l demand
that you release him
to our custody.
l'll investigate the matter
immediately.
ln the interim, if you care
to dock your vessel
l'll be glad
to hear an explanation
for having violated
Bajoran space
and threatened
a Federation facility.
We have made no threat
to your facility.
l stand corrected.
Sisko out.
The Major and l
will be at the lnfirmary.
l'd like some time to talk
with this fellow Tahna.
When Gul Danar comes in
it would be nice if we had
a few docking regulations
to keep him outside a while.
Understood.
You're not seriously considering
handing Tahna over
to the Cardassians?
Were you part of
this Kohn-Ma, Major?
lf l had been,
l would not be working
with the provisional
government now.
No, you'd still be out there
murdering Cardassians,
or even some Bajoran
that the Kohn-Ma
hold in contempt.
Didn't they claim responsibility
for the assassination
of one of your First Ministers
last month?
Look, l know Tahna.
ls he Kohn-Ma?
Yes, but...
l suggest you get your
priorities straight, Major
because l don't have any
room for divided loyalties
in this command
and l won't have
a Kohn-Ma terrorist
using this station
as a protective shield
for continuing violence.
My priorities are straight,
Commander.
Let's not be confused here.
My loyalties are to Bajor
and Bajor needs men
like Tahna Los.
Apparently, his war with the
Cardassians isn't over yet.
lf Bajor is ever to rebuild
a strong and independent
society
it will require the repatriation
of splinter groups
like the Kohn-Ma.
You have-- we have--
an opportunity here, Commander.
l hope you don't miss it.
How is he?
Second-degree burns, lacerations
a minor concussion.
Not much compared to what
he's been through before.
Before?
The most recent of these scars
is only two,
perhaps three years old.
Two and a half, actually.
lt's remarkable you
lived through this.
lt's a Cardassian technique
designed to keep you alive.
l'm Commander Benjamin Sisko.
l have a few questions
for you
if you're up to answering them.
Commander Sisko hasn't decided
whether or not to grant you
asylum yet, Tahna.
Major, perhaps l should
conduct this alone.
Major?
l'm the liaison officer
to the Federation here...
Still fighting for Bajor
in my own way.
l'll stop by later.
What do you need to know,
Commander?
For starters,
why were they chasing you?
You really want to hear
the story of my life?
l assume, as a member
of the Kohn-Ma
you've committed serious acts
against them.
Any one of a hundred
that would lead
to a Cardassian death sentence.
Any of them since
their withdrawal from Bajor?
Frankly, yes.
Why would you
continue the violence
against them now?
To be honest,
l'm not sure anymore.
We say we're punishing them
for crimes committed against us
for over half a century
but l've had enough
of the killing.
l'm sorry, Commander.
He needs rest now.
Admiral, l think Commander Sisko
is being incredibly
short-sighted.
He obviously doesn't understand
the issues involved.
Thank you for bringing this
to my attention, Major.
l'll stay in close touch
with the situation.
Thank you, Admiral.
Sir, the Cardassian warship
has docked.
Lieutenant Dax is making sure
that all procedural details
are precisely observed
no matter how long it takes.
Well done.
l have some more research
to do on the Kohn-Ma
before l see them.
Sir, l don't know much
about the Bajoran terrorists
but you've never fought
the Cardassians, have you?
No.
Well, you wouldn't want
to turn a man-- any man--
over to their tender care, sir.
You just wouldn't.
Subspace transmission
from Admiral Rollman
for you, Commander.
ln my office.
Ben, that Bajoran woman
you have working for you
interrupted a staff meeting
to tell me how she disapproves
of your handling
of this asylum matter.
l think you have
a problem there, Commander.
Yes, Admiral.
lt's all right.
You're safe.
Strange to run
into each other here, isn't it?
lt's good to be with someone
who knows what it's been like
out there.
Wearing that uniform,
l thought maybe you'd forgotten.
Never.
No?
Working on the inside
hasn't dulled
that old fire just a little?
Uh... ask Sisko about that.
Don't get along?
Oil and water.
You're tired.
l should go.
Kira?
Do you think he'll give me
to the Cardassians?
Over my dead body.
Now, that's the Kira l remember.
lf you require all vessels
to endure such lengthy
docking procedures, Commander
you're going to have
a lot of impatient traffic
out there.
l apologize.
We're still trying
to repair all the damage
your forces did
before they left.
lt does create
unreasonable delays.
l accept your apology,
but not your explanation.
What about Tahna Los?
Well, we've got a problem.
A diplomatic insult
to the Cardassian people
would be a problem.
Delivering a wanted criminal
to us would not be.
Danar, in war, both sides
commit atrocities.
l can only tell you
that we are certain
he plans to commit
more acts of terrorism.
He tells me that he has
renounced the Kohn-Ma
and wants to help
to rebuild Bajor.
He has committed brutal acts
of destruction and murder
and he must pay
for those crimes.
l appreciate
the Cardassian position
but l know if a Bajoran
freedom fighter
is turned over
to the Cardassians
by the Federation
that would be a mistake
that would undermine
everything that l'm trying
to accomplish here.
So, with apologies
l'm going to grant him asylum
for the time being.
Eventually, he'll want
to relocate to Bajor
and if you want
to pursue the matter
with the provisional government,
then that's your business.
How long since you've slept
in a comfortable bed?
l can adapt to that part
very quickly, thank you.
l'm glad you're here.
We need you, Tahna.
l don't think the Federation
has any use
for my particular talents.
l mean, Bajor needs you.
lf you had the impression
that l'm a Federation officer
in any way, l promise you, l...
l thought you were
under Sisko's command.
l am, but...
Now, you see, that's something
l could never adapt to.
Someone has
to coordinate relations
between the Federation
and the provisional government.
At least,
with someone like me here...
Why?
Why should they be here at all?
What right does this so-called
provisional government have
to bring them here after
all we fought for, Kira?
Freedom from domination.
True independence.
No outsiders.
No Cardassians
and no Federation.
Things have changed, Tahna.
With the discovery
of the wormhole...
Oh, yes, the wormhole.
Look, l don't want
the Federation here
any more than you do
but they are serving a purpose,
for the time being at least.
Without the Federation
the Cardassians would
be back in a minute
to take control of the wormhole
and the wormhole is
the future of Bajor, Tahna.
lt's bringing ships
and commerce.
lt's making us
a power in the quadrant.
l don't want to be a power
in the quadrant.
l want Bajor for Bajorans.
l want our homeland back.
We have it back.
And, as we grow stronger
we'll be able
to defend it ourselves
without having to lean
on the Federation
or anyone else.
l know it's difficult to see
after all we've been through.
We want it all now.
But with people like you
leading the way...
You have adapted, haven't you?
Tahna, l have put myself
on the line for you here.
You are finished
with the Kohn-Ma?
Yes.
Yes, l am finished
with the Kohn-Ma.
l've been talking
with several of the ministers
of the provisional government
about amnesty
for you and any member
of the Kohn-Ma who follows you.
Well, there are some
who might...
if there were assurances.
l'm working on it, Tahna.
l'll find a way
to make it happen.
What?
Sir, we've had a little problem.
These two women
are just arriving.
They objected to giving up
their weapons.
Klingons do not
surrender their weapons.
Who are you?
We are Lursa and B'Etor
of the house of Duras.
And we have
specific regulations.
You can leave the weapons
or leave the station.
Your choice.
Please make it now.
Who are you?
l'm the one
giving you the choice.
Welcome to DS9.
We have some new guests
you might be interested in.
A couple of Klingon sisters
from the Duras family.
Lursa and B'Etor.
You know them then?
They tried to grab control
of the Klingon High Council.
Started a brief civil war.
They've been out
of sight since then.
l ran a security check.
The Klingons have them
listed as renegades.
We've heard they've been
trying to raise capital
to rebuild their armies.
What are they doing here?
Sitting.
They went straight to Quark's,
but not for the gambling
and certainly not for the food.
They're just sitting.
l don't like it.
Why don't l... lock them up
and call the Klingons
to come get them?
Odo.
lf they're enemies
of the Klingon High Council...
They haven't broken
any laws here.
You can't just
throw them in jail.
You know, Cardassian rule
may have been oppressive
but at least it was simple.
Keep an eye on them.
As you wish, Commander.
And how are you this evening,
Mr. Garak?
Excuse me.
Just plain, simple Garak,
you said.
Plain and simple.
Join me, Doctor.
Enhance my evening.
Keeping an eye on the ebb
and flow of things, are you?
As a clothier,
l do have a keen interest
on what the population
is wearing from day to day.
Klingons have
an odd sense of style.
Don't you agree?
Oh, yes, they do.
But intriguing.
l would say
that those two outfits
are worth studying closely.
Look.
All right, where's the payment?
lt's on its way.
That was not the arrangement.
l couldn't stop to get it.
l barely got past
the Cardassians.
Your safety is not our concern.
Your gold is.
lt will be available tomorrow.
Good.
Because if we have made
this trip for nothing
you will have made
a fatal mistake.
l managed to arrange a hearing
of the Ministers' Court.
Any predictions?
Well, l have
two of the ministers--
the smart ones--
ready to vote for amnesty.
l'm sure one of the others
will fall in line.
Good.
And Tahna says
two more of the Kohn-Ma
are willing to follow him
if you'll guarantee
their safety.
Done.
l have to say this, Commander.
When we first talked,
l wasn't sure you...
This wouldn't have been possible
without your support.
l want you to know
it's appreciated.
Be sure to mention it
the next time you chat
with Admiral Rollman.
Sir?
Go over my head again
and l'll have yours
on a platter.
So, Constable, news
about our Klingon sisters?
They seem to make friends
easily.
Friends?
Our reformed Kohn-Ma,
for example.
Tahna, with Lursa and B'Etor?
Talking about
a business arrangement.
He's paying them for something.
l don't know what.
The gold is
supposedly on its way.
Two other members of the Kohn-Ma
may be bringing it.
How do you know that?
Major Kira mentioned
that they were on their way.
Do you want her
to know about this?
Not quite yet.
You are the clothier Garak?
At your service, madam.
May l show you some
of our latest fashions?
Perhaps some silk lingerie
from Kraus lV?
Watch your tongue,
Cardassian, or l'll
rip it out and eat it!
l meant no offense.
l have few Klingon patrons.
So, is there something
you wish to buy?
We're not here to buy.
We are here to sell.
We understand
you still represent
Cardassian interests here.
Ah, l am only a simple
clothing merchant.
We have no time for your games!
Do you want Tahna Los or not?!
Are you in a position
to deliver the Bajoran
to Cardassian authorities?
What is he worth to them?
ln gold-pressed latinum?
You insult us!
Ladies, ladies, please.
Everything is negotiable.
l am no more
than what l seem to be--
a merchant trying to make
the best transaction.
So... let us haggle.
Yes?
l have
the third minister's vote.
The hearing is simply
a formality now.
You are going
to receive amnesty, Tahna.
l never realized you were such
an accomplished politician.
Me? A politician?
No, l don't think so.
You manipulate Sisko
and the Federation
the ministers
of the provisional government...
l'm just determined.
l think they all simply
get tired of hearing my voice.
And here we expected to find
that Kira Nerys had lost
the fire in her heart.
What are you talking about?
You knew l was here
before you even came.
Tahna, l trusted you.
l am Kohn-Ma.
l fight for the freedom
of Bajor.
You once fought for it, as well.
l'm still fighting for it.
Stop deluding yourself!
You say you don't believe
in the Federation.
in the provisional government
and yet you are
their dance instructor.
That's not fair.
Don't be naive, Major!
l don't want the Federation
here, but, for now...
Once you're in your comfortable
bed with the Federation
you won't be able to get out.
We won't be able to get out.
lf you expect me to commit
some act of violence
against the Federation...
No... no, the violence is over.
That is the truth.
No one will get hurt in any way.
l promise you that.
But l do need your help.
You already lied to me, Tahna.
l know how the game works.
To do what we plan
we need a small ship
capable of warp speed.
l gambled that l could convince
you to get it for us.
And just what is
this peaceful plan?
ln one move, and nonviolently
we accomplish everything
both of us has ever wanted
for Bajor.
How?
l know the game, too, Kira.
You know l cannot risk
telling you that.
How do you know l won't
just go straight to Sisko?
Well, if you do,
then we'll both know
where your loyalties are
won't we?
Ah, plain, simple Garak.
How are you today?
Being observant, Doctor.
l'm sure of it.
There's a time for levity,
my young friend
and a time for genuine concern.
The arrival on this station,
for instance
of those two Kohn-Ma terrorists.
Terrorists?
What are they doing here?
l'm not exactly sure,
but, together
we might have some success
at finding out.
Garak, l'm a doctor, not...
And, once you do have
the appropriate answer
l'm sure you'll know
what to do with it.
l really must
be getting along now.
Uh... Doctor...
l think it's time for you
to take advantage of my shop.
lf you'll be there
at exactly 2055 hours tonight
l promise to show you a suit
that will make you
into a new man.
A suit?
We're talking about terrorists
and you want me
to buy a new suit.
Doctor, am l making
myself clear?
l want you to buy
a new suit tonight at 2055...
exactly.
Uh, yes.
l see.
Well, if you'll excuse me.
Mmm.
A suit.
Major.
Commander.
l'd like to meet the two Kohn-Ma
who just arrived
as soon as possible.
Of course.
l'll arrange it.
How do they seem to you?
Sir?
Do you feel as secure about them
as you do about Tahna Los?
Absolutely.
Commander Sisko.
l need some guidance.
Yes, Doctor.
lt's about Garak--
the Cardassian.
l'm afraid this relationship
has gotten a little out of hand.
How's that?
He wants me to buy a suit.
A suit?
At exactly 2055 tonight.
Why 2055?
l don't know,
but it has something to do
with those two Bajoran
terrorists on board.
He says that, together,
he and l might discover
what they're really doing here.
l don't understand
why he wants me involved.
Sometimes communications
can't be conducted
through official channels.
Maybe this is their way
of telling us
that we have a common enemy.
Well, what do you want me to do?
l think, Doctor, you could
definitely use a new suit.
Busy?
What can l do for you?
Are, um... are all
the security measures in place
for the trip
to the Ministers' Court?
l told you they'd be
taken care of and they will.
Fine.
You know, there's one thing
about you humanoids
l can't imitate very well.
What's that?
Pretense.
There's a special talent to it.
lt's as hard for me
as creating one of your noses.
Maybe that's why l've learned
to respect your opinion
Constable-- never any pretense.
How much do you know about me,
Odo?
More than you probably realize.
l've done some things
l'm not proud of.
l still have nightmares about
the raids on the Haru Outpost
but at least l was sure
about what l was doing then.
And...
there's something
you're not sure of now.
You have no more love
for the Federation than l do.
Meaning?
Maybe there are still wars
to be fought
and l'm just
making a fool of myself
doing what l'm doing here.
lt sounds like you're trying to
talk yourself into something...
or out of something.
Either way,
l have to betray someone.
The only important thing
is not to betray yourself.
How could l possibly turn
against my own people?
Are they
your own people?
They're no different
than l used to be.
Used to be?
l could just refuse
to help them--
ignore the whole thing.
The Joranian ostrich hides by
sticking its head underwater--
sometimes even until it drowns.
And they'd find a way
to do whatever
they want to do anyway
and l'd still feel responsible
for the consequences.
lt was so much easier
when l knew who the enemy was.
Odo to Sisko.
Go ahead.
There's someone down in here
in security
who wants to talk to you,
Commander.
Come in quickly, Doctor.
You're late.
lt's 2057.
Now just take this
and try it on
as many times as you like.
And stay very, very quiet.
l was just...
Ah, right on time.
Welcome.
Save your welcome, Cardassian.
Do your people
want the Bajoran or not?
l can now venture to say,
with some certainty
that you will receive
the agreed-upon payment
on delivery.
We will complete
our business with Tahna Los
in four hours.
And what business might that be?
That is not your concern.
lf it requires
that those l represent
must take extra precautions,
it becomes my concern.
We will deliver him
a cylinder of bilitrium.
The rendezvous will be
on the dark side
of Bajor Vlll's lower moon.
The Cardassians
can have him then.
What's bilitrium?
Ah, a rare, crystalline element
that can be an incredibly
powerful source of energy
provided, of course, one has
an antimatter converter.
Unfortunately,
that's why Cardassians
were chasing Tahna Los
when he arrived here.
He stole one.
But if he's got both...
Quite right, Doctor.
He has the ingredients
for a bomb--
a bomb of significant
destructive capability.
We have nothing to hold them on.
They haven't
committed any crime yet.
Conspiracy is a crime.
Conspiracy to what?
We don't even know
what their plan is.
Once the switch
with the Klingons is made
you've got them holding
the components
to an explosive device.
That's evidence
enough right there.
Chief O'Brien is right.
We have to give them
the runabout.
Agreed.
And l have to be on it.
Not agreed, Major.
Commander, Tahna doesn't know
if he can trust me as it is.
lf l try to stay behind,
he won't buy into this.
The only way to convince him
is if l'm on board.
lf Tahna fails
l promise you, others will try.
At least this way,
you can find out
what they're up to.
Mr. O'Brien,
you and l will take a runabout
to a point behind
the second moon of Bajor Vlll
to avoid detection.
Aye, sir.
Dax, stay in touch with us
on a secured channel.
Keep an eye on the Cardassians.
They'll be coming
to the party, too.
You get him there, Major.
We'll be waiting.
They're moving
into the runabout.
Acknowledged.
DS9 to Ganges.
Go ahead.
They're in the Yangtzee Kiang.
They're initializing
prelaunch systems now.
Understood, Lieutenant.
Shut down
all main power systems.
Dead quiet.
Bajor Vlll
in 120,000 kilometers.
Dropping to impulse.
What is that?
An antimatter converter.
l'm transferring power
from the ship's warp drive
into the storage cells.
We've got a Klingon bird-of-prey
de-cloaking dead ahead.
lt's all right.
We're here to meet them.
Klingons? Why?
You'll know soon enough.
The Klingons have powered up
their transporters.
Prepare to go to full impulse.
13 kilograms
of gold-pressed latinum,
as promised.
This is yours.
'eH. HlmaH!
What is it?
Bajoran independence.
Bird-of-prey is moving off
and cloaking.
Set up an intercept course
for the runabout.
lntercept in one minute,
12 seconds.
DS9 to Ganges.
Ganges.
The Cardassian Warship Aldara
is crossing the border,
Benjamin
on an intercept course
with the Yangtzee Kiang.
They'll enter Bajoran space
in 29 seconds.
Acknowledged.
The Yangtzee's sensors should
be picking us up now, sir.
What is that?
lt's another runabout.
They must have been
waiting for us here.
How did they know?
We also have a Cardassian
warship three minutes away.
The Klingons must have
sold us out.
Prepare to engage warp engines.
There's nowhere to run, Tahna.
We don't have to go far.
l should have known.
Now set the course for DS9.
No.
lf you don't, l'll explode
the bomb right here and destroy
all six colonies on Bajor Vlll.
You would kill thousands
of your own people for this?
The question is
whether you would kill them
by refusing to set the course.
They've gone to warp.
Follow them.
Ganges to Yangtzee Kiang.
Drop out of warp,
or we'll open fire.
Repeat:
Reduce your power immediately
or we will open fire.
l doubt he'll shoot
while his Major is on board
but just in case...
This is the voice
of the Kohn-Ma.
There is an armed
bilitrium explosive device
on board this ship.
Fire on us,
and you will detonate it.
lf that device goes off
while they're at warp
they'll spread radiation
across half the system.
He's headed straight back
to the station.
This is the Federation
Vessel Ganges
to the Cardassian
Warship Aldara.
So... we're finally allies,
Commander.
Gul Danar
the Federation Runabout
Yangtzee Kiang
is carrying an explosive
bilitrium device.
Can you intercept
before it reaches
the space station?
Our time to intercept
is two minutes, 14 seconds.
That's about a minute
too late, Commander.
lf l may take
this opportunity to say
that l warned you...
Can we get them
in a tractor beam?
Not at these speeds.
They have 27 seconds on us.
We may have to shoot
them down, Commander.
Ready photons, Chief.
We'll fire as soon
as they slow to impulse.
Aye, sir.
100,000 kilometers to DS9.
This is your idea
of a nonviolent solution?
You realize there are hundreds
of Bajoran civilians
aboard the station?
No one's going to be hurt, Kira.
Adjust your course
to take a vectored approach
past the mouth of the wormhole.
The wormhole...
lt's not the space station
you're after.
You can't possibly believe
you can destroy
the wormhole with that device?
l don't have to destroy it--
just collapse the entrance.
You're only hurting Bajor
by doing this, Tahna.
No more wormhole
no more Federation
or Cardassians...
or anyone.
Drop out of warp.
Now!
My God, they're going
into the wormhole
at full impulse.
Damn you.
Sisko to Kira.
Are you all right, Major?
No, she's not all right,
Commander!
And if you want her alive,
you'll do exactly as l say!
Listen to me carefully, Tahna.
You can either surrender now,
to me
or you can wait
for the Cardassian warship
and l can let them
deal with you this time.
Your choice.
There'll be no further
resistance, Commander.
Tahna...
the old ways don't work anymore.
Everything is different now.
l had to do this.
One day, you'll understand.
Traitor.