Chief Medical Officer's Log,
supplemental.
Chief O'Brien and l are
on board a T'Lani cruiser
helping the T'Lani
and the Kelleruns
eliminate their stockpiles
of harvesters--
deadly biomechanical
gene disrupters
used by both sides
in their centuries-long war.
Dr. Nydom,
how's our muon charge?
Coming up to full power.
Go ahead.
Computer...
this is harvester test sequence
number 37 5.
Muon generator
now at full power.
Once more unto the breach.
l hope this works
because, quite frankly,
l'm running out of ideas.
lt took ten years
to perfect the harvesters.
We've only been trying
to eliminate them for a week.
ls that all it's been?
lt feels like we've been
working for more than a month.
l've never seen
a nano-biogenic weapon
so resistant
to broad-spectrum radiation.
lt's just a matter
of finding the right combination
of muon frequencies.
lt should be simple,
but it's not.
Doctor?
Start the sequence,
or we will be here for a month.
Right, Chief.
l'm introducing the harvester
into the genetic bath.
Beginning muon influx now.
Doctor, please check
for any gene-disrupter phasing.
The genetic integrity
of the sample is holding steady.
l'm not reading
any genetic disruption at all.
Are you sure?
Check the sequence again.
The results are identical.
What?
lt worked, didn't it?
Would somebody say something?
lt worked, all right.
The harvesters
have been destroyed.
Good news, l take it.
Ambassador Sharat, l am pleased
to inform you
that we have found a way
to eliminate the harvesters.
Excellent.
Well done.
l knew if our people
stopped killing each other
and worked together
we could put an end
to these horrible weapons.
This is a symbol
of the new future
we have embarked upon.
Yes, and let's not forget,
we couldn't have done it
without the help of our friends
from the Federation.
At first, we questioned
Dr. Nydom's decision
to bring in outside help.
Obviously, it was
the right thing to do.
We're all very grateful
for your assistance.
lt was our pleasure,
we assure you.
But eliminating the harvesters
is only half the task.
We must make certain
all scientific data
concerned with them
is wiped out as well.
l've purged every file
in the T'Lani
and Kellerun data banks
pertaining to the harvesters.
lf anyone gets it in their head
to build these things again
they'll have to start
from scratch.
Then it's finished.
Not quite.
We shouldn't rest
until the entire Kellerun
and T'Lani supply of harvesters
has been destroyed.
We will begin immediately.
Commander, l have Dr. Bashir
for you on subspace.
ln here.
Commander, we have
some good news to report.
l've already heard.
You have?
Yes, l received a message
from both
the T'Lani and Kellerun
Ambassadors, informing me
of your success
in neutralizing the harvesters.
Congratulations, gentlemen.
Thank you, sir
but the Doctor here deserves
the bulk of the credit.
Actually, it was a team effort.
The Doctor's just
being modest, sir.
He was the one
who came up with muon rays
as a possible solution.
Luckily, it worked.
When can we expect you back?
Soon, l hope.
The Ambassador said something
about a celebration
on T'Lani Prime.
Yes, it's set for tonight
but the Chief is quite anxious
to return back to the station.
lt's been a long week.
Still...
l think we can spare you
for another day.
l agree... if that's okay
with you, Chief.
l suppose another day
won't kill me.
That's the spirit.
Then we'll expect you back
day after tomorrow.
Yes, sir.
Enjoy yourselves, gentlemen.
You've earned it.
The last cylinder.
l believe that you should have
the honor, Doctor.
My pleasure.
lt's ironic, isn't it
that the war should finally
come to an end up here
above T'Lani lll?
A planet whose entire population
was decimated by harvesters.
l hope this will be
a lasting peace.
What is this?
Weapons aren't allowed up here.
They're all dead.
We will be, too,
if we don't get out of here.
O'Brien to Ganges.
Computer, activate remote
transporter sequence.
O'Brien to Ganges!
They must be jamming
communications
with the runabout.
We sure as hell can't stay here.
We'll have to beam down
to the surface.
But they'll be able
to follow us.
l'm programming the system
to overload
30 seconds after we transport.
Let's go.
l'll have a cup
of Alterian chowder
uttaberry crepes...
Ah, and a slice of...
Kira to Sisko.
Go ahead, Major.
The T'Lani
and Kellerun Ambassadors
have just arrived
on the station.
They're asking to see you.
Are O'Brien
and Dr. Bashir with them?
No, Commander,
and the Ambassadors refuse
to speak to anyone but you.
Show them to my office.
l'll be right there.
Yes, sir.
l'll have to cancel that order.
Are you saying both
of my officers are dead?
Along with some
of our greatest scientists.
We're sorry you had
to share in our misfortune.
What happened?
lt was...
lt was a terrible accident.
lt appears one
of your officers--
a Chief O'Brien, l believe--
inadvertently tripped
a security device.
A lethal pulse of radiation
flooded the room
killing everyone.
Ambassador Sharat
transported off the ship
just minutes before
the accident occurred.
This security device?
lt was built
into the lab's computers
decades ago.
We didn't even know it existed.
lf there were no survivors
how do you know that Chief
O'Brien caused the accident?
l was able to return
to the ship
almost immediately
after the accident.
The first thing l did
was to check
the internal security sensors.
They recorded
the entire incident.
We assumed...
you'd want to see for yourself.
Thank you.
Commander, l...
l just want you to know
we don't blame Chief O'Brien
for what happened.
On the contrary.
Both he and Dr. Bashir
will always be considered heroes
to both the Kellerun
and the T'Lani.
Without their help
we never could have
destroyed the harvesters.
Please extend our sympathies
to their families.
l'll do that.
Chief. Chief.
ln here.
Wait!
Don't touch anything.
But why not?
There's food
and medical supplies.
Yeah, they could
be booby-trapped.
The Cardassians used
to rig the supplies
they left behind
with pressure grenades.
l've seen more than one soldier
permanently lose
his appetite that way.
Well, did you find anything?
Looks all right.
Good.
At least we won't starve.
Here.
No.
Why not, Chief?
l thought you loved
military rations.
Yeah, Federation rations.
l've had enough T'Lani food
this past week
to last me a lifetime.
Well, we've got
to keep our strength up.
We're going to have to find
some way
of warning the T'Lani
that the Kelleruns
have broken the treaty.
l still can't figure it.
Why would the Kelleruns wait
till the harvesters
were destroyed
before they made their move?
Maybe they didn't hand over
all the harvesters
for destruction.
Maybe they're convinced
they can defeat the T'Lani
with conventional weapons.
l suppose, but that might mean
continuing the war
for another hundred years.
Well, whatever the reason,
we'd better keep moving.
Wait! Listen to me, Julian.
The Kelleruns are going to
expect us to be on the move.
We start running,
their sensors will pick us up
before we've gone a kilometer.
lf we stay still,
maybe, just maybe
it'll take them longer
to find us.
The way l see it,
we have only one chance
to survive this thing
and that's to stay alive
long enough
for Commander Sisko to find us.
But that won't be
for at least another day.
He still thinks we're
celebrating on T'Lani Prime.
l said it was our only chance.
l didn't say it was a good one.
What have we here?
Looks like some
kind of com system.
Maybe we can contact
the T'Lani from here.
Do you think
you can get it working?
Well, l'll have to open it up--
see if there's
a backup power supply.
Why don't you take
a seat, Doctor?
Well, l thought
maybe l could help.
l took the engineering
extension courses
at Starfleet Medical.
Extension courses?
They were actually
quite informative.
Julian?
Hmm?
Do you really want to help me?
Yes.
Then let me do my job.
Of course.
l'll, uh, l'll inventory
the supplies, then.
Fine. Why don't you do that?
The last cylinder.
l believe that you should have
the honor, Doctor.
My pleasure.
The harvesters
have been destroyed.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
We must make certain
that all records
of their existence
are wiped out.
l've purged every file in the
T'Lani and Kellerun data banks
pertaining to the harvesters.
lf anyone gets it in their head
to build these things again
they'll have to start
from scratch.
Then it's finished.
Hold on.
What's this?
Chief?
l don't know.
Closing the last file
seems to have activated
some kind of security program.
lt looks like it was part
of the original
operating system.
l can't shut it down.
Do you know
anything about this?
No.
Maybe you should try
cutting the power.
lt's not responding.
l've heard of security
weapons like this--
a radiation pulse that
vaporizes any intruder
who doesn't enter
the proper code.
l'm surprised the Chief
didn't detect it.
lt must have been buried
very deep in the system.
l'd like to talk
to the Chief of Security
for that ship.
So would l.
Remember, they lost people, too.
But the T'Lani were responsible
for O'Brien and Bashir's safety.
They should have known
about that device
and deactivated it.
That will do, Major.
l'd like for you to contact
Bajoran medical officials.
We'll need a doctor
to be temporarily assigned
to the station
until Starfleet can send us
a replacement for Dr. Bashir.
Dax, inform Starfleet
of the accident.
Tell them we'll need
a new Medical Officer
and a new Chief of Operations.
Would you like me to go
with you to see Mrs. O'Brien?
No, l'll take care of it.
Find out how l can contact
Julian's family.
Major, inform the crew we'll
be holding a memorial service
tomorrow evening at 1800 hours.
Yes, sir.
All right, people
l know the next few days
are going to be hard
but we all have jobs to do.
Dismissed.
So, having any luck?
l wish you'd stop
asking me that.
l'm sorry.
lt's just all this
standing around.
At least you're doing
something constructive.
You just keep your eyes open
for any Kellerun soldiers.
Don't worry, l will.
lt's such a mess in here.
You'll make it work, Chief.
This is the kind
of challenge you live for.
You know, l was looking forward
to the celebrations
on T'Lani Prime.
l don't know if you've noticed
but T'Lani women
are quite attractive.
l'm not blind, you know.
Of course not.
But you are married.
Just 'cause you're married
doesn't mean you stop
looking at women.
Just as long as you don't
let your wife see you look.
For me, tonight's celebrations
would have been an adventure.
The most you could have hoped
for was a good meal.
Women--
that's all you think about.
No, it isn't.
Although l do think
about them a lot.
Yeah, well, one of these days
you'll fall in love with one.
l did once.
Not work out?
Not quite.
Close.
Oh, l don't know.
Somehow, marriage
just doesn't seem fair.
Fair?
Fair... to them.
l mean, look at us.
Our lives are constantly
in danger.
There's enough to worry about
without worrying about
the wife and kids at home
worrying about us.
l'm sorry, Chief.
l just feel that way.
A lot of career officers
feel that way.
Well, you career officers
don't know what you're missing.
Really?
That may be so.
l just look at you
and Mrs. O'Brien, and l...
What about me and Mrs. O'Brien?
Nothing.
What?
Nothing, absolutely nothing.
lt's no secret that your
assignment to this station
hasn't been conducive
to your marriage.
Say that again?
Why don't we just forget it?
That's the first
intelligent thing you've said
since we got here.
Are you cold?
Yes, aren't you?
No. Actually,
it's quite warm in here.
You're looking a little pale.
l'm fine.
Your blood pressure's low
and you're running a fever.
You better sit down.
l don't want to sit down.
l've got work to do.
Roll up your sleeve.
Why?
Do it.
Please.
You were behind the genetic bath
when it shattered, weren't you?
You have something
to tell me, Doctor?
You've been infected
by the harvesters.
Come in.
Commander Sisko.
Keiko.
Something's happened to Miles.
There was an accident.
Both your husband and Dr. Bashir
were involved.
They're dead.
l'm sorry.
Tell me what happened.
The T'Lani security sensors
recorded the entire incident.
l want to see it.
l'll have it sent to you.
Miles was a fine officer
and a fine man.
l'll miss him.
Thank you, Commander.
l would like to be alone now.
lf there's anything you need,
just let me know.
Chief?
lt's my eyes.
They're... getting fuzzy.
You better sit down.
l'll take over from here.
What makes you think
you can fix this?
Because you're going
to talk me through it.
Now take a seat.
Maybe...
just for a minute...
or two.
Now, tell me where you left off.
You see the dark blue coil
in the upper right-hand corner?
No.
lt's there...
beside the...
the green cylinder.
Just... just below it.
Yeah, l see it.
You have to...
you have to lock
the base of the coil
into the tiny receptor...
just below it.
You know, l just remembered
l still have Julian's
medical school diaries.
He let you read them?
He felt they would help me
understand him better.
How? By reading about
all the women he went out with?
That's not what they were about.
When he gave them to me
he told me that they were about
his innermost thoughts...
his struggle to graduate
top of his class
his dream of having a career
in Starfleet
his constant fear of failure.
Really.
And did you?
Understand him better?
l never got around
to reading them.
l suppose l should send them
to his parents.
You could keep them.
Really?
l think he'd like that.
He cared a great deal about you.
l know.
l cared about him, too.
These, um... are on the house.
How come?
l thought we'd have a toast
to the memory of Chief
O'Brien and Dr. Bashir.
That's very thoughtful, Quark.
l can be thoughtful.
To our dear, departed comrades.
We may have had our differences,
but l'll say this for them--
and it's the highest
tribute l can think of--
they were good customers.
They always paid
their bar bills on time.
That's it?
l'm not done yet.
At times like this,
l'm reminded of
the 57th Rule of Acquisition:
''Good customers are
as rare as latinum.''
''Treasure them.''
Mrs. O'Brien...
Major, l need to see
Commander Sisko.
lt's very important.
l'll tell him you're here.
l just wanted you to know
how sorry l am--
how sorry we all are.
Thank you.
lf anyone gets it in their head
to build these things again...
Watch. lt's coming up
in just a few seconds.
Then it's finished.
Computer, freeze image.
There.
Do you see it?
l see the Chief drinking coffee.
Exactly.
Now look at the time index.
1500 hours.
That's right.
Late afternoon.
Miles never drinks coffee
late in the afternoon.
lt keeps him up all night.
Maybe he made
an exception this time--
working long hours,
under a lot of stress...
l know my husband.
He never drinks coffee
late in the day.
Maybe he isn't drinking coffee.
Maybe it's tea.
l checked the data clip.
lt contained
a spectroscopic analysis.
The liquid in Miles's
cup consists
of vegetable-based
oils and caffeine.
lt's coffee, all right.
You're suggesting
someone tampered
with this recording?
Yes, l am, and l want
to know the reason why.
Lieutenant, when
were you planning
on bringing the Ganges
back from T'Lani lll?
Tomorrow.
l don't see any reason
to wait, do you?
l'll leave right away.
Good.
l'll come with you.
Mrs. O'Brien, if this recording
has been altered,
we'll find out why.
You were right, Chief.
The contacts on the
sub-processor are corroded.
Yeah.
They need to be cleaned.
Oh, um, l think
there are some sterile pads
in the med kit.
Here we go.
Don't leave me, Chief.
l still need you.
Don't worry.
l'm not going anywhere.
So, who was she?
Who?
''Not quite. Close.''
Palis. Palis Delon.
She was a dancer-- a ballerina.
She had the most exquisite feet.
l'm serious.
lt's very important for a dancer
to have good arches.
She was gorgeous
not to mention brilliant.
l used to watch her onstage.
l couldn't believe how anyone
could be so graceful.
And she was crazy
about you, huh?
We were crazy about each other.
l used to think,
''Julian, you lucky devil.
You found the perfect woman.''
We used to finish
each other's thoughts.
There.
What do you think?
Good... good.
Put it back in the com panel.
Looks like we have some power,
anyway.
Still no response
from the transmitter, though.
Try re-tuning
the R-F oscillators.
So what happened
with you and Palis?
What happened is l graduated.
Her father was
the top administrator
at a medical complex in Paris.
He offered me a job.
Promised l'd be Chief of Surgery
within five years.
But you would have to give up
your Starfleet career.
l can't tell you
how close l came.
But... here l am.
You made your choice.
Yeah.
Sometimes, l wake up
in the middle of the night
and l think to myself...
will l ever find anyone
that wonderful again?
The oscillator's working
but the frequency's
still fluctuating.
Let me take a look.
Oh!
What is it?
lt's... my legs.
l can't feel them.
We're approaching T'Lani lll.
Establishing a synchronous orbit
alongside the Ganges.
Open a channel
to the T'Lani cruiser.
Commander Sisko,
what a pleasant surprise.
l take it you're here
for your runabout?
That's correct.
We were about to leave
for the memorial service
on T'Lani Prime.
You're welcome to accompany us.
Perhaps we will, but first
l'd like to see for myself
where the accident took place.
Of course.
While you're on the cruiser
l think l'll beam
over to the Ganges
and take a look around.
Good idea.
Chief.
Chief, it's working.
Signal's very faint.
You'll have to switch to
a higher-carrier frequency.
Reset the actuators
on the chambers coil.
That's better.
lt's still pretty weak, though.
l'm sending a distress signal.
lt's set to repeat
every two minutes.
Let's hope the T'Lani find us
before the Kelleruns do.
They better get here soon.
Don't worry, Chief.
l'm going to get you home.
ln a box, maybe.
Nonsense.
Don't go giving up on me now.
l'm not giving up.
l'm dying.
Listen to me...
listen to me, Julian.
You must tell Keiko and Molly...
You tell them yourself.
You were wrong, you know...
about marriage.
Whatever you say, Chief.
Listen to me, Julian!
You're the one
who's always talking
about adventure.
Ha... adventure.
Marriage is the greatest
adventure of them all.
lt's filled with
pitfalls and setbacks
and mistakes and...
but it's a journey
worth taking...
because you take it together.
l know Keiko's been unhappy
about us coming to the station.
We still argue about it.
But that's all right
because at the end of the day
we both know
we love each other.
Chief...
And that's all that matters.
Huh?
You better get some rest.
The T'Lani will be here soon.
l see there's still
some residual traces
of the radiation pulse.
Well, that's to be expected
given the pulse's intensity
but it poses no danger.
Tell me, Ambassador
have you been able
to learn anything else
about the fail-safe device
that caused the accident?
Not yet, Commander,
but we're working on it.
lt was Ambassador Sharat that
brought you the data clip?
That's right.
And l suppose
he showed it to you
as soon as you arrived?
Of course.
Could the clip have been
altered before you saw it?
Why would Ambassador Sharat
alter the data clip?
l have no idea.
Dax to Sisko.
Sisko.
Commander,
when you're through there
could you join me on the Ganges?
Yes, l'll be here
a few more minutes.
Commander, the T'Lani
and the Kellerun
have finally made peace.
That peace cannot survive
unless both sides
trust each other.
What have you got, Dax?
lt looks like someone
erased five seconds
from the Ganges' computer log.
Show me.
At first, l thought it was just
some kind of power fluctuation.
but when l checked
the log's memory core
it showed traces
of a remote transport command.
Did you find any indication
of transport activity
at that time?
No.
And you're saying
somebody erased it later on?
Look at the time index when
the call for transport came in.
1534-- that's
a full three minutes
after the accident
on the T'Lani cruiser.
Which means if either
Chief O'Brien or Julian
made that request...
They would have been alive
after the fail-safe device
went off.
Good work, Lieutenant.
Chief...
Chief!
Don't leave me now.
Breathe.
That's better.
Now you're doing it.
Tell me, Julian...
ever talk to that
ballerina of yours?
Not since l left Earth.
Well, maybe...
maybe you should.
Well, maybe one day l will.
Ambassador E'Tyshra.
Am l glad to see you.
Chief O'Brien was infected
by the harvesters
when the Kelleruns
attacked your ship.
They killed
all of the scientists.
Not all of them.
You're too late, Sharat.
No, Doctor, he's right on time.
But why kill
Nydom and the others?
To ensure
that the peace agreement
between our two races will last.
But we'd already destroyed
the harvesters.
There was no reason
for more killings, unless...
lt's not enough to simply
destroy the harvesters.
We have to be sure
no one can ever recreate them.
The only way to do that
was to eliminate everyone
who possessed such knowledge,
including the two of you.
But we have no use
for such horrible weapons.
As long as the knowledge exists,
there's a danger it may be used.
That's a risk
we refuse to live with.
l truly am sorry, Doctor
but at least you
have the consolation
of knowing that your deaths
will be for a noble cause.
Wait.
Let him speak.
Help me...
help me up.
l want to die on my feet.
l'm sorry l didn't
get us home, Chief.
You did your best.
lt's been an honor...
serving with you.
Thank you, Chief.
That means a lot.
Commander, am l glad to see you!
Chief O'Brien is going
to be dead within the hour
if we don't get him back
to the station.
What happened?
He was exposed
to the harvesters.
That should stabilize him
for now.
They told us
you were both dead, Julian.
We would have been
if the T'Lani and Kelleruns
had had their way.
They're killing
everyone involved
with the harvesters project.
The T'Lani cruiser's
coming this way.
They're hailing us.
lgnore them.
Send a general distress signal
on all Federation
subspace frequencies.
They're blocking
all subspace communication
with a broadband inversion.
They're hailing us again.
ls the inversion field
affecting sensors, as well?
All short-range
sensors are useless.
Which means...
theirs are useless, too.
Ambassador, Commander Sisko
is attempting to escape.
We are in pursuit.
Can we overtake them?
Their runabout
is no match for this ship.
Fire a warning shot.
Confirmed.
Commander Sisko is hailing us.
l thought he would.
By firing on this vessel
you've committed an act of war
against the Federation.
Commander, we have no quarrel
with the Federation or with you.
But we must insist you turn over
Dr. Bashir and Chief O'Brien.
Why?
So you can murder them?
Unfortunately, Commander,
your officers
are the only two people left
who have seen the data
concerning the development
of the harvesters.
They have no intention
of using that information.
You have my word.
Their intentions are irrelevant.
The fact is, the threat remains
as long as the knowledge exists.
Commander, l know this
is painful for you.
lt wasn't easy for us
to order the deaths
of our own people
but it is necessary.
And if l refuse
to turn them over?
You can't outrun us,
and you can't fight us.
We can destroy your runabout
at any time.
Lieutenant Dax and l have
no knowledge of the harvesters.
Are you willing to kill us, too?
We'll do whatever we have to do
to ensure our safety.
Commander,
you are running out of options.
You have one minute
to turn over Dr. Bashir
and Chief O'Brien.
You want them?
You're going to have
to take us all.
He leaves us no choice.
The runabout is turning.
lt's heading back
in our direction.
Full stop.
He's preparing to fire.
Employ shields.
Shields employed.
Put the runabout on screen.
He must know his phasers
can't hurt us.
He's aiming his vessel
straight for us.
The man must be crazy.
Fire phasers.
lt's over.
Head back to T'Lani lll.
Prepare to take
the other runabout in tow.
Ambassador...
sensors indicate
the other runabout
is no longer in orbit.
Well, then, where is it?
l don't know.
lt's gone.
lt can't just have disappeared.
l'm picking up a warp signature.
Sisko.
Maybe he and the others weren't
on that runabout we destroyed.
They could have transported
to the other runabout
while our sensors were down.
And then piloted the first ship
by remote navigation.
But we saw them die.
Did we?
What's this?
Something Molly made for you.
She painted it herself.
Oh, it's lovely.
She has real talent.
How's my patient?
Better.
Can l go home now?
You should be out of here
by tomorrow.
l just wanted to let you know
how much l appreciated what
you said back on T'Lani lll.
What did l say?
That it was an honor
serving with me.
Oh... right.
And l'd like to return
the compliment, if l may.
lt's been an honor
serving with you, too, Chief.
You know, Mrs. O'Brien, they say
that when two people face death
together, it creates a bond
that cannot be broken.
l never believed that
until l went...
Julian...
Hmm?
Oh.
Um, of course
you'd like to be alone.
l understand.
Miles, he saved
your life, you know.
Mmm. He's never going
to let me forget it.
So, what was it like
spending all that time
alone with him?
lt was hell.
You can see for yourself.
The man never stops talking.
You know, l wouldn't mind
a cup of coffee right now.
Miles, you never drink coffee
in the afternoon.
Well, sure l do.
You do?