Dabo!
Quark!
Oh... not now, Odo.
We have to talk.
lt'll have to wait.
lt can't wait.
Of course not.
Make it fast.
l have business to attend to.
You remember
that Subytt freighter
we were discussing
the other day--
the one you claimed
was smuggling
defective isolinear rods
to Bajor?
Yes, yes.
What about it?
Well, l conducted
a little investigation
of that freighter
and do you know
what l discovered?
That l was telling the truth.
That's right.
l arrested the First Officer
and two of the crew.
Congratulations, Constable.
l knew you could do it.
Now, if you don't mind,
l am needed upstairs.
Hold on.
l'm not finished with you.
Oh, really, Odo?
Sometimes l think
there's no pleasing you.
l help you crack
a notorious smuggling ring
and yet you still insist on
treating me like the enemy?
You are the enemy.
Then how do you explain
my helping you?
That's just it.
l can't explain it.
lt's simple, really.
l figured we've been at each
others' throats long enough.
lt's time we called a truce.
Truce?
You must be joking.
Ask the Subytt First Officer
if l'm joking.
From now on, you and l
are going to be friends.
You're up to something.
Why would you say that?
Because you're always
up to something.
l can see this is
going to take time
but eventually you'll
learn to trust me.
Hmm, hmm.
That'll be the day.
l don't think l can remember
Odo ever looking so...
perplexed.
He's not alone.
Those Subytt smugglers
were a potential source
of great profit.
Must l quote you
the 7 6th Rule of Acquisition?
The 7 6th...
''Every once in a while,
declare peace.
lt confuses the hell
out of your enemies.''
Hi, Quark.
How are your lobes?
Tingling at the sight of you.
What'll it be, hmm?
Another black hole?
No, l don't have time.
My ship's about to pull out.
Do you know of anyone
going to Bajor?
Ships go back and forth
from there all the time.
Why?
l promised someone
l'd deliver this for them.
Doesn't look like l'm going
to get there this trip.
lt's an earring.
l know it's an earring.
lt was given to me
by a maintenance worker
on Cardassia lV.
Are you saying a Cardassian
gave you a Bajoran earring?
He asked me to take it to Bajor.
Said whoever l showed
it to would understand.
He said that?
Well, this is a Bajoran
station, isn't it?
Mm-hmm.
Well, there must be someone here
who would know
what to do with it.
Oh, there is.
Who?
Me.
Come in.
Surprise.
What do you want?
l always wondered what
your quarters looked like.
That better not be
your only reason for being here.
You don't entertain much,
do you?
Oh, l entertain a lot--
l just don't entertain you.
Let me guess.
The bedroom.
You take one step in here
and l promise you,
it'll be your last.
lt could be worth it.
You've got five seconds
to tell me what you want.
Aren't you going
to offer me a beverage?
Five... four...
Can we at least sit down?
Three, two, one.
Wait!
l brought you something.
Where did you get that?
ls it valuable?
l said where did you get it?
From a Boslic Freighter Captain.
She got it from a Cardassian.
Where?
On Cardassia lV.
That's what she told me, anyway.
Consider it a gift!
Hey, Dad, wait up.
You got a minute?
For you, absolutely.
l've got some great news.
You passed your algebra test.
Better than that.
You learned how to hit
Bob Gibson's fastball.
No, even better.
Better than hitting
Gibson's fastball?
This l want to hear.
You remember that Bajoran
girl l told you about?
The one
with the beautiful smile?
That's right-- Laira.
l decided to ask her out.
Well, good for you.
And now you've come
to the old man
for advice
on what to say to her.
Dad, l al...
The main thing is you can't
be afraid of rejection.
Dad, l already asked her
out, and she said yes.
She did?
That's wonderful.
l was just wondering
if you had any ideas
on what we could do.
l was thinking of taking her
to the holosuites.
The holosuites?
l don't think so.
Why not?
Because you're too young
to take a girl
to the holosuites.
Okay, then how about if l
take her to our quarters?
Oh, no, no.
No quarters.
We're just going to talk.
Talk in public.
lt's not the same.
You want to talk?
Take her upstairs.
And that way you can talk
and watch the ships
go through the wormhole.
That's boring.
Since when?
Since l started
going out with girls.
This is your first date.
And l don't want it
to be my last.
Commander,
l need to speak with you.
One moment, Major.
l can see you're not ready
to have this conversation yet.
l'm not ready?
l'll just have to come up
with a few ideas on my own.
Really, don't worry about it.
Who's worried?
Commander?
Join me, Major.
One raktajino
with a jacarine peel.
Nothing for me.
One icoberry torte.
So... Major
what can l do for you?
l need to borrow a runabout.
For what?
You really don't want
to ask me that.
lt's too late.
l already asked.
You don't want
to know the answer.
Major, l can't loan you
a Starfleet runabout
without knowing
where you plan on taking it.
To Cardassia lV to rescue
a Bajoran prisoner of war.
You're right.
l wish you hadn't told me.
This earring was recently
smuggled off the planet.
Do you see this?
That is the insignia
of Li Nalas.
The resistance leader?
The greatest we ever had.
His victory over Gul Zarale
in hand-to-hand combat...
Major, l have already
heard the story.
Wasn't he reported
killed in action?
His body was never found.
Look, Commander,
l wouldn't be asking you this
if l thought there was
any other way to rescue Li.
But Bajoran ships just don't
have the maneuverability
or the defensive capabilities
to get me safely in and out
of Cardassian territory.
You're sure this is genuine?
Dax found dermal residue
on the backing.
A genetic analysis matched
it to Li's DNA records.
lt's genuine all right.
Have you told
the provisional government?
l contacted three ministers.
Their response was
exactly what l expected.
ln other words,
they're unwilling
to risk going to war
with Cardassia over an earring.
l can't say l blame them.
Commander, you and l both know
the provisional government
is made up
of political opportunists
too busy
fighting amongst themselves
to care what happens to Bajor.
Since the loss of the Kai
the situation has only
gone from bad to worse.
There are reports
of factional fighting
in half a dozen districts.
Religious riots have spread
throughout the southern islands.
Bajor needs a leader--
someone the people
will listen to
someone they can trust.
And you think that Li Nalas
is that leader?
l know he is.
O'Brien to Sisko.
Go ahead, Chief.
l think you and Odo had better
join me in the Habitat Ring
level 13, section 4.
There's something
you should see.
We'll be right there.
Do l get the runabout?
l'll have to think it over.
l was on my way
to Crossover Bridge 3
to do some repair work
on the field modulators
when l noticed this.
This is the emblem of the
Alliance for Global Unity.
They call themselves the Circle.
The Circle, huh?
What gives them the right
to mess up our station?
They're an extremist faction
who believe in Bajor
for the Bajorans.
All other species are inferior
and should be expelled
from the planet.
l understand this emblem
has appeared all over Bajor.
That's correct
but this is the first
time l've seen it here.
l want to be informed
immediately
if this emblem appears
anyplace else on the station.
Understood.
lf they think scrawling
a few signs
is going to get rid of us
they've got
another thing coming.
Right now, they're just
trying to show us
that we're vulnerable.
l wouldn't be overly
concerned, Commander.
This section is
a low-security area.
As of now, Constable
there are no low-security areas
on this station.
You wanted to see me, Benjamin?
Ah, yes.
Have a seat.
Am l to assume this is
going to be about baseball?
Not this time.
Good.
l thought you enjoyed
talking about baseball.
Curzon enjoyed it
but not half as much
as he led you to believe.
So what's on your mind,
Benjamin?
l've been thinking
about our mission here.
l look at the turmoil on Bajor
and l see everything
we fought for this past year
starting to unravel.
l told you this was going
to be a tough assignment
when we came here.
Of course, l didn't realize
it was going to be this tough.
What if l told you
that l knew someone
who could bring stability
to Bajor?
Someone who could
unite the factions
and give us a chance
to do our job?
l'd say give Kira the runabout.
How do you know
about Kira wanting a runabout?
l promise not to tell.
All right.
Supposing l do help
and she does rescue Li Nalas.
What do we say
to the Cardassians?
The question is
what do they say to us?
They swore they released
all their Bajoran prisoners.
Chief...
Major Kira needs a runabout.
Oh, so she's going
to Cardassia lV after all.
ls there anyone on this station
she didn't tell?
l doubt
she mentioned it to Quark.
Well, then,
as far as Quark's concerned
she's going to Lamenda Prime
to bring back mineral samples.
l see.
Now, is there any way
we can prevent
the Cardassian sensors
from picking up
the runabout's signature?
l could modulate
the engine's power emissions
reconfigure
the deflector shield grid
and install field buffers
around the subspace
emitter coil.
By the time l'm done,
the Cardassians will think
they're picking up
a Lissepian transport.
Yeah?
l see you've already given this
a bit of thought.
l suppose l have.
Come in.
Commander... Chief.
l was just getting ready
to leave.
l just stopped by
to wish you luck.
And...
to tell you that Chief O'Brien
will be accompanying you
on your mission.
l don't think
that's a good idea.
Having a Federation officer
along
could cause complications
for you later.
l'm willing to risk that.
You're an excellent
pilot, Major
but Mr. O'Brien here
is better.
And l want to make sure
that l get my runabout
back in one piece.
l appreciate the offer,
but this is a Bajoran problem.
l don't agree.
The truth is, l need
Li Nalas back on Bajor
as much as you do.
Besides
l've seen how the Cardassians
treat their prisoners.
No one should have
to suffer like that.
lf the Cardassians
get their hands on us
we'll be the ones suffering.
They'll have to catch us first.
l suppose l could
use the company.
You've got the controls, Chief.
Right.
Before we go
there's, uh, one thing we need
to clear up between us.
What's that?
This mission can end
only one of two ways--
either we bring back Li Nalas,
or we don't come back at all.
Understood.
Then take us out of here,
Mr. O'Brien.
lnitializing launch sequence.
How much longer
till we reach Cardassia lV?
l estimate another 30 minutes.
Hold on.
We're being scanned.
Can you get a fix on the source?
lts position is holding steady
at bearing 219 mark 23.
lt must be
a navigational control post.
lt's probably
just a routine scan.
We're being hailed.
Then again,
we could be in serious trouble.
They're repeating the hail.
We're on the edge
of their scanner range.
That puts us out
of visual contact.
l say we try and bluff them.
Opening a channel.
This is Cardassian Navigational
Control Post 24.
ldentify yourself.
This is the Lissepian
Transport Martuk.
According to our scan
your subspace field emitters
appear to be malfunctioning.
The field buffers must be
distorting our power signature.
Uh, we're... having problems
with our phase modulators.
We're attempting
to correct the problem.
Do you require assistance?
We can dispatch a repair ship.
They want to help us?
Your offer is most appreciated,
Post 24, but unnecessary.
Are you certain?
Your power signature
is still fluctuating.
He's getting suspicious.
l believe we can correct
the problem on our own.
Besides, Gul Marayn is waiting
on Cardassia lV to receive
my shipment of rulot seeds.
Any delay could ruin
the entire crop
not to mention the Gul's mood.
Understood.
You can put in for repairs
after you deliver your cargo.
My plan, exactly.
He's cut off their transmission.
Tell me, Major...
who is this Gul Marayn?
Don't ask me.
l just made him up.
We're in synchronous orbit
above the Hutet labor camp.
l've limited the bio-scans
to detect
only Bajoran life-forms.
Hold on.
We're getting multiple readings.
There must be about a dozen
Bajoran prisoners down there.
What?!
ls there any way of beaming up
more than two at a time?
l'm afraid not.
As soon as we beam
the first two up
all hell is going
to break loose in that camp.
There's no way of guaranteeing
that Li will be
one of the first two.
What's security like down there?
The compound is surrounded
by a standard
Cardassian force field.
We're going to have to land.
lt's our only chance of getting
them all out of there.
l'll find us a secluded
place to put down.
Back to work!
Do as l say!
How do l look?
l doubt there's
a Cardassian alive
who could resist you.
l hope you're right.
So do l.
Stop talking!
Halt!
We want to see the Prefect.
What for?
She has an appointment with him.
l used to be stationed on Bajor.
Then you know why the Prefect
doesn't want
to be kept waiting, huh?
What's this all about?
l'm not quite sure.
What would it cost me
for an appointment?
More than you could afford.
Two strips
of gold-pressed latinum--
she's all yours.
He wouldn't know
what to do with me.
She needs disciplining.
From a boy like you? Ha!
l don't think
you're capable of it.
Step back.
l want to examine
what l'm paying for.
Sure, sure
but no sampling the merchandise
until the sale's complete, okay?
Come here.
Now...
show me why
you're worth two strips
of gold-pressed latinum.
All right.
Li Nalas!
Who are you?
Major Kira Nerys.
We've come to get you
out of here.
The earring-- you got it?
Yes.
l don't understand.
My earring was lost.
No, l had it smuggled
back to Bajor.
Gentlemen, l suggest you keep
this discussion for later, okay?
Come on.
Oh!
Come on, we have a ship waiting.
Let's get him
behind those rocks.
l see them!
Keep down.
We'll never make it
at this rate.
Get Li back to Bajor.
Four of us will stay behind
and hold them off
till you reach your ship.
No, l won't allow it.
Don't you see?
We did this for you!
Just get him back safely.
That's all that counts.
You have my word.
-All right, go.
-Come on.
-Go!
Come on!
Ready to launch, Major.
Not yet, some of the others
might still make it.
Standing by.
l'm picking up two Galor-class
warships entering orbit.
They should be overhead
in one minute, 45 seconds.
Major, you can't leave
those men behind.
One minute, 30 seconds.
lf we don't leave now, Major,
we never will.
Take us home, Chief.
Yes, sir.
Careful, he took a phaser hit.
Easy now, l have you.
Doctor, these people have been
prisoners for ten years.
They need medical attention.
They'll get it
but first, l better take
a look at this wound.
Bashir to Dax.
Go ahead, Doctor.
We've got a patient
who needs emergency treatment.
Beam us to the lnfirmary.
Stand by.
Commander, l need to talk...
Ah, Major, l'm glad
you could join us.
l'm sorry.
l didn't know you were busy.
Apparently not.
l'll just wait outside.
Hold on, Major.
There's something
l want you to hear.
Go ahead, Dukat.
Major, l have just informed
Commander Sisko
that the Cardassian High Command
has issued a formal apology
to the people of Bajor.
An apology?
We had no idea
that Bajoran prisoners
were still being held
on Cardassia lV.
Such detentions
are a direct violation
of Supreme Directive 2645
and l assure you
the camp Prefect
will be chastised accordingly.
What about the prisoners
that were left behind?
They are already en route
to Bajor.
Well, l look forward
to their safe return.
l'm sure you do.
And l hope
that our quick response
to this unfortunate situation
will prove once and for all
that Cardassia
is no longer your enemy.
Commander?
l'm as surprised as you are.
There's got to be a reason
why they're being
so accommodating.
l'm sure there is
but until we can figure out
their motives
let us just be grateful
that all the prisoners
are being returned safely.
Congratulations on the success
of your mission, Major.
There, that should do it.
How do you feel?
Better.
Good.
Luckily, your wound
wasn't as serious
as it looked.
You've probably had a lot worse.
Well, actually,
this one was bad enough.
You know, l've read
all about your battle
with Gul Zarale.
That was a long time ago.
Well, l consider myself
a bit of a history buff
and l must say
some of the campaigns
you led against the Cardassians
were truly remarkable...
Doctor, l think that you'll find
that others enjoy talking
about those days
far more than l do.
Of course.
l understand completely.
Amazing.
What is?
Being here.
l used to work
in one of this station's
ore processing plants.
l think you will find
that things have changed
considerably.
Commander, a transport
carrying Minister Jaro
has just arrived from Bajor.
Major
l think you should
have the honor
of welcoming him aboard.
Thank you, Commander.
lf you're hungry
the Replimat has some
passable Bajoran food.
Actually, l'm a bit tired.
l think l'd like
to see my quarters.
Of course.
That's Li Nalas.
lt appears you've
been recognized.
Minister Jaro.
Major.
Where is he?
He's on the Promenade
with Commander Sisko.
And he's all right?
Considering
what he's been through
in the past ten years.
Li Nalas alive--
who would have ever imagined?
The Prophets were kind
to you today, Major.
l'd, uh, say they were
kind to all of us.
You know, your little adventure
made you some enemies
in the Chamber of Ministers.
l'm not surprised.
All l did was risk my life.
What you did today, Major
was declare war on Cardassia.
Thankfully, they declined
the invitation.
l'd do it again if it meant
bringing Li Nalas home.
Yes, l'm sure you would.
Although, officially,
l have to warn you
that the next time
you disobey orders
will mean the end
of your military career.
As a private citizen...
l want to thank you
for what you've done this day.
That's good to hear.
Now take me to see Li Nalas.
Move it back, please.
No pushing, no pushing.
l'm sorry about this, Commander.
l don't think they're
going to leave
until you say a few words.
l agree.
lf that's what it takes.
lt's good to be free.
lt's good to know that...
after all our years
of struggle...
...Bajor is finally free.
Yes, it is good to be free.
Well...
it really is you, isn't it?
Li Nalas.
l'm Minister Jaro Essa
and l can't tell you
how delighted l am
to welcome you home.
Believe me, it is
a pleasure to be here.
Would you mind if l
address the crowd?
You can't expect a politician
to give up an opportunity
like this.
You go right ahead.
Thank you.
Fellow Bajorans, l have
only one thing to say to you--
to ask you, really.
Never forget this moment
because l promise you
that one day, your children
and your grandchildren
will ask you what it was like
the day Li Nalas
returned to Bajor.
l hope you'll find
these quarters satisfactory.
Commander...
l just spent ten years
in a Cardassian labor camp.
l'm just grateful...
for a moment's privacy.
Enjoy it while you can.
Judging from the crowd
on the Promenade
a moment may be all you get.
l thought they would have
forgotten me by now.
lt appears you were wrong.
This morning, l was a slave.
Tonight, l am a hero.
lt must seem
a little overwhelming.
l tell you what is
overwhelming, Commander.
lt's knowing that something
l have waited for my whole life
has finally happened.
The Cardassians are gone.
We won.
You've been there recently.
What's it like, a free Bajor?
l think you'll be pleased,
for the most part.
For the most part?
Bajor lacks strong leadership.
So that's what Major Kira meant.
On the runabout,
she told me that my return
would bring stability to Bajor.
She's right.
Bajor could use your help,
and frankly, so could l.
But before you go off
saving Bajor
l suppose you could use
a good night's sleep.
lt sounds
like l'm going to need it.
One for you...
and six for me.
One for you and...
six for me.
One for you...
and six for me.
Would you stop
looking so glum?
Payday is supposed
to be a time of... joy.
l know, brother
but, every week,
it's the same thing.
Six for you
and only one for me.
lt's not fair!
You're right.
l am?
Yes. lt's not fair.
lt's not?
Absolutely not.
One for you...
and...
...seven
for me.
One for you, and...
seven for me.
ls that better?
And where are you going?
To bed, to dream
of an equal share of profits.
Dream on.
One for you...
and seven for me.
What is it now?
Quark... Quark!
Hold still.
Doctor...
will there be a scar?
l said, hold still.
Does that mean yes?
No, this dermal regenerator
should repair any damaged tissue
as well as prevent scarring.
Unless, of course,
you don't hold still.
Did you recognize
any of your assailants?
They were wearing masks.
Are you sure they didn't
say anything?
Not a word.
They came in,
branded me and left.
The Promenade is usually
deserted at this hour.
No one saw them
enter or leave.
Constable, l want
all security personnel
put on full alert.
l've already seen to it.
Who was responsible for this?
An extremist group from Bajor
who call themselves the Circle.
Bajorans did this?
l'm afraid so.
But why?
Their goal is to rid Bajor
of all non-Bajorans.
Hasn't the provisional
government
tried to stop them?
Oh, they've tried,
but the truth is
the Circle is more organized
than the government.
Well, the government
better get organized
because l intend to sue them
for financial compensation.
Not now, Quark!
People have grown impatient
with the government's inability
to get things done
so they turn to the Circle.
Constable.
We need someone to speak out
against these reactionaries--
someone the people
will listen to.
There.
That should do it.
How do l look?
As... handsome as ever.
Really?
Huh.
Jake, what are you doing up?
l couldn't sleep.
How was your date?
lt was tonight, wasn't it?
lt was supposed to be.
She couldn't make it.
lt happens.
She said her father
wouldn't let her go out with me.
Why not?
Because l'm not a Bajoran.
That's not much of a reason.
Oh, Jake.
There are some things
happening on Bajor.
Troubling things.
l'm sorry you've become
a victim of them.
You don't deserve it.
Nobody does.
Time for bed, okay?
Okay.
Night, Dad.
Commander,
there's a call for you
from the Tygarian freighter
docked on Upper Pylon 2.
Put it through.
Commander Sisko,
l am Romah Doek
Executive Officer of the Nanut.
We were preparing to depart
this station for Gamma Quadrant
when we discovered
a Bajoran citizen
trying to stow away on our ship.
l was hoping you would know
what to do with him.
The Nanut isn't scheduled
to return from the Gamma
Quadrant for two years.
Actually, l planned
on staying considerably longer.
l don't follow.
Commander, l'm going
to tell you a story...
and you may even believe it.
l'm listening.
During the occupation
l was a member
of a minor resistance cell.
Name's unimportant.
One day-- this was
in the mountains
surrounding
the Sahving Valley--
we were ambushed
by Cardassian troops.
Only three of us
managed to escape.
We hid in the hills
for two days.
Finally, the lack
of food and water
forced us down into the valley.
We made our way to a ridge
overlooking a small lake.
As l was the only one
still carrying a phaser
l went on ahead
to scout for the enemy.
Halfway down the embankment,
l slipped...
went sprawling on my back
down to the edge of the lake
just as a huge Cardassian
emerged from the water.
He must have
just finished bathing.
He stood there...
frozen in surprise
dressed only in his underwear
shivering in the cold.
l lay there, looking up at him,
too stunned to even move.
And it was only when he reached
for a phaser rifle
that was lying across
his clothes on a nearby rock
that l realized that l was
still holding my own phaser
and l shot him.
His body fell on top of me.
And that's how my companions
found us a moment later.
One of them recognized him
as, uh, Gul Zarale
responsible for the massacre
of half a dozen
Bajoran villages.
Now, l tried to tell
them what had happened
but they had already
convinced themselves
that l had killed Zarale in
some kind of a savage struggle
which is what they insisted
on telling every
Bajoran that we met.
And no matter how hard
l tried to deny it
the story continued to spread
until it seemed
all of Bajor had heard it.
Soon every victory
won by the resistance
was attributed to my leadership.
Stories of my brilliance,
my daring, my courage
grew more and more unbelievable
yet the people
insisted on believing them.
My reputation even followed me
into the labor camp
where my mere presence seemed
to inspire my fellow prisoners.
And l had done nothing
but shoot an unarmed Cardassian
in his underwear.
l'll never forget the look
on his face when he died.
He was so... embarrassed.
So you see, Commander
l have done
what Bajor needed me to do.
l have allowed myself
to be a slave to my reputation
all of these years.
And now...
it is enough.
They still need you.
But l am not the man
that they think l am.
Perhaps not.
But Bajor doesn't need a man.
lt needs a symbol
and that's what you are.
No one's asking you
to lead troops into battle
or to kill
a hundred Cardassians
with your bare hands.
l saw you...
in front of the crowd
on the Promenade.
They look at you
and they see strength
and honor and decency.
They look at you and see
the best in themselves.
But it's all based on a lie.
No. lt's based on a legend.
And legends are as powerful
as any truth.
Bajor still needs that legend.
lt needs you.
The Yelikan transport
is ready for departure.
Opening mooring clamps
on Docking Bay Six.
Major.
Commander.
Minister Jaro.
Li.
Navarch Li--
as of yesterday's
unanimous assembly vote.
Congratulations.
Navarch...
there's never been one before.
They felt any existing title
was inadequate
so they created
a new one for me.
l hear that thousands
of people showed up
to greet your ship
when it arrived on Bajor.
Yes, it was
quite a celebration.
l wish l could
have stayed longer.
Why? What stopped you?
The Navarch needed to return
here to assume his new post.
He's been made the Bajoran
Liaison Officer to Deep Space 9.
l already have
a liaison officer.
Not anymore, you don't.
Major Kira is no longer
assigned to this post.
She's been recalled to Bajor.