You wanted to see me,
Commander?
Actually, what l'd like to see
is next month's duty roster.
You'll have it on your desk
first thing in the morning.
That's what you said yesterday.
l know.
l just spent the whole
day yesterday...
Talking to Minister Rozahn
about irrigating
the Trilar Peninsula.
How did you know?
lt's hard to keep
a secret in Ops--
especially when you've
been shouting
at a monitor
for the last two days.
Thought l kept it down
to an angry whisper.
Let's just say
that your voice carries.
Every time l talk
to one of the ministers
l promise myself, l'm not
going to lose control.
But then they give me
some stupid bureaucratic excuse
for why something
isn't getting done
and l get so...
-so...
-Frustrated.
Oh, Commander,
l am way beyond frustrated.
Bajor is in trouble.
l just want to help.
l can understand that,
and l sympathize.
As far as l'm concerned
you can shout at the provisional
government all you want to
as long as it doesn't interfere
with your duties
here on the station.
You're right.
l'll get on that report
right away.
Oh, Major.
Quark's been looking for you.
He says it's urgent.
Perfect.
Huh?
l hear you've been trying
to get in touch with me.
You hear right.
Look around you.
Does anything seem
to be amiss?
That sonata Varani
is playing is lovely.
Your customers
seem to be enjoying him.
Why be modest, Major?
They're not just
enjoying him
they're mesmerized by him.
So?
So, while they're
being mesmerized
they're not gambling,
they're not eating
they're barely drinking.
Profits are down
across the board.
He just started yesterday.
l monitor my gross
income hourly.
My hourly figures
become my indicators.
My indicators
become my projections.
And my projections--
based on the last 26 hours--
show an unprecedented
decline in profits.
Will you stop overreacting!
When people hear
how wonderful Varani is
they'll come
beating down your door.
What are you basing
that projection on?
Bajoran intuition?
That and a strip of latinum
will get you
a couple of spins
at the dabo wheel.
You promised me you would
try him out for a month.
lf my projections hold true
in a month, l'll be
out of business.
Quark, you are going to do this.
What for?
Because l asked you to.
Maybe he could play
something with a little more...
bounce to it.
Bounce?
For a change of pace.
That was beautiful.
Having my work
appreciated again--
l've almost forgotten
how it feels.
Granted, it's not quite
the exhibition halls
you're used to.
Ah, one can't be choosy
about performance
venues these days.
l just spoke with Quark.
He likes what you're doing
but he's hoping you'll play
a variety of styles.
A little less exhibition hall
a little more music hall,
is that it?
Something like that.
l think l can accommodate him.
Dabo!
l'd love to hear you play
in a more appropriate setting.
Have you spoken
to Minister Bolka
about my idea to rebuild
the Jalanda Forum?
l mentioned it to him.
He's got a lot on his mind.
You must keep trying.
Bajorans must reclaim
their artistic heritage
if they ever hope to regain
their sense of self-worth.
Next time l talk to the
Minister, l'll bring it up again
but l can't promise anything.
Ah, Major.
Get everything settled
with Quark?
Oh, that little toad is this far
from doing a 360 out an airlock.
l'm glad to hear
everything went okay.
Commander, sensors are picking
up elevated neutrino readings.
A ship's coming
through the wormhole.
On screen.
Sensors are detecting
four life-forms on board.
l'm reading a plasma leak
in their engine core.
Hail them.
No response.
The reactor's overheating.
Life support is
barely functioning.
Get them out of there, Chief.
Aye, sir.
l'm Commander Sisko
of the United
Federation of Planets.
You've just been
beamed aboard
a Bajoran space station.
We don't mean you any harm.
We're going to bring
your ship in.
Once it's docked
we'll diagnose its problems
and hopefully fix them.
After that,
you can be on your way.
l can offer medical
assistance for that wound.
Oo-mata! Oo-mata!
Dongo patar meeoto fenta!
Fenta!
Naga dentana.
Dentana.
Oobay a-tal?
Oobay a-tal.
Keetama sootay.
Shalanta Skrreea.
Skrreea.
Does anyone understand
what she's saying?
Something must be wrong with
the universal translator.
Chief?
lt's working, Commander
but for some reason,
it's having a hard time
analyzing
their language patterns.
Their syntax
and their grammatical structure
must be completely unlike
anything in our database.
We'll have to keep them talking
until the computer can establish
a translation matrix.
Ketoh maseeca.
Skrreea.
Tolak mayssefaka.
Koo samek.
Gadoux besoolin fenta.
Fenta?
Keeping them talking
shouldn't be much of a problem.
Oobay a-tal?
Fisdak setoma meeka?
Major, we've got to get them
down to the lnfirmary.
They seem to be
most comfortable with you.
Why don't you lead the way?
A-All right.
Um... we're going to take
a little ride on the turbolift.
Toma.
Bessa.
Sisko to Odo.
Yes, Commander.
We're bringing some new arrivals
from the Gamma Quadrant
down to the Promenade.
Meet us at Turbolift 9.
l'm on my way.
We're here.
You can come out now.
There's no need to be afraid.
Come on.
lt's all right.
What seems to be the trouble,
Commander?
The computer's
having a hard time
translating their language.
l can see how that
would be a problem.
lt's okay.
Come on.
Hold on!
Let's stick together.
No wandering off.
Now you just stay put
while l round up your friend.
Uh, let me try.
Come with me.
Hello.
lntaowa.
Dress.
lt's called a dress.
lntaowa.
lntaowa?
Uh, l'm afraid
you'll have to put that back.
Vala.
Vala!
lntaowa!
Do you like it?
Yes, it's very nice,
but it's not yours.
And that, that goes
for you, too.
Major, perhaps you'd
better handle this.
All right.
Let's put those back--
both of you.
They really need
to put those back.
We can go shopping later
but right now,
it's very important
that we go to the lnfirmary.
So, everyone, follow me.
We'll all go together.
Fazeek.
Cromay fazeek!
Kootana.
Kootana batoo lakar asheem!
Dokka!
Pestani voe lakar asheem.
Kolat kee!
Hmm, there's no doubt
who the boss is.
How bad is it, Doctor?
Looks like a second-degree
plasma burn.
The dermal regenerator
should take care of it.
l'm sorry.
l'm not the doctor.
Kolat gadoux?
l assure you...
l will not hurt him.
He's going to be all right.
These will be your quarters
while you're here
at the station.
l'm sure you want to rest
and clean up and...
you don't understand
anything l'm saying, do you?
l know something
they might understand.
Seven maaza stalks.
This is food.
Please, try one.
Major, show them it's okay.
See.
Mmm.
Mmm, it's really very good.
Mmm...
l'm glad you like them.
Naloux bataak rama setta.
Rama emal jeetaka.
Zoola koo.
Gadoux soka gee.
l'm sorry,
l still don't understand.
Bataak rama setta.
Rama setta.
Zoola koo.
Hemena kee.
Soulak.
Need ikstassa.
Wait.
Did you hear that?
l think she said ''need.''
Go on, keep talking.
Ganoux.
Noloux bataak rama setta.
My people yeekopa
Skrreea.
Havou fotar save them.
Save them? How?
Do you understand
what l'm saying?
Keep talking.
Noloux Skrreea.
Soka roo need your help.
There's no time soulak.
We are the Skrreea.
My people need your help.
There's no time to waste.
Your people are the Skrreea.
You need our help.
There's no time to waste.
Your people-- where are they?
They are on the creshnee
side of the Eye.
The ''Eye?''
The Eye of the Universe.
The tunnel.
l think she means the wormhole.
They are on the other side.
They don't realize
we found the Eye.
How many people
are we talking about?
Many... three jeetaka.
Three hundred?
Three thousand?
Three million?
Three million.
Three million of my people
are on the other side.
We must bring them
through the Eye.
We must bring them here.
l-ls there anything wrong?
l'm just not used
to the men being here.
Skrreean men don't
involve themselves
in situations like this.
Are all your leaders women?
Yes.
All of them?
You heard her, Julian.
Men are far too emotional
to be leaders.
They're constantly
fighting among themselves.
lt's their favorite thing to do.
l'm sorry.
l hope l haven't
offended anyone.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
lt's all right, Benjamin.
Haneek was just telling us
how the Skrreea are
a female-dominant society.
lt seems the men are a bit
too emotional to be leaders.
Please do not misunderstand.
We love our men.
Really!
Are you one of the leaders
of your people, Haneek?
Me?
Oh, no.
l'm little more than a farmer.
l was just lucky.
How so?
l was the first one to find
the Eye of the Universe.
You were looking
for the wormhole?
We had heard about a great
tunnel being discovered.
We knew it must be
the Eye of the Universe
that would lead us to Kentanna.
Kentanna?
Kentanna is the legendary
home of the Skrreeans.
lt has always been portrayed
in our sacred texts
as being just beyond
the Eye of the Universe.
A planet of sorrow,
where the Skrreean will sow
seeds of joy.
l can't guarantee
you'll find Kentanna.
But l can promise you
that we'll help you find a home.
We sent our runabouts
to the Gamma Quadrant
to make contact with your ships.
That will be difficult.
They're all spread out
looking for the Eye.
And when we find them--
what then?
This station
only holds 7,000 people.
You're talking about
three million Skrreeans.
l'm afraid most of your people
will have to be confined
to their ships.
l understand.
ln the meantime
is there any one person
we should be looking for?
A leader or leaders?
Most of our leaders were
killed by the T-Rogorans.
The T-Rogorans.
Who are they?
For eight centuries, my people
have lived under their rule.
We have been forced to work
as laborers and servants.
We were able to escape
when the T-Rogorans were invaded
and conquered.
Who conquered them?
l do not know their name.
l only know they were members
of something called
''The Dominion.''
Did l wake you?
Oh, that's all right.
Please, come in.
Computer, lights on full.
l can come back.
No.
You've been so kind to me.
How could l possibly
refuse your company?
Go back to bed.
Go on!
Go on.
l'll join you again
after l'm through.
Are those your husbands?
Hus-bands?
l'm not familiar with that word.
They're bonded to me.
Do you sleep with them both?
Of course.
Don't you sleep with your males?
No, l don't have any males.
Not at the moment, anyway.
They're very useful.
Yes, l can imagine they are.
l just wanted to tell you,
we found some of your ships.
Several hundred
Skrreeans should be
arriving at the station today.
We thought it would be
a good idea
if you were there to greet them.
Why me?
You yourself said most
of your leaders were dead.
Yes, that's true,
but, Kira, l'm just a farmer.
You also were the first one
through the Eye of the Universe.
That's got to mean something...
in some symbolic sort of way.
Oh, here.
l brought you something.
Go ahead, open it.
You seemed to like it.
l'm sorry.
l think you misunderstood.
What do you mean?
l thought this was
the most hideous thing
l'd ever seen.
Well, that makes two of us.
lt's awful.
lt's horrible.
Who would wear that?
lt was no big deal.
You go on a date with a dabo
girl for the first time
and you sit there and tell me
it was no big deal?
lt wasn't really a date.
Does your father know
you went out with her?
Not exactly.
He doesn't?
l told him l had to help
someone with her homework.
Good thinking.
Too bad l'll never
be able to use that lie.
My dad knows
l never do homework.
lt's not a lie, Nog.
Mardah's studying entomology.
She asked me to help her out.
A dabo girl
who studies entomology?
Ha! Sure.
lt's true.
Yeah.
What is entomology?
The study of bugs.
Oh, you mean
she wants to be a chef?
Hey, who's that?
l don't know.
What's he doing?
Oh, that's disgusting!
He must be
one of those Skrreeans.
My dad says there's
a lot more on the way.
Hi!
Doesn't he know
what a replicator's for?
ldiot!
So, does Mardah
have any sisters?
Commander, l've cleared
the Skrreean ship
to dock at Upper Pylon 2.
lt's time to welcome your people
to the Alpha Quadrant, Haneek.
Come along, don't be afraid.
Come on, it's all right.
You're among friends.
Don't be afraid.
lt's all right.
Slow down!
There's no running
on the Promenade.
lt's going to get
awfully crowded
around here, Commander.
l know, Constable,
but it's worth it.
Just look at them.
They're experiencing
their first taste of freedom.
Nog, where you going?
Can't talk now.
Gotta run!
Nog!
You know there's no running
on the Promenade.
Who's running?
What seems to be
the problem here?
What's that smell?
Ask him.
Me?
You're the one who stinks.
That's because you sprayed
that vapor on us.
ls that true, Nog?
No!
Nog...
lt was a joke.
Very amusing.
Thank you for bringing
this to my attention.
l'll take care of it from here.
This isn't over yet, big ears.
Hey, here's a new one.
What kind of name is
''Plix Tixiplik?''
l believe he's a Reegrunion.
''Wanted in seven star systems
for illegal weapon sales.''
Weapon sales, huh?
Very profitable.
How would you know about that?
My Uncle Quark told me.
And what would your Uncle Quark
know about illegal weapon sales?
He, uh... he, uh...
Knows better than to ever
get involved in anything
so disreputable.
l'm sure.
l asked that the boy's father
come to see me.
Rom is doing
the weekly stock inventory.
l don't want to interrupt him.
You know how easy
he loses count.
So, l came in his place.
Nog, have you been
causing mischief again?
No, Uncle.
lt's all a misunderstanding.
He sprayed
several Skrreean boys
with a foul-smelling vapor.
Did he?
What do you have
to say for yourself?
l-l'm sorry...?
You see the boy's
beside himself with guilt.
That doesn't excuse his actions.
And he will be
punished severely.
l will?
l want you to tell
the Constable here
that you will never do it again.
l won't?
l mean, l won't.
l promise.
Never again.
See that you don't.
Can l leave now?
Go on.
You know, you really
can't blame the boy.
And why is that?
Oh, come on, Odo.
You know these Skrreeans
are nothing but trouble.
They're all over the station
looking and touching,
never buying anything.
And they flake.
l didn't notice.
Come to my place.
You'll see little pieces
of Skrreean skin
all over the bar and the floor.
lt's disgusting.
Well, they won't be here long.
l hope not.
They're driving
my paying customers away.
They stay here too long,
and l'll be out of business.
ln that case,
l hope they never leave.
We've talked it over
among ourselves.
Our feelings were unanimous.
You discovered
the Eye of the Universe.
You must lead us
the rest of the way.
l'll do the best l can.
That looked serious.
ls everything all right?
Look at them.
Look at my people.
l've never seen them so happy
and here l sit, feeling trapped.
Why?
They expect me
to lead them to Kentanna.
lt's going to be okay.
Commander Sisko is doing
everything he can
to find you a place to live.
You're not alone.
l hope l'm not intruding.
Oh, not at all.
Haneek, this is Varani,
a great musician.
Maybe the greatest
Bajor has ever known.
She exaggerates, but that's
why l'm so fond of her.
Being a Bajoran, l know what
it's like to be displaced.
As a token of friendship,
l would like to give you this.
lt's from a concert
l played
many years ago
at the Jalanda Forum.
Tumak, where have you been?
Nowhere.
Where are you going?
To wash.
Computer...
please show me a chart
of this star system.
So, what'd your dad say?
About what?
About you getting
in trouble with Odo.
He was very angry.
He was?
He always gets angry
when l get caught.
l just remembered.
l have some errands
to run for my uncle.
You're going to have
to face them
sooner or later.
That was very funny,
what you did.
You see, Jake?
There's a man
with a sense of humor.
Nobody's laughing.
And luckily nobody got hurt.
l think my friend's real
sorry for what he did.
Aren't you?
l suppose.
See?
What'd l tell you?
He doesn't sound sorry to me.
l'm sorry, l'm sorry.
That's enough.
Break it up.
l said, break it up!
lt's bad enough you're
all hanging around the station
without buying anything.
You have to start fighting, too?
l thought we were welcome here.
Well, make yourself welcome
somewhere else.
You don't want us here.
You don't want anything
to do with us.
Well, we don't want anything
to do with you.
Any of you!
l can see the Skrreeans
don't bother
to teach their children manners.
Dax and l have been
combing through data
on every uninhabited
M-Class planet in the sector.
We think that Draylon ll
would make a perfect home
for the Skrreea.
Draylon ll?
l've never heard of it.
lt's near Sefalla Prime.
lt's got definite possibilities.
Stable orbit, temperate climate
and a very low
surface radiation.
Add to that good soil
and a long growing season.
l think it's our best bet.
May we come in?
Of course.
Ladies.
Forgive them, Commander Sisko.
They don't mean any disrespect.
l understand.
We have some encouraging news.
We think we've found a planet
for you and your people,
one with excellent potential
for resettlement.
We appreciate all your hard work
but l'm afraid
it was unnecessary.
You see, we found Kentanna.
You did?
A planet of sorrow, Kira.
Don't you see?
Kentanna is your planet.
Kentanna is Bajor.
Station Log, Stardate 47391.2.
Chief O'Brien is continuing
to oversee repairs
to the Skrreean ships docked
at the station.
Meanwhile, Minister Rozahn
and Vedek Sorad have arrived
from Bajor
with an official response
to the Skrreeans' request
to immigrate.
Major, if l may have a moment?
l'm sorry, Varani.
l'm on my way to a meeting.
l know-- with Minister
Rozahn and Vedek Sorad.
l presume Haneek
will be there as well.
That's right.
Please tell here that my heart
goes out to her and her people.
Tell her how much
Bajorans everywhere
regret having to refuse
their request.
Aren't you being
a little premature?
Am l? You know what
the provisional government's
answer is going to be.
These are people who have
lost everything, Varani.
l know, and l wish there was
some way we could help them.
But Bajor is in shambles, Kira.
You know that as well as l do.
First of all,
l want you all to know
that the provisional government
has taken the Skrreeans' request
for immigration very seriously.
The debate
in the Chamber of Ministers
became quite heated at times.
Though l suppose
you could say that
about all of our debates.
But a decision was reached.
Yes, l was sent here to tell you
that the Ministers-- in accord
with the Vedek Assembly--
have decided to deny
the Skrreeans' request.
l am sorry.
Bajor simply cannot absorb three
million refugees at this time.
After what the Cardassians
did to our planet
we can barely
take care of our own.
But no one is asking you
to take care of us.
This decision is not based
strictly on Bajoran
self-interest.
Such a huge increase
in population
would prove to be tragic
to your people as well as ours.
But Bajor has more
than enough room for us.
The plains
of the Northwest Peninsula
are practically uninhabited.
The land's ideal for farming.
lt used to be
before the Cardassians
got their hands on it.
Minister Rozahn,
the Skrreea are farmers.
Just give us the land.
l guarantee you,
we can make it thrive again.
Under ideal circumstances,
perhaps you could.
But what if the circumstances
aren't ideal?
What if we go through
another long winter?
What if your crops fail?
What if the famine
that has been plaguing Bajor
continues to spread?
What then?
We are willing
to take that risk.
l'm afraid we aren't.
We ran a series of projections
to see whether a Skrreean
settlement could survive
on the Northwest peninsula.
The results were
not encouraging.
Haneek?
l think you should
seriously consider
Draylon ll as an alternate
to Bajor.
The winters are mild.
There's plenty of good farmland.
No!
Projections can be wrong.
But what if they're not?
What is Bajor to do
if your people start dying?
l thought l made that clear.
We are not expecting your help.
Do you really think we could
stand by and do nothing?
We would feel obligated to help
with food, with clothing
with whatever it would take.
And where would
that aid come from?
Our resources
are already depleted.
To help you would mean
depriving our own people.
l am afraid the decision
of the provisional government
is final.
The Skrreea will have
to find somewhere else to live.
Please, talk to them.
Tell them they're wrong.
Help us.
l can't.
l'm sorry, Haneek...
but they're right.
l wish they weren't.
l wish Bajor was Kentanna.
But it's not.
There's still Draylon ll.
Ooh!
Look at this!
Excuse me.
lf you like cake
the icoberry torte
is really good.
ls that big-eared troll
really your friend?
Yeah.
He's an idiot.
You're not the first
to say that.
But he's not such a bad guy
once you get to know him.
l don't plan on being
around here that long.
My dad says you're probably
going to Draylon ll.
Does he?
Yeah, sounds like a nice place.
Do you want to move there?
No.
Neither do l.
Come in.
Haneek...
The thing l don't understand
is why you pretended
to be my friend.
l wasn't pretending.
Ahh!
So you are my friend...
until l need you.
l know it's hard
for you to see right now
but l am trying to help.
l think l've had quite enough
of your help.
You've got to believe me.
Commander Sisko
has found you a wonderful home.
You betrayed me, Kira.
No, l didn't.
l honestly believe
the provisional government
made the right decision
both for Bajor
and the Skrreeans.
lf that's true,
we have nothing more to discuss.
l was hoping
we could still be friends.
So in other words, you came here
looking for forgiveness.
Well, l don't forgive you.
Sisko to Kira.
Go ahead, Commander.
ls Haneek with you?
Yes.
l need both of you
in Ops immediately.
Tumak has taken a ship.
He's headed for Bajor.
They're not responding, sir.
Keep trying, Mr. O'Brien.
How did this happen?
With all the traffic
around the station
Tumak and two of his friends
were able to slip away.
We didn't even know
the ship was gone
until the Bajorans contacted us.
Haneek, l need for you
to try to talk to your son.
There's a high-energy radiation
leak in the port nacelle.
l've tried
to make him aware of it
but he refuses
to acknowledge us.
Major, open a channel
to the Skrreean vessel.
Yes, sir.
Ready.
Tumak?
Listen to me.
Your ship's in danger.
Have him turn off
his engines and drift
until the Bajorans
can tractor him in.
Tumak, turn off your engines.
You must turn
your engines off, now!
He's not responding.
Tumak, this is serious!
Your life is in danger.
The others who are with you,
their lives are in danger.
Please!
Answer me!
Sensors are detecting
two Bajoran vessels
closing in on the Skrreean ship.
Display it here.
Mr. O'Brien, patch us
into the Bajoran interceptor.
Aye, sir.
...entered restricted space.
You must turn around
and leave immediately.
Open a channel.
This is Major Kira
Nerys on Deep Space 9.
The Skrreean vessel has refused
to acknowledge our hails.
Communications may be down.
You have to let them land.
That's impossible, Major.
We have strict orders
not to allow
any Skrreean vessel to land.
The pilot's just a boy.
He took the ship
without permission.
lt's barely operational.
We're not even sure
he'll make it back here.
l'm sorry, Major,
but we have our orders.
Who gave you those orders?
They come directly
from General Hazar.
Dax, get me General Hazar
on Bajor.
Tell his people
it's an emergency.
l want to speak to him now.
Stand by, interceptor.
General Hazar will be
countermanding
those orders any minute.
The interceptor is closing
on the Skrreean ship.
lt's General Hazar, Benjamin.
On screen.
What is this about, Commander?
lt's about the Skrreean vessel
that's approaching Bajor.
l've already given the orders
to have it turned back.
That ship is being flown
by a child
and it's leaking radiation.
A child?
...Skrreean ship.
Repeating.
Return to the space station now.
Have him shut down his engines.
We'll tow him back.
Tumak, please,
turn your engines off.
lnterceptor One,
what's going on?
They've opened fire on us.
Taking evasive action.
Tumak, don't do this!
We've been hit!
Commander,
they're returning fire.
No!
Disengage, interceptor!
Repeat, disengage.
General, tell your pilots
to hold their fire.
Relaying that order now.
lnterceptor One.
The Skrreean ship exploded.
l didn't even think we hit it.
The phaser beam must've
ignited the radiation leak.
l'm very sorry, Commander.
We all are, General.
l just stopped by to wish
you luck on Draylon ll.
Haneek, l still believe
this is the best choice...
for Bajor and for you.
You still believe
we would have been a burden
to your people?
Yes.
l think you've made
a terrible mistake.
All of you.
Maybe we could
have helped you.
Maybe we could have
helped each other.
The Skrreeans are farmers, Kira.
You have a famine
on your planet.
Perhaps we could have made
that peninsula bloom again.
We'll never know, will we?
50 years of Cardassian rule
have made you all frightened
and suspicious.
l feel sorry for you.
You were right.
Bajor is not Kentanna.