Station Log, Stardate 47 573.1.
To respond to questions
about setting up colonies
near the wormhole
Chief O'Brien and l have set out
to survey nearby star systems.
lf it's an imposition...
No, sir, it's fine.
You're sure?
l'm sure, Commander.
Jake's a good fellow.
l'll enjoy working with him.
l don't want you to make it
easy for him, Chief.
He has to know what it takes
to make it in Starfleet.
l'll have him
up to his elbows
in thorium grease, sir.
lt's not going
to be easy for him.
He placed in the lower
third of his age group
in mechanical aptitude.
Oh, good for him.
So did l.
You? Come on.
No, it's true.
lt wasn't until l got
to the Cardassian front
l found out l had talents
l never knew l had.
At the front?
lt was a matter of figuring out
how to get a field transporter
operational in ten minutes
or wind up being
a Cardassian prisoner of war.
Now, l didn't know a transporter
from a turbolift in those days
but somehow,
in nine minutes, 53 seconds
l got that thing to work.
l got 13 men safely
off the surface of Setlik lll.
Next thing l know
l'm the tactical officer
on the Rutledge.
That's how l got the gold suit.
Well, Jake is ready
for a new suit, too.
The boy seems to grow
a centimeter each week.
You know, he struck me out
with a curve ball the other day.
First time.
They grow up in a hurry,
don't they, sir?
That they do.
l think l've got one.
Computer, set a new heading.
41 mark 301.
Confirmed.
lt's an M-Class, all right.
160 million kilometers
from Orellius Minor.
Should be a perfect place
to set up a colony.
Mm-hmm, but it looks like
someone's beaten us to it.
You're reading life-forms?
Human life-forms.
l don't see anything
on the books
about a colony
in the Orellius system.
Trying all hailing frequencies.
Moving into synchronous orbit.
No response.
l'm picking up some kind of low-
level duonetic field down there.
lt may be blocking
communications.
Let's introduce ourselves
to our neighbors.
Yours, too?
Even the self-diagnostics
aren't working.
Just plain dead.
Sisko to Rio Grande.
Computer, respond.
l'd say there's no EM activity
at all around here.
Any idea why?
l'm not sure.
But it might have
something to do
with that duonetic field
our sensors picked up.
Well, l hope you find
a few more of those talents
you never knew you had
because, if you don't,
we're going to have
a hard time getting off this...
Don't move!
And put your hands up!
Turn around...
slowly.
They're from Starfleet.
That's right.
Mind if we put our hands down?
Well, the uniforms
have changed...
or have l just forgotten
what they look like?
My name is Joseph.
Vinod's the one playing
with the sharp object.
l'm Benjamin Sisko
and this is Miles O'Brien.
How did you get here?
We were going to ask you
the same thing.
We were surveying
for habitable planets
when our sensors picked
up your life signs.
There was no record
of a human colony here.
Well, our group was on its way
to settle on Gemulon V
over ten years ago
when our ship developed
life support problems
and we had to land here
for repairs.
Once we got here,
all our systems failed.
Nothing worked anymore.
So we've seen.
We've been stuck here
ever since.
And l guess you are, too, now.
We have a ship in orbit.
lt won't take our people
long to find us.
We'll be able
to get you all out of here.
Well, after ten years,
this is our home.
But you just said it yourself--
nothing works.
Well, we still do.
Well, come, we'll show you.
Vinod, run ahead
and tell your mother, uh...
we have guests.
Come.
Erewon-class
personnel transport.
Commissioned the Santa Maria.
Now we just call it ''the cabin.''
After all this time-- visitors!
Alixus, meet Ben and Miles.
Welcome to our community.
Miles.
Are there others?
Just an empty runabout in orbit.
Hopefully, it will
attract some attention.
A runabout-- is that some kind
of new Starfleet vessel?
Yeah, they commissioned
the first ones two years ago.
They're a short-range
interstellar craft
about a quarter the size
of your ''cabin'' there.
l was the engineer
aboard the Santa Maria.
You and Miles will have a lot
to talk about, Joseph.
l'm sure all of us have
questions for our guests.
Who won the soccer matches
this year?
ls Golanga still playing?
No, he hurt his knee
four years ago.
They replaced it
with a bio-implant
but he wasn't
the same after that.
Who was it that won
last year, anyway?
l can never remember.
What are women's fashions like
back home now?
Oh, well...
Chief, you're the married one.
Oh, Keiko, my wife
she's been replicating
longer dresses lately.
Oh, no, that means
l'll have to alter
everything l own.
Well, that may just be
the Bajoran styles
she sees on Deep Space 9.
On Deep Space 9?
l'm sure Ben and Miles
will be happy to tell us
everything we want to know.
There will be plenty
of time for that later.
Actually, the first
thing l'd like to do
is try and get some response
from the EM systems.
We gave up any hope
of that years ago.
Yes, we noticed a low-level
duonetic field in the area
before we transported down.
Yes, the same thing
appeared on our sensors
when we were landing.
Our engines failed almost
the instant we hit the surface.
Without a functional tricorder
it was virtually impossible
to track down the source.
We do know that the
marshes all around us
are filled
with astatine deposits.
That's the only
explanation we have.
But we've done pretty well
without our tricorders
EM converters and com links,
haven't we?
After all, the human body
is a powerful tool.
We can plow the crops,
harvest the fields
construct the walls
that we need for protection
against the wilderness.
Weave the clothes that
we need to stay warm.
ln a way, we've rediscovered
what man is capable of
without technology.
lt hasn't been easy.
We've had some bitter winters
and... we've lost
some dear friends.
But we're very proud
of what we've accomplished here.
You have every right to be.
Are we all going to leave
when the others come
to rescue them?
That's something each of us
is going to have
to think about, isn't it?
Are you going to leave, Alixus?
Speaking for myself, no.
No, l'll never leave.
And l'll never want what we have
in our community to change.
lt means too much to me.
But while you are here
you are welcome to everything
our community has to offer.
The only thing we ask
is that you contribute.
We all work for our supper.
You'd be surprised
how much sweeter it tastes
when you do.
We'll be happy to do our part.
Joseph, would you find them
some bunks, please?
Two more strong,
healthy men, Vinod.
That could mean an awful lot
to this community.
Do you know an Admiral Mitsuya?
Best poker player in the fleet,
next to me.
Well, he's diverting
the Crockett
to stop at DS9
day after tomorrow
to talk about Cardassian
foreign policy?
That's just an excuse
to get Benjamin in a game.
Mitsuya cleaned him out
last year.
We better hail the Rio Grande
and get them
headed back this way.
l've worked two lifetimes
on Benjamin's poker.
He just can't learn
how to bluff.
That's odd.
l know, you'd think
a man like Benjamin...
No, the Rio Grande...
it's not responding
to our hails.
Commander?
Oh, come in, Chief.
l was just reading
one of the books
our host has written.
Alixus is quite
a prolific author.
Yeah, a bunch of these
were left in my room, too.
l haven't had a chance
to look at them.
What does she write about?
She seems to have something
to say on just about everything.
Yeah?
Economic analysis,
political commentaries
literary critiques.
She says she's spent her life
examining the human condition.
And what's her prognosis?
Not very good.
She says we have become
fat and lazy and dull.
My wife told me something along
those lines just last week.
''The common conceit that
the human species has evolved
''over the last several
centuries is ludicrous.
''What gains we have made
''have come at the cost
of our own core identities.
Man has lost touch
with his true power.''
Sounds like it took
a crash landing
for her to find her paradise.
Have you found anything
in their ship
that can help us restore
contact with the runabout?
There's nothing to find.
Wave guides,
conduits, baffle plates--
you name it, it's gone.
The ship looks like
it's been through
a Ferengi junkyard.
What happened to it all?
We threw it away.
Well, since,
uh, none of it worked
to us, it was merely useless
junk taking up space.
Alixus felt its presence
was a constant reminder
of who you used to be.
Well, we all had to abandon
our dependence upon technology.
Removing every trace of it--
well, that made
the transition easier.
As an engineer,
you must have had
some problems with that.
Well, l was the last convert.
But, as time passed,
l realized Alixus was right.
She was helping us discover
a new philosophy of life
together
because we needed one
to survive.
And l'll tell you, every one
of us is better for it.
We are more committed
to each other.
We are truly a part
of each other's lives.
We've renewed a sense
of community
that man left behind
centuries ago.
Joseph, Meg's fever
is getting worse.
The new herb doesn't seem
to be helping at all.
May l see?
Please.
We have an insect here
that transmits a disease
we haven't found a cure for.
We've lost three to it already.
Have you found
anything in the forest
like the sleeper fungi?
We've searched everywhere
for the right fungus or root
that would draw out
the infection.
lf it keeps spreading
she'll die
before the rescue team finds us.
The medical kit in the runabout
could probably
take care of this in a second.
We have got to find a way
to restore the com link
to the transporter.
That would only be
a waste of time.
This duonetic field
inhibits energy flow
but a duonetic field
is a form of energy, too.
Maybe we could modify
our communicators
to run on the field itself.
Do you really think you could?
No!
lf you want to put
your efforts to good use
search the forest
for something else we might use.
This is primitive medicine.
You can't expect to save her...
Ben! May l see you
outside, please?
Talk like that isn't
constructive.
l'm talking
about saving the life
of one of your followers.
You don't understand this yet.
No one follows me.
They follow their own hearts.
My heart tells me to try
to get back to my ship.
l'm sure it does
but if we'd had that attitude
for the last ten years
we wouldn't have been doing
what was necessary
to survive here.
To find the plants, herbs, molds
that cure disease.
We've conquered 17 illnesses
with the most powerful resource
man has--
his ingenuity.
An interesting philosophy.
And while we're debating
it, a woman is dying.
We're doing everything
we can for her.
No, we're not.
l won't have you disrupting
everything this community
has worked for, Ben.
l don't intend to stay here
any longer than necessary.
And that's another thing.
Let's not bring up the Starfleet
rescue party again.
Until they come-- if they come--
you'll have to do things
our way.
l'd strongly advise
you get rid of that uniform.
By mid-afternoon,
it gets hot in the fields.
The Rio Grande's been spotted.
Where?
Details are coming in
from Starfleet.
The Romulan vessel Gasko
reported seeing
an abandoned runabout.
Markings NCC-72452.
That's our ship, all right.
Traveling at warp 2
through sector 401.
At warp, with no one on board?
Command wants to know
if we can send someone
to investigate.
Signal them affirmative.
l already have.
Runabout Pad C.
You've got a real
talent for this, Ben.
Well, my father was a chef.
He grew all his own vegetables.
My brothers and l were sent out
to the gardens every day.
Most of the others--
they'd only eaten
replicated food
before they got here.
The flavor of the foods
we prepare
was quite a surprise to them.
But not you?
My mother would never
let me eat replicated food.
What?
l can't help thinking
what my wife would say
if she saw me doing this.
Why?
Well, around my house, l'm
known as ''the black thumb.''
l'm just one
of those people, you know.
The only way l could get
anything to grow
was to marry a botanist.
Oh, a botanist, really?
Yeah.
You should have seen
the arboretum
she grew on the Enterprise.
That's where l asked her
to marry me.
Oh, she'd love it here.
Maybe you'll bring her someday.
Trouble is,
she wouldn't want to leave.
That's okay, too.
Come on.
Reach in.
Get my hand.
Here we go.
Good.
Easy now.
Get him into the shade.
All right, sit him down there.
Easy, easy.
All right, here.
Here, Stephan,
if you chew these
they will help you
regain your strength.
What did he do to deserve this?
He stole a candle.
One candle?
How long was he in there?
Since yesterday.
ln that hell box?
ls this part of your philosophy
of life, too?
You're a Starfleet Commander.
l'm sure
you've had to discipline
members of your crew.
Discipline is one thing.
Torture is another.
The first thing
this community accepted
was the need to establish
rules of conduct.
All of us, including Stephan
approved this form
of punishment as necessary
and fair.
How are you, Stephan?
l'll be all right.
l'm sorry, Alixus,
that l let down the community.
The matter is closed.
Go inside.
Get some rest now.
Thank you, Alixus.
Come on, easy.
Easy.
Stephan will never
steal another candle
and neither will anyone else
who saw him here today.
ln time, you'll understand
that this is a simple
and effective way
to maintain law and order
in our community.
l get the distinct impression
she expects us
to be here for a while.
lf there is a way to adapt the
energy in the duonetic field
to get us back to the runabout
l want you to find it, Chief.
Yes, sir.
ls there anything you need?
No, l don't think so.
l'm sorry, Alixus
doesn't believe in doors.
We all take it for granted now.
You'll get used to it.
Hopefully, l won't be here
long enough to get used to it.
You don't like it here, do you?
lt's not what l'm used to.
Alixus has reminded us all
that it wasn't easy
for us at first either.
She's told us
to be patient with you.
Has she?
Your muscles must be sore
from all the work today.
This is an oil extract
from the Xupta tree.
lt's wonderfully soothing.
Thanks, l'll try some.
Would you like me
to massage you with it?
l don't think so.
Thanks anyway.
lt'll make you feel
a lot better.
Here, let me show you.
Did she send you here?
Did she send you here
to make love to me?
Ben, come in.
l was just writing about you
and Miles in my journal.
l understand
you're quite a chef.
That's the first core behavior
l've seen from you
since you arrived.
Core behavior.
Does that chapter come
before or after
sexual procurement?
l assume you're talking
about Cassandra?
Did you send her to my room?
Yes.
l think you're contemptible.
lnteresting.
Contemptible.
Try and see it
through our eyes
just for a moment, Ben.
Cassandra came to me;
she was worried.
She sensed
that you weren't happy.
She was right about that.
She was concerned
that all you see here
is work and hardship
and she wanted you to share
in our joy as well.
So you sent her to me to win
my devotion to your cause.
l suggested she might
make it easier for you
to become a member
of our community.
The choice was hers.
Cassandra really likes you, Ben.
lt's fortunate that all these
books of yours aren't on padds
like the other materials
the colonists brought.
l used to print them myself.
l'm not surprised.
Vinod tells me that you never
ate replicated food
before you came here.
l'm not sure
l see the connection.
lt's just that you
never had much use
for technology, did you?
lt's interesting how you
happened to crash on a planet
that fit your philosophy
of life so well.
l agree.
ln fact, l've started
writing a book
about our experiences.
l've been wondering
if, in the ancient
religions of man
there aren't some new
truths to be found--
something to explain
how sometimes fate delivers us
exactly where we need to be.
Perhaps one day,
you'll even feel
the hand of God
on your shoulder.
You won't give a millimeter,
will you?
Look at you,
still in your uniform
wanting so badly to get
back to your station
with its artificial gravity
and its sterilized air.
You are so disconnected
from your core identity, Ben.
There is a better way.
How can we help you see it?
Perhaps good hard
work is the answer.
Vinod.
Yes, Mother?
Ben will be standing
watch tonight.
Are you all right, Commander?
l'm a little tired,
but l'll be fine.
Any luck on your end?
This duonetic field
is still a mystery, sir.
l can't believe
it's being generated
by the astatine deposits
in the stream bed.
Good morning, Ben.
Ready for some breakfast?
We have some lovely fruit.
Try this.
We found it growing
along the riverbank
a few years ago.
lt's some kind of native pear.
Oh, Ben, will you be able
to work your regular shift
in the field today?
What are you talking about?
You just had him up all night,
standing watch.
Of course, if you'd like
to be relieved of your duties
all you have to do is ask.
l'll work my shift.
Good. We're so shorthanded
out there.
But you really should
do yourself a favor
and change into some
more comfortable clothes.
Oh, by the way, you'll
be pleased to know
Meg seems better this morning.
Joseph is very optimistic
about a new combination
of herbs he's trying.
We're picking up a ship ahead.
lt's the Rio Grande,
moving at warp 1.3.
Plotting an intercept course.
Once we're abeam,
match our speeds exactly
and l'll transport over.
Like hell you will.
Sorry,
l'm the ranking officer here.
At warp, l wouldn't be
in such a hurry to volunteer.
You got a better idea?
l'm the science officer.
lt's my job
to have a better idea.
What are you doing?
l'm trying an old rope trick
l learned on Earth once.
A rope trick?
A very talented Hopi l knew
did things with a rope
you wouldn't believe.
lt's an Old West American
art form.
You're suggesting we try to rope
the Rio Grande at warp.
With a tractor beam.
Once we pull it back to impulse,
isn't there a risk
that the strain
will rip both hulls apart?
lf the ship assembly teams
back at the yards
did their jobs really well,
we'll probably make it.
lf they had an off day,
we're going to have a problem
but it's our best shot.
Unless as a ranking officer,
you have a better idea.
We're within tractor range.
Locking on.
Engaging impulse engines.
Remind me to send
a thank-you note
to the assembly teams.
All stop.
Computer, ready transporter.
Meg has died.
Suddenly, quietly.
No one was prouder
of what we've accomplished here
than Meg was.
Her dedication
to this community
and to us, was an inspiration
which is why l find myself
so troubled today by an act
that, by its very nature,
defiles her memory.
Vinod.
All of us have welcomed
our new arrivals with open arms
but they continue to reject us.
Despite their agreement
to respect
our fundamental way of life
this man has committed
the worst offense
that can be committed
against this community.
He has selfishly
wasted precious time
that could have been
put to productive use.
Miles was discovered
trying to activate
his technological devices
so he could return to his ship.
Alixus, l'm sure
he only wanted to get
to the medical equipment
which might have saved
Meg's life.
Thank you, Joseph.
l knew you would feel that way
and l'm glad you said it,
so that all of us could see
the true danger
these two represent.
Our very own Joseph
defending
what he knows is wrong.
He knows that if we
had spent our energy
all these years,
trying to escape
we'd all be dead today.
This is good.
This is a test
of our convictions
and we will survive.
You're not going
to put him in there.
No, Ben, l'm not.
You are his commanding officer.
l hold you responsible
for his actions.
l'm putting you in there.
Wait a minute.
No signs of resistance.
None of the on-board weapons
has been fired.
But the logs have been erased.
Someone else
must have been here.
Maybe Sisko and
O'Brien beamed off
before the ship was boarded.
But then why would somebody
send the runabout off at warp?
Why wouldn't they just
keep it or destroy it?
l think they were
trying to destroy it.
How can you tell?
The hull's been exposed
to high temperatures
and intense gamma radiation.
lf we retrace the
Rio Grande's course
it takes us right back to...
An F-type star.
Orellius Minor.
There's only one way
the ship could be coming
straight from Orellius Minor
and that's if someone
tried to destroy the ship
by flying it into the star.
And missed.
lf the trajectory
were slightly off
the star's gravity flux
would have deflected it
in a new direction.
Computer, send a tractor beam
to the Orinoco.
Prepare for a warp tow.
With a little luck
we'll be able to find
the warp signature
the engines left
when they were fired up.
Tractor beam in place.
Course laid in
for the Orellius system.
Engaging warp engines.
Please.
This is painful for me, too.
l want so much to give you water
to let you lie down
to sleep, but l can't.
Not without your help.
l know it's too difficult
to speak right now.
Just rest.
Change doesn't come
easy to you, Ben.
l realize it.
Believe me, l'm not expecting
some sudden,
miraculous conversion.
Change will come by itself,
if you're open to it.
But you do have to show us
that you're open to it.
A good start would be
to get rid of the uniform.
l'll leave you these clothes.
Once you've changed,
you can have this water.
Join us, Ben.
Miles.
What are you doing here?
l need your help, Joseph.
With what?
There's nothing l can do,
so please, don't ask me.
l've got to try to track down
where that duonetic field
is coming from.
We told you, there
are astatine deposits.
That's not what's causing it.
lf it were, l'd have
that transmitter running
and we'd all be out of here
already.
lt's got to be something else.
And l think l figured a way
to get me to the source of it.
And you want me to look the
other way while you leave.
She'd put you in the box,
wouldn't she?
Then do me a favor.
Look down at that hematite
deposit l just discovered.
Miles...
l can do it
so it won't hurt at all.
l owe you one, my friend.
Well, you finally got one of us
out of our uniform.
Come on, move it.
Where's Alixus?
Get her out here.
Get him some water!
Do you know why this phaser
is working now?
Because l shut down
the duonetic field
that was stopping it
from working.
An artificially created
duonetic field.
Sisko to Rio Grande.
Computer, respond.
Your ship is no longer
in orbit, Ben.
l destroyed it.
l assume that means you control
the duonetic field.
l helped invent it.
You'd be surprised
how many scientists
are sympathetic
to my philosophies.
Then it was no accident
we developed life-support
problems near this planet.
No, we were always
on our way here, Joseph.
l chose it months in advance.
lt was far away
from any trade route
completely isolated.
lt was perfect for our...
ideal community.
l hoped when we landed
we would never leave here.
You lied to us.
You've been lying to us
for ten years.
Yes, but perhaps a lie can lead
to a more important truth.
Would any of you have learned
who you really are at the core
if you hadn't have come here?
Joseph, you would
have been a repairman
all of your life.
Cassandra, you would have
been a technical clerk
in some closed-in room.
And, Stephan, my friend
you probably would have
been in prison by now.
Look at yourselves!
Look at what you've become!
What you've achieved here
has redefined your potential--
the potential of man--
just as l knew it would.
You are the living proof.
What of the dead?
What of Meg and the others?
Only my son knows
how l have suffered
as l watched each of them die.
You were willing to let them die
for your theories.
You're going to have to answer
for what you've done.
l'm prepared to go with you.
Casualties were inevitable.
l had to accept that
from the start.
What if it were your son
who had been sick?
Would you let him die, too?
Yes.
For the sake of the community.
l did it all for the community.
Kira to Sisko.
Are you all right, Commander?
Everything is...
under control, Major.
Stand by to begin
multiple transports.
Acknowledged.
We have room for all of you
on the runabout.
lf you have anything
you want to bring with you
you ought to get it now.
Miles...
this is our home.
Whatever Alixus may be guilty of
she did give us our community.
l'm not sure if we'll
leave the device
on or off, now that
we know it's there.
And we'll have to decide
if we want to establish contact
with the outside world.
But Alixus is right.
We have found something here
that none of us is willing
to give up.
lt's time for those of us
who don't belong here
to leave, Ben.
Four to beam up, Major.
Come, come.