All right, Morn.
You know the rules.
No sleeping on the Promenade.
Go home.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
The risk is to you, Lieutenant.
l could probably think better
without your hand on my thigh.
Now, how did that get there?
So, uh, what's it going to be?
Confront, evade,
acquire, retreat...
Confront.
Yes!
Doesn't she ever lose?
Tell me, Lieutenant
how'd you get to be
so good at tongo?
Actually, it was Curzon
who played it all the time.
Well, that explains it.
lt's Curzon who's beating
us-- not this female.
This female happens
to be a better player
than Curzon ever was.
And a prettier one, too.
Maybe so, but l still
prefer a Ferengi female--
one who never wears clothes
never talks back
and never plays tongo!
ls that really how you
prefer your women--
naked and submissive?
You find such a lifestyle
appealing?
Ah, don't you wish?
l do, l really do.
All right.
The opening risk is
at five strips of latinum.
The purchase is at three
the sell is at eight.
Absolutely not.
This isn't the proper time!
l'm trying to concentrate.
l'm sorry, Brother.
lt's this insolent
young waiter's fault.
My apologies, Quark
but l really think
you should try this.
What is it?
A way to double
your beverage profits.
Taste it.
You see, just as l told you.
He immediately
reached for his drink.
So l did.
Amazing.
You don't even
realize you're thirsty.
What are they?
Gramilian sand peas.
They inhibit the secretion
of the salivary glands
while drying out
the tissues of the tongue.
lt works every time.
lf you replace
your complimentary
dishes of lokar beans
with Gramilian sand peas,
you won't be able
to fill your customers'
glasses fast enough.
What's your name again?
Pel.
So, what do you think
about my idea?
l think l agree with
the 59th Rule of Acquisition.
Free advice is seldom cheap.
True, but the 22nd Rule says
a wise man can hear
profit in the wind.
l see you know your Rules.
All 285 of them
and the various commentaries
on them, as well.
l don't plan on being
a waiter forever.
Good, then you're fired.
Shut up, Rom.
When it comes to business
my brother has the weak
little lobes of a female.
So, uh, what made you take
a job here at the station?
l wanted to learn
from the very best.
Uh-huh, which brings to mind
the 33rd Rule of Acquisition.
lt never hurts
to suck up to the boss.
What's that?
The Grand Nagus Zek's
personal subspace frequency.
l wonder what he wants.
Why do you look so surprised?
l told you l'd be back.
Uh, l've looked forward
to your return, Nagus.
Still the perfect
little toady, eh, Quark?
l try to be.
Then listen carefully.
The Ferengi expansion
into the Gamma Quadrant
is about to begin.
l'd like you to be
my chief negotiator.
Me?
That's right.
l'm offering you an opportunity
to make more profit
than you ever dreamed of.
All you have to do is earn it.
Can l interest you
in some Hupyrian beetle snuff?
l don't think so.
Major?
No, thank you.
Well, suit yourself.
More for me.
Little late, aren't we?
So you wanted
to see me, Commander?
l understand you're
planning to host
a business conference
here at the station.
Yes, with the Dosi,
a race from the Gamma Quadrant.
A very profitable
opportunity for all concerned
l might add.
Profitable for the Ferengi,
maybe.
Are you implying something,
Major?
Me?
Not at all, no.
The Ferengi reputation
speaks for itself.
A reputation for honesty
and decency and reliability.
You always know what to expect
when you do business
with the Ferengi.
Which is why, if you're smart
you don't do business
with the Ferengi.
l think you've made
your point, Major.
As misinformed and misguided
as it may be.
Besides, how we do business
is no concern of yours.
Except when you conduct
your business on this station.
ln other words, Zek,
Grand Nagus or no Grand Nagus
if we allow you to hold
your negotiations here
and we find out
you're cheating the Dosi
l'll see to it you never
set foot on this station again.
Did anyone ever tell you
your eyes shine
with the brilliance
of Kibberian fire diamonds?
Not that l recall.
Well, they do.
So, tell me, Major,
could Bajor use
50,000 kilos of brizeen nitrate?
Of course, we could.
With that much brizeen,
we could fertilize
the entire northern peninsula.
Well, l've recently
come into possession
of 50,000 kilos
of brizeen nitrate
and to show you how much
your cooperation means to me
l'll let you have
the entire shipment.
l'll still need your assurances
that the Dosi will
be fairly treated
while they're here.
You have my word.
Good.
Then, it's settled.
Now, let's see--
50,000 kilos at, uh,
25% of our usual price.
25% ? You just said
you were giving it to them.
Well, you're right, Commander.
We're all friends here.
So, l'll let you
have it at cost.
l have a better idea.
Why not consider the nitrate
as a gift
to the people of Bajor?
A gift?
That doesn't sound
very profitable.
lt depends.
On what?
On whether you want
to conduct business here or not.
Your negotiating skills
aren't bad for a hu-man.
Your nitrate will be
delivered promptly.
Anything else you need,
come see me personally.
Well, Quark, l've been involved
in some very profitable
opportunities in my time
but my lobes are telling me
that this may be
the most profitable opportunity
in Ferengi history.
lmagine that.
And part of those profits
will be mine.
Profit, fame, power--
as much as you want.
Tell me, uh, Nagus, what exactly
is this great opportunity?
l can sum it up in one word--
tulaberries.
Tulaberries?
Exactly.
Go on.
Well, they're the main
ingredient in tulaberry wine.
Your job will be to purchase
10,000 vats from the Dosi.
We're going
into the wine business?
Within a single year,
we'll have made tulaberry wine
the most popular drink
in their entire sector.
That's enough!
Oh, l like it--
very distinguished.
Tell me, Nagus--
how are tulaberries going to be
the most profitable opportunity
in Ferengi history?
Do l have to spell it out
for you?
lf you don't mind.
Tulaberries
will establish
a Ferengi presence
inside the Gamma Quadrant.
And once we get our foot
in the door
they'll never get it out.
Yes, l see!
Tulaberries, Quark, tulaberries.
Tulaberries.
l wonder what they taste like.
Who cares what they taste like?
They're an opportunity
to get a Ferengi foot
in the Gamma Quadrant door.
And it'll be your foot, Brother.
l'm so proud.
l'm going to make history, Rom
and l'm going to be rich.
And l have the Grand Nagus
to thank for it.
He must really like me.
Just remember one thing--
the bigger the smile,
the sharper the knife.
48th Rule of Acquisition.
He has some nerve.
l warned you about that fellow.
Pel, do you mind telling me
what you meant just now?
Did you ever think
about why the Nagus
has put you in charge
of such a lucrative opportunity?
lsn't it obvious?
He knows l have
the lobes for business.
That's only part of it.
l refuse to stand here
and allow my brother
to be insulted.
You're fired.
Shut up!
Go on.
lf the negotiations
are profitable
then the Nagus becomes
the greatest hero ever
but if they fail
he's going to need
someone to take the blame.
You mean me?
All l'm saying is, be careful.
l never heard
such ridiculous lies.
He's just jealous
of your success, Brother.
No, he's right.
lf something goes wrong,
it'll be my fault.
Then you're going
to need help, Brother.
Yes!
Someone to serve
as your consultant
during negotiations.
Yes!
Someone like me.
No.
Uh, l've been thinking
about what you just said
and, uh, l probably
could use some help
during these negotiations.
l accept.
Good.
Then we're partners.
Not quite--
l don't need a partner.
l need an assistant.
All right, but l get 25%
of everything you make.
Fifteen.
Twenty.
Done.
But, Brother,
what can l do to help?
You want to help?
Table six is waiting.
How do l look?
Nervous.
Who, me?
What have l got
to be nervous about?
Yeah, it's Zek
who should be nervous--
with Quark here
as his chief negotiator.
lf you ever do that again...
Do what?
lf you ever do that again
l'll stick those 50,000 kilos
of brizeen right up your...
Here they come!
Don't worry,
just a minor disagreement.
So, uh, can l get anyone
something to eat?
All right.
Um, in that case,
let's go over our offer.
As you know, the Ferengi
are interested in purchasing
10,000 vats
of tulaberry wine.
ln exchange,
the Dosi will receive
what l consider to be
a very fair trade package.
There are some very interesting
items on that list--
a subspace field modulator
uh, some optical
data processors...
We'll give you 5,000 vats.
l'm afraid that won't be enough.
Um, we're looking to establish
a vast distribution network
in the Gamma Quadrant.
We'll need at least 10,000 vats.
l'm offering you 5,000 vats.
l suggest you take it.
The Nagus will never agree.
This is a waste of time.
We should be talking
directly to Zek.
l know we should
be talking to Zek.
Then why do you bother talking
to this insignificance?
Now, see what you've done?
What?
You've made me look foolish.
l didn't mean to.
Then bring us Zek.
The Nagus has asked
Quark to represent him
during these negotiations.
Are you implying
that Zek is too important
to negotiate with us?!
We never meant to imply
anything of the sort.
Because, if we kill you
Zek will have to talk to us.
You want to do business
with the Ferengi
you talk to Quark.
So how about it?
Do we say 10,000 vats?
We'll think about it.
Can l help you?
What is it?
lt's beautiful.
lt's latinum.
Excuse me,
l really can't accept this.
Did Zek really think
this was going
to get him anywhere?
Probably not.
But it doesn't stop
a Ferengi from trying.
You sound like you
admire them for it.
l suppose, in a way, l do.
l don't understand your attitude
about the Ferengi.
That's because you don't
socialize with them
the way l do.
Looking back
over seven lifetimes
l can't think of a single
race l've enjoyed more.
Did anyone ever tell you
you have very strange taste?
l admit, they place
too much emphasis on profit
and their behavior towards
women is somewhat primitive...
They're greedy, misogynistic,
untrustworthy little trolls
and l wouldn't turn my back
on one of them for a second.
Neither would l.
But once you accept that
you'll find
they can be a lot of fun.
Evade.
Retreat.
Acquire.
Confront.
Did l say ''acquire''?
l meant ''evade.''
You said ''acquire.''
Well, l meant ''evade''!
Why don't we just
play the round over?
That sounds fair.
Who asked you?
And shouldn't you
be plotting strategy
for tomorrow's negotiations?
Believe me, Nagus
l've thought of nothing
else all evening.
That must be why
you're losing so badly.
And l think, by tomorrow,
we should have an agreement.
Well, l've been thinking, too
and 10,000 vats
of tulaberry wine aren't enough.
Tell them we want 100,000.
100,000?
But l'm not sure they'll even
agree to sell us 10,000.
100,000 vats would mean
more profit for them and for us.
Now, do as l say!
Or l'm going to take over
the negotiations myself.
l think raising the stakes
is a brilliant idea.
You do?
lt'll show the Gamma Quadrant
we mean business.
No wonder Quark says
you're a genius.
Oh, he says that, does he?
All the time.
That's very touching.
Now bring me
some fresh tube grubs.
These are losing their crunch.
Right away.
So, l believe the next challenge
goes to you.
l think l'll pass on this round.
Such loyalty must be expensive.
You can't buy
that kind of loyalty.
You can where l come from.
ls the Nagus always
this impatient?
He wants results
and he expects me to get them.
But he's not making
my job any easier.
100,000 vats--
that's a lot of tulaberries.
You'll get them.
How can you be so sure?
Because you're good
and with me helping you,
you're even better.
Why are you being so nice to me?
For 20% of your profits.
Why else?
Fair enough.
Quark, where are my grubs?
Coming.
Mmm. Now this is
what l call fresh.
l didn't know the Replimat
had a Ferengi menu.
lt doesn't.
l like to try new things.
That's unusual for a Ferengi.
l never heard of a Trill
who could play tongo.
l guess that makes
us both unusual.
You know, l was impressed
by your show of loyalty
to Quark last night.
He deserves it.
That's not the point.
Any other Ferengi would've let
Zek pick him to pieces.
But you're not like
any other Ferengi l've ever met.
Quark really likes you.
He talks about you all the time.
You know he once convinced me
to go up to a holosuite
with him?
Turns out, he recreated
the bedroom l slept in
as a child.
He overheard me
describing it to Kira.
Of course, most of the details
were wrong
but it was
a very sweet gesture--
up until he tried to kiss me.
That sounds like Quark.
l don't care what anybody says.
l love him.
So do l.
You really do, don't you?
What?
Love Quark.
Don't bother trying to deny it.
l've seen the way
you look at him.
Please, keep your voice down.
Does he know?
He doesn't even know
l'm a female.
You're a woman?
Please lower your voice.
Please.
l knew there was something
different about you.
But l've never met
a Ferengi woman before.
You probably never will again.
On my world, women aren't
allowed leave the house
or wear clothes,
or learn to read.
And you wanted more.
Why not?
l'm as smart as any man.
So l made myself a pair
of synthetic lobes
and became one.
Why come here?
To acquire profit, of course.
There's only one thing
l wasn't counting on.
Falling in love with Quark.
What do you think l should do?
l don't know.
But l do know there's
more to life than profit.
Pel, it's time!
We don't want to keep
the Dosi waiting.
Hurry!
Okay, now, l think our best...
Excuse me.
Ah, Major.
Did that shipment of brizeen
nitrate arrive on time?
Yes, it did.
Good.
And here you are to thank me.
Have a seat.
Actually, l just stopped by
to return this.
Why, is something
wrong with it?
No, it's lovely,
l just can't accept it.
Then l suppose
a night of wild,
passionate romance
is out of the question?
That's right.
Just thought l'd ask.
Dax must be crazy.
Nice view, isn't it?
Don't tell me the negotiations
are already over.
That's fast work, Quark.
Now, let's see the contract.
There is no contract.
No contract?
But you offered to buy
100,000 vats, didn't you?
Yes.
And?
And that's when they left.
The room?
-The station.
-What?
l begged them to stay.
This is a catastrophe,
a complete catastrophe.
This was your big chance, Quark,
and you blew it!
You may have seriously harmed
future Ferengi opportunities
in the Gamma Quadrant!
Hold on a minute.
We said we're going
to get you the tulaberries
and that's exactly
what we're going to do.
We are?
How?
We're going to travel
to the Gamma Quadrant,
find the Dosi
and get them
to sign the contract.
And how do you plan
to get there?
We'll take your ship.
My ship?
Oh, and l suppose
you expect Maihar'du
to pilot it for you.
We don't need Maihar'du.
l can pilot the ship myself.
lt's up to you, Nagus.
Do you want
those tulaberries or not?
All right.
You can use my ship,
but l'm warning you, Quark--
either you get the Dosi
to sign that contract
or you'll be tending
that worthless little bar
for the rest of your life!
l've waited my whole life
for an opportunity like this.
So have l.
So far, it hasn't turned out
quite the way l planned.
lt's not over yet.
l still don't understand
why the Nagus
is suddenly insisting
on 100,000 vats.
Neither do l.
You don't think
he's purposely trying
to sabotage the negotiation?
Why would he?
l have no idea.
Hmm. One thing's for certain--
he knows more
than he's letting on.
About what?
Everything--
the tulaberries, the Dosi
even the Gamma Quadrant.
Well, if you ever figure out
what he's up to,
make sure you tell me.
Don't worry, l will.
So far, the only thing
l've done right
is pick you as my consultant.
l'm glad you feel that way.
Now, if we can only
make some profit.
Quark, there's something
you should know.
Oh, you're too late.
l already know
what you're going to say.
You do?
lt's no secret.
lt's not?
l admit you've been
a great help to me
but you agreed to a 20%
share of the profits
and that's all
you're going to get.
l see.
Never place friendship
above profit.
21st Rule of Acquisition.
l'm glad you agree.
Hmm.
Go, just go!
Go!
Oh...
Feeling a little
overwhelmed, are we?
l'm glad someone notices.
When's Quark due back?
Oh, how should l know?
He never tells me anything.
He doesn't even bother
to insult me anymore.
Go, go.
lt's Pel, that,
that flabby-eared interloper.
He's stealing
my brother's affections.
Hmm, you're better off.
But he's my brother!
Would you let someone
steal your brother?
l don't have a brother.
Not that l know of, anyway.
But if you did.
Well, l suppose
if l did have a brother
even one as worthless
as Quark
l wouldn't let anyone
come between us.
There must be something here
l could use against him.
l've got controlling interest
so l want to supervise
all operations.
That's ridiculous.
Well, then find another partner.
Let's not be hasty.
l said, no!
Are you enjoying yourselves,
little Ferengi?
How could we not?
Tell us, Z yree--
what is this place?
This-- this is where
opportunities are made.
Really? l thought it
was some kind of party.
Then you thought wrong.
This is all about profit.
And like the Ferengi
the Dosi are very serious
when it comes to profit.
You, take him away.
Very serious.
Look who finally showed up.
lt's about time.
Where are you going?
To get serious about profit.
Hey, watch it!
Oh... it's you, Ferengi.
Aren't you on the wrong
side of the wormhole?
lt certainly feels that way.
Fortunately, all l need
is your thumbscan
on this very lucrative contract
and l can go home.
You had your chance.
Go away!
Not until we finish
our discussion.
You... are starting
to annoy me.
Sorry.
l should have killed you
back on that station.
But you didn't because
deep down inside
you recognize a good opportunity
when you see one.
Just put your thumbscan here.
All right, you can
have the 10,000 vats.
100,000.
l told you before
that's impossible!
100,000 and l'm not leaving
till l get it.
Fine.
Then stay.
Wouldn't we be more comfortable
sleeping on the ship?
No, l want to be right here
in case lnglatu
changes his mind.
Don't worry, l don't snore.
Wait!
What is it?
The mattress.
What about it?
lt looks lumpy.
Actually, it's very comfortable.
l can't sleep
on a lumpy mattress.
Well, you're in luck, there's
not a lump to be found.
Try it for yourself.
What side do you want?
What are you doing?
Getting undressed.
What does it look like?
You're not going to sleep,
are you?
Why not? l'm tired.
Shouldn't we be discussing
rules of strategy?
There's nothing to discuss.
But you know
what the 103rd Rule
of Acquisition says.
Not offhand.
Sleep can interfere...
And l don't care, either!
Wait!
What is it now?
First a toast.
To what?
To, uh, profit, of course.
Of course.
ls it warm in here?
lt must be the wine.
l hope so.
l was really impressed
with the way
you handled lnglatu.
l was good, wasn't l?
Now let's get to bed.
Wait!
The look on his face
when you knocked
over that barrel.
That was risky.
The riskier the road,
the greater the profit.
62nd Rule.
That's right.
You really know your Rules.
And you have a very nice smile.
l do?
Oh, Quark, l have something
l have to tell you.
l'm not interrupting anything,
am l?
No, definitely not!
Are you sure?
Positive!
l'll come back tomorrow.
Wait!
No, wait!
This is all a silly
misunderstanding.
But you seem to be... busy.
Busy?
Don't be ridiculous.
We can't wait to hear
what you have to say.
Besides, we could use
the company.
Uh, isn't that right?
Absolutely.
All right, then.
Let me give you some advice--
lnglatu will never
sell you 100,000 vats
of tulaberry wine, not
because he doesn't want to
but because he can't.
lf he can't, who can? You?
l wish l could, but there aren't
that many vats
on the entire planet.
Then we're finished.
Not necessarily.
lf you really want
100,000 vats of tulaberry wine
l can put you in touch
with the right people.
For a price, of course.
Of course.
l always said you were
my favorite Dosi.
Now, um, who do we have to see?
The Karemma.
Who's the Karemma?
An important power
in the Dominion.
The Dominion, what's that?
Let's just say,
if you want to do business
in the Gamma Quadrant
you have to do business
with the Dominion.
''The most profitable opportunity
in Ferengi history''--
that's what Zek called it
but he didn't mean tulaberries,
no.
He meant the Dominion.
That's why he sabotaged
negotiations.
He never wanted to do
business with the Dosi
he just wanted to use them
to get
to a more important member
of the Dominion!
Quark, we need to talk.
We are talking.
Don't you want to know
why l kissed you?
You never kissed me.
Yes, l did.
No, you didn't
and l don't want
to discuss it anymore.
Let's just concentrate
on the Dominion.
l only wish Z yree
would have told us more.
Maybe it's
some planetary alliance
or trading consortium.
Whatever it is, it's important
and l want a piece of it.
Quark, l'm very disappointed.
l really wanted
those tulaberries.
You and l both know my trip
had nothing to do
with tulaberries.
lt didn't?
l must speak with you, Brother.
Can't you see l'm busy?
Does the word ''Dominion''
mean anything to you?
What have you found out?
You first.
Please, Brother, it's urgent.
Not now!
l'm waiting.
Well, most of my information
consists
of little more
than hints and whispers
but it's enough to convince me
that whoever learns
the secret of the Dominion
whatever that may be,
will learn the secret
of the Gamma Quadrant.
Unfortunately, the Dosi
don't seem to know very much.
l was hoping they'd lead
us to someone who does.
What would such information
be worth to you?
A lot.
What if l told you
l could arrange a meeting
between you and a powerful
member of the Dominion?
lf you can do that,
l'll see to it
that you earn a percentage
of every Ferengi opportunity
in the Gamma Quadrant.
Ah...
that's a lot of latinum.
Give me... a name.
-The Karemma.
l always knew you had
the lobes for business.
Now may l speak with you,
Brother?
All right, but make it quick.
Easy, now.
That's quite a bump
you've got there.
Where's Rom?
Right here, Brother.
Luckily, there
doesn't seem to be
any serious damage.
Uh, if you don't mind
l'd like to rest here
for a few minutes.
Of course.
l'll be in the other room
if you need me.
Thank you, Doctor.
You haven't told anybody,
have you?
You mean about Pel?
Quiet.
l haven't breathed a word.
l thought it'd be best
if you told Zek yourself.
Nobody's going to tell Zek
anything, is that clear?
But she's a female...
Not so loud.
Who wears clothes and is
trying to earn profit.
Why, she even quotes
from the sacred Rules
of Acquisition.
Such a female must be
severely punished.
l know that.
Then we'll stop her.
No.
You're scaring me, Brother.
Could it be you have
feelings for this woman?
Of course not.
Don't you see?
lf Zek learns that l've
been deceived by a female
l'd be ruined.
He'd never trust me again.
But if you don't tell
him and he finds out
you're certain to be ruined.
You have to tell him, or l will.
Let me go.
l have to save you
from yourself.
Forget about me.
What about the bar?
The bar?
You still want it, don't you?
Don't you?
Who needs the bar
when l can have
the Gamma Quadrant?
l'll transfer
ownership immediately
but only on one condition--
that you never mention the truth
about Pel to anyone.
Pel?
W-W-What about him?
Yeah.
Come.
Where are your lobes?
Over there.
Well, put them on
before somebody sees you.
No one's going to see me.
Put them on.
Now.
And wrap yourself up.
Have you finished packing?
Am l going somewhere?
As far away from this station
as possible.
But you need me, Quark.
l'm the only one you can trust.
Not anymore.
Well, what did you expect?
l mean, look at you.
You're wearing clothes.
ls that a crime?
As a matter of fact, it is.
Look, it's just too risky
for you to stay here.
And you can take this with you.
What is it?
Ten bars of latinum.
To help you start a new life.
lf you're going
to pretend you're a man
act like one.
Take the profit.
This is not about profit anymore
it's about love!
Oh, spoken like a true female.
l love you, Quark
and l know you care
about me, too.
Admit it!
What difference
does it make if l do?
You'd never be happy
being a Ferengi wife.
Then come with me
to the Gamma Quadrant.
No one there cares if
l wear clothes or not.
l'd care.
Then l guess
l'd better start packing.
l guess so.
Mmm... mmm... mmm.
Mmm... mmm...
Mmm!
Mmm.
These flaked blood fleas
are surprisingly succulent.
Mm-hmm, you really should
try them, Brother-- mmm...
l'm not feeling
particularly hungry.
Let me guess.
Too busy thinking
about how to spend
all that latinum
we're going to earn?
Well, l don't blame you.
Come.
l thought you said
she left the station!
l thought she did.
l hope you don't mind, Quark
but l couldn't leave without
saying good-bye to the Nagus.
l'm glad you stopped by.
l know how much
you helped Quark
during the negotiations.
l predict a big future
for you, Pel.
You certainly have
the lobes for it.
So, you like my lobes?
Pel...
Yes, l do.
Good, then you can have them!
No!
lt's a female!
Does this mean
l don't get the bar?
Rom... out.
Quark, this is outrageous!
Now what's going on here?
l-l-l...
Leave him out of this!
You dare give me orders?
You knew about this all along,
didn't you?
l...
So tell me more
about my big future.
You have no future.
l'll see to it that you spend
the rest of your life in prison.
No.
Let me remind you
that taking business advice
from a female
is a violation of Ferengi law.
l didn't know she was a female.
Stupidity is no excuse.
Now, one more word out of you
and you are going
to share her cell.
Then, you better make sure
it's big enough for three.
Are you threatening me?
l wonder
what your associates will say
when l tell them you allowed
a female to represent you
in a business negotiation.
l didn't know
she was a female.
Stupidity is no excuse.
l see your point.
lt seems that Pel's identity
will have to remain
our little secret
but it's going to cost you.
My Gamma Quadrant profits.
l've always said you were
a bright fellow, Quark.
Shame on you!
l hope you're satisfied.
l'm sorry...
but it's time you learned
that when it comes
to accumulating profit
women are as capable as men.
Well, do me a favor
and don't tell anybody else.
l should go.
l've booked passage
on an Andorian transport.
You could come with me.
l can't.
l know.
Well, then, l guess
if l can't have you
l'll take those ten bars
of latinum after all.
So, Lieutenant...
you ready for another
night of tongo?
Haven't you lost enough
for one day?
l don't know
what you're talking about.
l'm talking about Pel.
She came by to see me
before she left.
l'm going to miss her.
So are you.
You really think l'd let anyone
come between us?
Nice try, Quark
but l know you better than that.