l'm not what a lot of people
think.
l mean, if you're a dabo girl
you know, you get a reputation.
Miss Sarda, why don't you
tell me exactly what happened.
When did you start
to have trouble with Quark?
About five minutes
after l got off the ship.
He immediately made
sexual advances?
He said it was part of the job.
And what did you say?
l told him l'd wear the costume
and entertain the gamblers
but to keep his Ferengi
knuckles to himself.
That didn't stop him?
No. He said again that
it was part of the job.
He showed me
my employment agreement.
See, there it is
in the Ferengi print--
page 21, subsection D,
paragraph 12.
You're telling me the contract
you signed requires you to...
l guess l should have
read it more carefully.
l'm not a legal expert,
Commander.
l'm not a legal expert either,
but l can assure you
after l talk to Quark
he won't hold you or anyone else
to this provision concerning...
Commander, sensors
are picking up
elevated neutrino readings.
Something's coming
through the wormhole.
Excuse me.
Thank you, Commander.
Are any of the transports
due back?
Not according to our logs.
Put us on Yellow Alert.
lt doesn't match anything
in Starfleet files.
l'm getting readings
of a massive energy flux.
lt could be damaged.
Sensors indicate a single
humanoid life-form on board.
Hail it.
Aye, sir.
Hail acknowledged.
Response coming in.
On screen.
Welcome to the Alpha Quadrant.
l'm Commander Benjamin Sisko
of the United Federation
of Planets.
Alpha Quadrant?
You've passed through a wormhole
into a new part of the galaxy.
l saw a small ship disappear.
l followed it.
That was one
of our patrol vessels.
You've traveled
almost 90,000 light years.
What planet do you come from?
How long does it last,
this anomaly?
lt's stable.
You can return
whenever you want to.
ln the meantime,
you're welcome to dock here
and we'll try
to answer all your questions.
No. No time.
lnertial stress is overloading
his structural capacity.
Prepare to transport him
off his ship.
l will not abandon my vessel.
Sir, your ship
is in danger of...
l will not leave!
We can use a tractor beam
to tow him in.
The beam's graviton field
should shore up
the structural integrity.
Do it.
Cut your engines.
Why?
So l can save your ship, friend.
We'll bring you in
try to fix you up
as good as new.
Good.
Engaging tractor beam.
Steady, now.
You feel the graviton field
taking hold?
Yes.
You'll be fine now.
Just relax and enjoy the ride.
l think we might want to skip
formal first-contact
procedures for now.
Agreed.
Why don't you meet him
by yourself
at the airlock, Mr. O'Brien?
He might find that
a little less intimidating.
Aye, sir.
And, if you can...
find out
what he's so nervous about.
Aye, sir.
O'Brien to Ops.
Go ahead, Chief.
Sure you didn't
beam this fellow out
when l wasn't looking?
Negative.
He's not in here.
Sensors say
he's still on board, Chief.
Friend... if you're in here
you've got nothing
to worry about from me.
Understand?
l'm just going to take
a look at your ship
see what the problem is, okay?
And just to let you know,
l'm an engineer.
l know a little bit about ships.
Well, more than a little,
actually.
Though l'll tell you
l've never seen anything
close to this.
All right, then.
ls this some sort
of plasma injector?
Okay, then...
then that must be an off-axis
field controller over there.
Uh-huh.
The coladrium flow
has been damaged.
You can't go sneaking up
on someone like that, friend.
lt's an Alpha Quadrant rule.
Can it be repaired?
Well, that all depends.
Depends?
On what exactly
a coladrium flow is.
On my world, it would be simple.
With proper materials,
l could do it myself.
Hang on.
l didn't say we
couldn't figure it out.
You're just going to have
to teach me as we go.
l'm sure that we can...
l have no time.
l know.
Everyone's
in a hurry these days.
We'll have you on your way
as soon as it's
humanly possible.
That's me, by the way--
human species.
Name's O'Brien.
Oh Brien.
Miles O'Brien,
Chief of Operations.
How about you?
l am Tosk.
That's your name
or your species?
l am Tosk.
Oh.
Tosk it is.
Come on.
There's nothing to be
afraid of out there.
We've got to wait for your
reactor to cool down anyway
before we can
do anything else.
Come on.
l've got work to do.
So, what happened
to you, anyway?
Looks like you took
some sort of a shock
to your hull.
The passage through
the anomaly was very rough.
Yeah, sure.
The wormhole can
shake you up, all right.
Security sensor.
Screens for weapons.
lt's just picking up my phaser.
You're fine.
You wear a weapon.
Defensive purposes only.
lt may not seem hospitable
but when you go into an alien
ship for the first time
you never know
what might be in there.
You may even find someone
who can make
himself invisible.
You know what l mean?
l understand.
A health center?
Yeah. That's Dr. Bashir.
He looks after
our medical problems.
How many live here?
Well, 300, more or less.
What is its purpose?
Purpose?
Defense?
Surveillance?
Well, sometimes,
when l walk along here
l feel like we're
the flea market
to the sector.
But l guess our real job
is to keep an eye
on the wormhole.
There's traffic going in
and out all the time now.
Many ships dock here.
Five or six a week.
We sometimes
have a whole convoy
on its way
through the wormhole.
But you have the honor
of being the first visitor
from the other side.
Others will detect ships
from your quadrant, as l did
and follow them here.
We hope so.
Our mission as
Starfleet officers
is to seek out new life-forms
so we can learn
about each other.
Madam, l distinctly saw you
move your wager
to the green line
after the play was completed.
l will return your currency
but you will promptly
leave the establishment.
You are not welcome here.
Well, there are some things
to learn about us that can wait.
How about you?
You an explorer?
A scientist?
l am Tosk.
Right.
Computer, lights.
Oh, l wasn't the decorator.
l wish to begin work
on my ship.
Yes, well, we'll start
as soon as we can.
Now, why don't
you get some rest?
l require only 17 minutes
of sleep per rotation.
17? No kidding?
lf l don't get a good
eight hours a night
l'm not the same man.
Are you hungry?
Hungry?
You know, would you like to eat?
Take in sustenance.
Liquid nutrients are stored
in plasmic fibers
throughout my body.
Oh.
Well, this is the food
replicator over here
in case you change your mind.
We finally got it making
a pretty good bowl of oatmeal.
Just ask the computer
if you need anything else.
Oh Brien...
thank you.
As the Vulcans say,
we're here to serve.
Computer...
State request.
l wish to see a display
of this facility.
Specify exterior
or interior display.
lnterior.
lnterior display available
in 19 sections.
Specify requirements.
Show me where
the weapons are stored.
Habitat ring, level five,
section three.
Access restricted to security
clearance 7 and above.
lt's hard to say, sir.
You hate to prejudge anyone.
What are you thinking, Chief?
You know the old saying--
''A man who's always
looking over his shoulder
is waiting for trouble
to find him.''
You think he's on the run?
l'll tell you this--
he wasn't telling
the whole truth
about the damage to his ship.
lt sure wasn't caused
by the wormhole.
Somebody took a shot at him.
lt came in at a 45 degree angle
to the hull
sliced through
two propulsion systems.
l'll know more when l get
a better look at it.
Stay with him as much
as possible while he's here.
l'll tell Odo
to keep an eye on him, too.
Aye, sir.
No. The coladrium flows
through the arva nodes.
What are they?
Some kind of high energy
magnetic coils?
For fuel replenishment.
Fuel?
Oh, like a ramscoop.
Ramscoop?
Yeah, to capture stellar gasses
and convert them
into usable fuel.
Yes. The arva nodes convert
space matter into fuel.
Ah, gotcha.
Mm, piece of cake.
Piece of cake.
Ramscoop. Arva nodes.
''Piece of cake''-- it's
an old human expression.
lt means they'll be
easy to fix.
They will be easy to fix?
Sure. Yeah.
We'll just get my crew
to remove your arva nodes
then we'll take them over
to the replicator center
and make new ones.
Piece of cake.
How long?
Oh...
maybe a day or two.
We'll want to run some tests
after the replacement unit's in.
No. No time for that.
Hey, l let you
take that unit out
without proper testing
it breaks down, you blame me
next thing l know
my work has a bad reputation
in the Gamma Quadrant.
l would not blame you.
l was joking, Tosk.
l cannot tell... Oh Brien.
Sorry, it's in my nature.
And you're the most
natural straight man
l've met in ages.
Come on, while the fellas
are working here
l'll buy you a drink
and you can tell me
why you're in such a rush.
Dabo!
Nothing like this
exists on my world.
This is where we do
most of our R&R.
What is ''R&R''?
Rest and relaxation.
You know, down time.
When we're not working.
You sleep a full third
of your rotation.
You rest and relax
while you are awake.
Alpha Quadrant has
far too much down time.
My wife would laugh at that.
She's barely seen me
in the last three weeks.
We are very different
Tosk and Oh Brien.
l've noticed.
Hey, barkeep!
Don't call me ''barkeep.''
l'm not a barkeep.
l'm your host.
The proprietor.
A sympathetic ear
to the wretched souls
that pass through
these portals.
And a man who will exploit
any vice you may have.
Two synthales, barkeep.
l am sorry.
l have no vices
for you to exploit.
A challenge.
Tosk is our first guest
from the Gamma Quadrant, Quark.
l'd take him at his word.
Perhaps a short adventure
in a holosuite?
Holosuite?
A fantasy encounter with
danger, romance, thrills
created for
your personal entertainment
by the brothers Quark.
l have no use
for fantasy adventure.
l live the greatest adventure
one could ever desire.
Then l envy you, Mr. Tosk.
What are you talking
about, Tosk?
What is this adventure
you're on?
l cannot discuss it.
Oh, sure.
Of course.
Sounds like you've changed
your mind about him, Chief.
Not exactly.
l mean he's running from
something, that's for sure.
And he's in danger.
And he can't, or won't
talk about it.
People tell doctors things
they wouldn't tell anyone else.
lf you could get him to have
a routine medical
examination, maybe l...
The thing is, l kind
of like the guy.
l'm not even sure why.
ln a way, he's almost naive.
l guess anyone would be
in an alien environment
but l don't sense a threat
of criminal intent
or dishonesty about him.
l thought you said
he lied about
the damage to his ship.
He didn't exactly lie.
But he didn't exactly
tell the truth either.
He keeps the truth
pretty much to himself.
When do you think
his ship will be ready?
Tomorrow.
l don't see that we have
much of a choice.
We can't hold him.
lf he wants to tell
you the truth, fine.
lf not...
wish him well
and send him on his way.
Just what do you
think you're doing?
Computer, seal off
corridor 14-A, Habitat Level 5.
Seal confirmed.
Security to Habitat 514-A.
When you get tired
of bouncing
off force fields,
we can talk, all right?
l did nothing to you.
lt's that security junction
l'm curious about.
l must prepare.
For what?
l cannot discuss it.
l am Tosk.
l'm sure you are.
Why don't we go down
to my office
while your friend,
Chief O'Brien takes a look
to see just what you've
been doing in there?
Oh Brien?
Right.
l'm going to release
the force fields now.
l don't need a fight
from you, understand?
l will not fight you.
Good.
Computer, release
the security seals.
l cannot discuss it.
And l can't accept
that as an answer.
l did nothing to you.
You were tampering
with the security grid.
l consider that a threat.
l think he was trying
to shut out the lock-outs
to section three.
The weapons locker.
What were you going
to do with the weapons?
Are you wanted by authorities
somewhere
in the Gamma Quadrant?
''Wanted?''
Have you committed crimes?
Never. l am Tosk.
What does that mean?
ls that supposed
to explain all this?
lt is all l can say.
Tosk, don't you think
we deserve some answers?
What should l do with him?
Hold him for now.
We'll wait to see
if someone shows up
looking for him.
Enough of this craziness, Tosk.
Tell me, what were you doing?
Oh Brien...
you must let me out.
Tell me.
Allow me to die with honor.
Die?
Who would want to kill you,
Tosk?
Allow me to die with honor.
He's climbing the walls
like a trapped animal.
l'm sorry our jail cells
aren't to his liking.
Somehow, l feel responsible.
You do?
Yeah, well, l guess
l kind of adopted him.
l talked him into coming
on board.
You didn't talk him
into breaking
into the security system.
l just feel sorry for him.
Somehow, l don't think
he means us any harm.
What the hell is his secret?
Sensors are picking up
ionized L-band emissions.
The patterns match Tosk's ship.
Hail them. Maybe we'll
finally get a few answers.
No response.
Again, rotate frequencies.
lt's a modulated particle beam.
lt's scanning us.
Ready shields.
Not yet, Major.
Let them have a good look at us.
l'm reading phased
power fluctuations.
They may be readying
a transporter of some kind.
Now, Major.
Shields up.
Open all hailing channels.
Open.
This is Commander Benjamin Sisko
of the United...
They're bombarding us
with some kind of radiation
l've never seen before.
Very rapid magnetic
flux variations.
What the...?
They've reversed
the polarity of our shields.
l'm picking up
transporter locks.
They're beaming on board.
Location?
Promenade.
Security to the Promenade.
Kira and O'Brien with me.
Dax, you have Ops.
Ready phasers.
l'm Commander of this station.
Put down your weapons.
lncrease setting to level six.
lt's that Tosk they're after.
Maybe they have a right to him.
Nobody's abducting
a prisoner out of my brig
as long as l'm alive.
You may need this.
Thanks, Major.
You know l never use them.
l have Tosk...
...alive.
lt is over.
What a disappointment.
And after such
an entertaining beginning.
Entertaining?!
These aliens gave us
a great deal of resistance.
We wondered how you got
their cooperation
without violating
your oath of silence.
l told them nothing.
But to see you here...
caged...
helpless...
how could you allow this?
lt is a disgrace to all Tosk
and the most disappointing
hunt in memory.
You're saying that this
whole thing is a hunt
and Tosk is the prey?
You are right.
This Tosk is unworthy
of such a noble description.
For this dishonor,
you will endure
the greatest humiliation
Tosk can know--
to be captured
and brought home alive.
You will live out your existence
on public display
where children
can make fun of you
toss you scraps of food
which is more than you deserve.
Release him.
You've disrupted
life on this station
for the pleasure
of your ''hunt''?
l'm not inclined to take orders
from you.
Odo, watch the prisoner
while our guest and l
discuss this in private
unless you intend
to take him by force.
ln which case, l'm
prepared to give orders
to open fire on your ship.
Over this Tosk?!
Have you nothing similar
in your own society?
Centuries ago, people on my
world engaged in blood sports--
killing lower species
for pleasure.
A few cultures still do
but even they wouldn't consider
hunting a sentient being.
But he is sentient only because
we have made him sentient.
He has been bred for the hunt.
His entire reason
to exist is the hunt--
to make it as exciting,
as interesting as he can.
Obviously, you
do not comprehend.
l comprehend just fine.
l have no tolerance
for the abuse of any life-form.
Abuse?
We honor Tosk.
They are the symbol of all
that is noble and courageous.
They train and condition
themselves
all their lives for this event.
They're proud of their role
in our culture.
l can't judge what is right
and wrong for your world
but on this station...
ln the future,
passage through the anomaly
will be considered
out of bounds for the hunt.
Will that satisfy you?
Now, you will arrange
for release of the Tosk.
l've agreed to release him.
But, sir, Tosk is
an intelligent, living being.
lt's their custom, Chief.
Under the Prime Directive
we have no right to interfere.
What if Tosk were
to request asylum?
lf he asks for it.
All right,
l have a way out for you.
A way out...
of here?
Request asylum.
Asylum.
You ask for the protection
of the Federation.
You understand?
My Commander is willing
to protect you.
Oh Brien, l am Tosk.
l cannot hide here
behind the protection
of your Federation.
lt is against
everything l believe.
You'd rather go back
and live in a cage
on public display?
To stay would be
a greater dishonor.
l am Tosk
the hunted.
l live to outwit the hunters
for another day
to survive
until l die with honor.
But that will not be my fate.
But l will not deny
my existence as Tosk.
Thank you, Oh Brien...
but l cannot request asylum.
So far, l'm not impressed
with the tourist trade
from the Gamma Quadrant.
Not one of them has
bought a single drink.
Shut up, Quark.
More trouble
with the little woman.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing, nothing.
l just thought you
might want to talk.
There is nothing wrong
between my wife and l.
And if there were,
l sure as hell
wouldn't want to talk
to some barkeep about it.
Sorry. My mistake.
What?!
Your face gets very...
pink when it gets aggravated.
Much more so
than most other humans.
So stop aggravating me.
Oh, not me.
You came in the door this way.
Fine. You're right,
l'm aggravated.
l am a keen observer
of behavior.
You want to talk about it?
No.
Why not?
Because it wouldn't do
any good talking to you.
Try me.
Forget it.
lt's just the rules of the game.
Uh-huh.
Rules of the game.
Go on.
lt's a hunt.
Did you know that?
They're chasing Tosk in a hunt
and everybody's
playing by the rules.
They're playing by their rules
we're playing by ours
and he's caught in the middle.
'Course, l suppose
if the Ferengi don't
like the rules
they just change them.
Well, rules, rules
are always subject to...
Of course.
Change the rules.
Why didn't l think of that?
Thanks, barkeep.
So... what's bothering you
today?
Computer, access the power grid
to Security Checkpoint 4
on the Promenade.
That isn't necessary.
Our ritual requires it
when a Tosk is captured alive.
All right, let's go.
l'll escort the prisoner
to the transporter station.
This is a security matter.
This is a Starfleet matter.
Orders from Sisko.
We'll see about that.
Do not trouble yourself.
My ship will transport us.
No, sir,
that won't be necessary.
Good relations
with other cultures
is our highest priority.
Commander Sisko
wants to make sure
you understand we're sorry
we interfered with your hunt.
The least we can do is give you
an official escort
off the station.
lt's a token of goodwill
and respect in our society.
Very well.
Starfleet has no business
taking charge
of a prisoner transport.
Calm down, Constable,
what are you talking about?
l'm talking
about you ordering O'Brien
to escort Tosk off the station.
l didn't give him
any orders at all.
Sisko to O'Brien.
Mr. O'Brien,
report to Ops immediately.
This way.
Glass jaw.
Now l know
why you wear a helmet.
Up here!
The hunt has resumed.
Come on.
Your ship's ready.
Security reports a fight
in the Promenade. Here.
Apparently,
O'Brien set him loose.
l'm showing someone in an access
conduit above Quark's.
Two life-forms.
One's human.
They're heading out
toward the docking ring.
l'll seal off
the adjoining corridors.
They won't get far.
Constable...
there's no hurry.
Here.
Now you are Tosk
as well, Oh Brien.
The Cardies made these conduits
from two-meter thick
duranium composite.
l've never seen
a scanning device
that could penetrate it.
Ah!
Till now.
Come on, Tosk.
Around this next corner
and we're there.
No, he is mine.
No!
Go on.
What now?
The hunt...
goes on.
You wish to come?
Oh, no, no.
l don't think so.
One day as a Tosk
is enough for me
and l've got a wife and kid
that wouldn't fit too well
into this lifestyle.
Will your Federation
punish you for helping me?
Maybe. But if l know
my Commander...
Hell, those guys
wanted a hunt.
l just gave them one.
Go on.
You better get out of here
while you still can.
Oh Brien.
Die with honor...
Die with honor, Tosk.
Just what did happen
at that security
checkpoint, Chief?
The weapons' sensors
must have overloaded
on all his various gear, sir.
Must have?
Yes, sir.
''Must have,'' since
l increased their output
by about 200%.
So in effect,
you assaulted him--
our first contact
with a new species.
Yes, sir.
We've got dozens
of top-level officials
back at Starfleet Command
eagerly waiting to hear
about our encounter
with the first new life-forms
to come through the wormhole.
How do you suggest
l write up this report?
Well, sir, l'm not
one to say, but...
well, you know
these hunters
weren't any happier
than we were at having
to bring Tosk home.
lt seems to me,
in the interests
of mutual understanding
and future relations...
Save it.
You ignored your duty
to Starfleet.
You took off your combadge,
so you could ignore me.
You even ignored the Prime
Directive by interfering
with their damned hunt.
Another stunt like this
and your wife won't have
to complain
about the conditions
here anymore.
Do l make myself clear?
l understand.
l was surprised
by one thing, sir.
What's that?
Well, l knew l couldn't override
all the security seals
in the station
and l figured once you
and the Constable located us
well, it'd be over.
We'd find ourselves
locked behind
some force field somewhere.
l guess that one got by us.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Dismissed.