Nerys?
Vedek Bareil.
Wanna play?
Help me.
Please.
All right.
Who is it?
lt's Prylar Bek.
No, it's not.
lt's you.
Good morning.
l thought you'd sleep till noon.
Shh... you're supposed
to be relaxing.
Oh, l'm very relaxed.
Good.
How are you feeling
this morning?
Oh, miserable.
l wish you could
stay here longer.
All right, l will.
l'll stay a few more days.
You know you can't do that.
Why not?
Because in two days
you are going
to be elected kai.
Hmm?
Oh, that!
You know, there's no guarantee
l'm going to win.
Of course, you're going to win.
The people need you.
Are you...
going to vote for me?
Ho, ho!
ls that why you spent
the last three days here, huh?
To get my vote?
Well, l know you don't agree
with many of my views,
so l thought
a personal appearance
might sway your opinion.
l was going to vote
for Vedek Tolena.
But l might be persuaded
to change my mind.
Good.
Because your vote
is the only one
that matters to me.
l may not always agree
with your interpretations
of the prophecies
but l think you will make
a wonderful kai.
Besides, everyone knows
that you were Kai Opaka's
personal choice to succeed her.
l could never replace Opaka.
Bajor wouldn't have survived
the occupation without her.
Once you become kai
we'll never have
these times together.
Listen to me.
No matter how busy l become,
l will always have time for you.
lt won't be easy.
l didn't say it would be.
l'm not going to lose you,
Nerys.
l promise you that.
Remember now,
honor the Prophets
and they will always love you.
As l understand the sacred texts
the Prophets' love
is unconditional.
They ask nothing in return.
Thank you, Vedek Bareil,
for reminding us
how the sacred text can be
so easily misinterpreted.
Nothing pleases me more
than providing you
with an opposing viewpoint,
Vedek Winn.
Somehow you never
fail to do that.
l had no idea you
were on the station
but perhaps l shouldn't
be so surprised.
Oh, l wouldn't even
try to surprise you.
l understand you've
been keeping a close eye
on my activities
these last few weeks.
The eyes of all of Bajor
are focused on you, Bareil.
Why should l be any different?
After all, the common wisdom
is that you are destined
to be the next kai.
Was that a concession speech?
Hardly.
The choosing is still
two days away.
The Prophets may yet
surprise us all.
Remember that, Bareil.
l would hate for you to start
celebrating prematurely.
What brings you to the station,
Vedek Winn?
My child, if l thought
the Prophets
wanted you to know
the purpose of my visit
l would have informed you
of it in advance.
Well, now that l know
you're here, l'll be sure
to inform Constable Odo
to increase station security.
That won't be necessary.
l feel quite safe here.
No, it wasn't your safety
that concerned me.
Just what are you trying
to infer, child?
l'm sure Major Kira meant
no disrespect.
No, not at all.
l just want to avoid
the violence
that occurred
during your last visit.
My child, l know
you still hold me responsible
for the deplorable attempt
on Vedek Bareil's life
but l can only pray
that some day
you will be cured of
this unfortunate misconception.
Well, that's one prayer
that will never be answered.
What a pity, for both of us.
Ooh!
Oh! Excuse me.
Uh, excuse me.
Don't l know you?
You must be mistaken.
No, no, l've seen you before.
You're... Kubus, that's it.
Kubus Oak.
You worked for the Cardassians.
Out of my way!
Now, you wait a minute!
You're not going anywhere.
l know who you are,
and l know what you did!
You're a traitor!
This is Kubus Oak!
He's a traitor!
He worked for the Cardassians!
What's going on here?
See for yourself.
Secretary Kubus.
Last l heard, you were living
on Cardassia.
l decided it was time
to come home.
Welcome back.
You're under arrest.
The Prophets have spoken.
All blessings on the new Kai.
Blessings on the Kai.
May the Prophets guide you.
Kai Opaka.
Be at peace, my child.
You must be strong,
now more than ever.
Why did you leave us?
All is as the Prophets
will it to be
as you will learn.
Follow me.
Be careful, Bareil.
The path she walks
is a narrow one.
See that you don't stumble.
Heed her words.
But l don't deserve
to walk in your path.
You must.
lt is your destiny.
Prylar Bek?
Accept this gift
from the Prophets.
You must not refuse
their offering.
Take it, my child.
lts venom
will make you stronger.
There was quite a mob
gathering out there.
l had to call in extra security
to disperse it.
l never doubted your ability
to handle the situation, Odo.
You always were good
at your job.
l could say the same for you,
Secretary Kubus...
special liaison between
the Cardassian occupation forces
and their pawns
in the Bajoran government.
l served the only
recognized government
on Bajor during the occupation.
Recognized by the Cardassians.
lf it wasn't for us,
the situation on Bajor
would have been ten times
worse than it was.
Maybe, but l don't see
how you could know that
seeing that you spent nearly all
your time here on the station.
l remember Gul Dukat
telling me once
that you were
his favorite Bajoran.
Really? Well, l never could
stand that arrogant tyrant!
You hid your feelings well.
lt kept me alive.
Bajor is my home.
l never should have left it.
But you did...
and you're going to have
to live with that decision.
This is Major Kira
the highest-ranking Bajoran
on the station.
Then l suppose you're the one
l should be talking to.
Make it brief.
l don't enjoy
talking to collaborators.
l'm not asking you to like me.
l'm simply requesting that l be
allowed to return home.
Your request is denied.
l doubt if you have the
authority to make that decision.
The decision has
already been made.
ln the llvian Proclamation,
every Bajoran who was a member
of the Cardassian
occupational government
was sentenced to exile.
Your name was number four
on that list.
Personally, l think
you all got off too easy.
Major...
l'm an old man.
l don't have many years left.
What's the harm of letting me
live them out on Bajor?
When the Cardassians needed
a new group of Bajorans
to work in the mines
who approved those work orders?
The Bajoran government.
Whose signature was
on those authorization forms?
Mine.
And you had to know
that those authorizations
were death sentences.
Did you ever once refuse
to sign them?
No.
And that's why
you can never be allowed
to set foot on Bajor again.
Because, if you do,
it would dishonor
the memory of every person
you sentenced to death.
Vedek Winn.
What can l do for you?
Emissary...
it has recently come
to my attention
that there are
some on Bajor who believe
that my relationship with you
is not all it should be.
Really?
Personally, l find
such a perception,
however inaccurate
to be most distressing.
l suppose the question
we have to ask ourselves
is whether or not
that perception is inaccurate.
Don't tell me
that you yourself, Emissary
believe that you and l are...
how shall l put it?
Enemies?
At odds.
Well...
let's see.
How could l have come
to such a conclusion?
Maybe it has something
to do with the fact
that the last time
you were here at this station
you claimed that l was
a danger to Bajor;
that l was here
to destroy your people.
What l was really saying--
what l have always maintained--
is that you, Emissary, were
sent here by the Prophets
to challenge
our long-held beliefs.
Am l correct in assuming
that you no longer consider
the Federation to be
an enemy to Bajor?
Emissary, l admit
l had some concerns
about Bajor's application
for Federation membership
but now, l see
that the Federation's
presence here is essential
for our long-term
security and growth.
Then, you support the notion
of Bajor joining the Federation?
lf that is the will
of the Prophets
l would never oppose it.
l'm glad you said that.
And l would be grateful
if you would tell it
to the Bajoran people.
Nothing could make me happier
than to please you, Emissary.
Perhaps you and l could address
the Vedek Assembly together
so everyone can celebrate
our new friendship.
An excellent idea.
Perhaps sometime next week.
Why wait, Emissary?
l'm sure the Assembly would
grant us an immediate audience.
l'm sure they would.
Unfortunately, if we were
to appear together
in public before the choosing,
it might be misconstrued
as an endorsement of your bid
to become the kai.
Oh, l doubt that, Emissary.
lt's common knowledge
that you support Vedek Bareil
although l have been pleasantly
surprised that you haven't made
any public statement
to that effect.
The election of the kai
is strictly
an internal affair to Bajor.
As a Federation officer,
l would never interfere.
What an enlightened philosophy.
So then, it's agreed.
l'll be seeing you
sometime next week.
l look forward to it.
Odo to Major Kira.
This is Kira.
Sorry to disturb you, Major
but l thought you should know
that Secretary Kubus
about to leave for Bajor.
How can that be?
Vedek Winn has
granted him sanctuary.
l'll be right there.
Kira to Ops.
Go ahead.
Dax, has Winn's ship
left the station?
Not yet.
l was about to clear them
for departure.
Well, keep those docking clamps
locked on.
l don't want that ship going
anywhere until l say so.
Understood.
Tell me what happened.
Kubus requested a private
meeting with Vedek Winn.
They talked for ten minutes
after which, Winn asked
for the use of my computer.
She accessed some information
from the library system.
And?
And then she called
the provisional government
and informed them she was
granting Kubus sanctuary.
Do you know what she looked up?
l'm trying to find
that out right now.
Ah...
That's Prylar Bek.
Now, why would Winn
be interested
in another Bajoran collaborator?
l'm not sure.
But Bek and Kubus
did know each other.
Bek was the liaison
between the Cardassians
and the Vedek Assembly
at the same time
that Kubus was secretary
to the occupational government.
They spent a lot of time
together on the station.
Hold on a minute.
See if Winn accessed
any information
about the Kendra Valley
massacre.
You're right, she did.
Do you think Kubus told her
something new
about the massacre?
What else is there to know?
Kai Opaka's son and 42 other
Bajoran freedom fighters
were ambushed and killed,
because Bek gave the Cardassians
the location
of their encampment.
He made a full confession
in his suicide note.
Well, you were here then.
You must have read it.
Major Kira, may l speak
to you, please?
Of course.
l was told you were the one
who stopped
my ship from leaving.
Yes, l did.
You know, you're
the last person l would expect
to help a collaborator
like Kubus
unless, of course,
he has something you need.
My needs are no concern
of yours, child.
Now, l suggest
you allow my ship
to depart immediately.
Oh, you're free to leave
anytime you like.
Unfortunately, in light
of public feelings about Kubus
l can't allow
any ship with him on board
to leave the station
until it's undergone
a thorough security check.
To prevent sabotage.
And that includes
a molecular scan
for nanotechnology.
And how long
would such a scan take?
Oh, l'm no expert
but l'm sure it could
take days... even weeks.
Very well.
lt seems the Prophets
have decided
you will have a part
in this, after all.
ln exchange for sanctuary,
Kubus has agreed to provide
the name of the man
responsible for the massacre
at Kendra Valley.
Prylar Bek was responsible
for the massacre.
Everyone knows that.
Bek was a pawn,
an intermediary.
He killed himself
to prevent the discovery
of the real traitor.
The real traitor?
Bek's superior--
the person
who ordered him to reveal
the location of the rebel base
to the Cardassians--
the man who was truly
responsible for the massacre--
Vedek Bareil.
Do you really think l'm going
to let you get away with this?
You know, no one's
going to believe
the word of a convicted
traitor like Kubus.
l never said l believed him.
l'm only trying to protect
the spiritual life of Bajor.
Don't flatter yourself.
You're trying to grab power,
nothing more.
My child, do you want
to risk the consequences
of having a collaborator
as the next kai?
He is not a collaborator.
That's yet to be determined.
But if he is chosen
and turns out to be guilty
the ramifications for Bajor
would be catastrophic.
lt would shatter faith
in the authority of the kai
and without a strong kai,
Bajor cannot survive.
You can't condemn
Bareil without proof.
l don't intend to.
l was planning to conduct
a quiet investigation
when l return to Bajor
but l didn't know
whom to trust
with such
a delicate assignment--
until now.
You want me to do
your dirty work for you.
All l care about is the truth
and l believe the Prophets
have chosen you
to help me find it.
l'll find out the truth.
Don't worry about that.
But l want you to keep
Kubus' accusations
from becoming public
until l have a chance
to prove Bareil's innocence.
You have my word.
Let the Prophets be my witness.
But if you discover proof
that he's guilty...
Whatever l find out,
l will share with you.
Then it's decided.
Oh, and, child, one last thing.
l know you're
under a terrible strain
but if you're wise
you will never speak to me
with such disrespect again.
Were you aware at the time
that Prylar Bek was
a collaborator?
He wasn't a collaborator.
He was only a messenger
between the Cardassians
and the Vedek Assembly.
At the time, l could,
l could see
in the weeks
prior to the massacre
that something
was bothering him.
He was tense and nervous
and he was in
constant communication
with the Vedek Assembly.
Do you know who?
Not at the time
but the day after the incident
Vedek Bareil came
to visit him at the station.
Did you see them together?
l saw Bareil
enter Bek's quarters
which were in the same section
as mine.
He was in there
for a couple of hours
and at times
l could hear shouting
through the bulkhead.
Did you hear
what they were saying?
No, but l saw Bareil
when he left the station.
He was upset.
ln the morning,
Bek hanged himself.
This...
is all the evidence you have?
Well, isn't that enough?
Bek was obviously
working with Bareil
and when he realized
the enormity of what he'd done
he must have wanted to confess.
Bareil wouldn't allow it
so Bek took the only way out
he had.
That's a fascinating story,
but it is pure conjecture.
There have to be
a dozen explanations
for why Bareil
came to see Bek.
And it's up to you
to find out which of these
explanations is true.
What exactly is it
you're asking me, Nerys?
l guess l'm asking
whether or not
you came to the station
to see Bek that day.
l visited Bek, yes.
That hardly makes me
a collaborator.
l know that.
lt's Vedek Winn
who needs convincing.
Oh, poor Winn.
Her desire to become kai
has clouded her judgment.
l wouldn't take her so lightly,
if l were you.
She is determined to ruin you.
Believe me when l tell you
there's no reason to worry.
l had nothing to do
with the massacre
and Winn will never
be able to prove otherwise.
All right.
But... l still need to know
why you came to the station.
Bek was a deeply troubled man
seeking spiritual guidance.
His guilt at betraying
the Kendra Valley base
was overwhelming.
He called me for help.
l came as soon as l could.
l only wish l could have done
more for him.
What did he tell you
about the massacre?
Nerys, you must understand
he was a monk speaking
in confidence to his Vedek.
l cannot betray that trust.
l understand.
ls there anything else you think
l should know about Bek
about the massacre?
Nothing that will satisfy Winn.
All right.
l'll keep looking
but one way or another
l am going to prove to Winn
that you are innocent.
Thank you, Nerys.
Ha, just as l thought.
When the Cardassians left
they purged all records
of communication
between the station and Bajor.
Then we'll just have
to get the information
from the other end.
l'll establish a computer link
with the Bajoran
Central Archives.
That way, l can access the files
of the Vedek Assembly.
Are you all right?
l'm fine.
You don't seem fine.
lt's nothing.
Uh-huh.
lf you say so.
He says he's not guilty.
l know he's not guilty.
But you're afraid he's guilty.
l love him, Odo.
Really?
Well, l, uh...
What?
l was just wondering
when you were going
to figure that out.
You humanoids.
When it comes
to emotional attachments
you never see the obvious.
Ah, l'm into
the Vedek Assembly files.
Can you retrieve
the communication files
between the station
and the Assembly?
l'll need a time frame.
Uh, try the week leading up
to the Kendra massacre.
That's odd.
What?
All the communications records
between the Assembly members
and Bek for that week
have been sealed.
-Sealed? By who?
-lt doesn't say.
lt just indicates
a security seal.
ln the Assembly records?
Who has that kind of authority?
Only a Vedek.
One, two, three, four, five
six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Okay, okay.
Eleven...
Fine, 12, 13, 14.
And not a strip more.
l hate payday.
Whatever she told you,
l didn't do it.
Relax, Quark.
No one's accusing you
of anything.
Eh, the day's still young.
Don't be so defensive.
l can't help it.
Between the two of you
l'm developing
a persecution complex.
l'm sorry to hear that.
All right.
What's going on?
You want something from me,
don't you?
How did you guess?
lt's simple.
We've been here
more than a minute
and we haven't insulted him,
threatened him
or arrested him.
Exactly.
So, what is it?
And how much trouble
is it going to cause me?
No trouble at all.
We just need you to
bypass a security seal.
lsn't that illegal?
Oh, spare us.
Quark, this is important.
We need access to certain
communication files
in the Vedek Assembly records.
Perfect-- not only is it
illegal, it's sacrilegious.
l'm sure the Prophets
won't mind just this once.
Okay, but l'm going
to have to have
written authorization from you,
countersigned by Commander...
Just do it, Quark!
Sure, when things go wrong,
l take the fall!
Nothing is going to go wrong!
That's what you think!
But l happen to be
a firm believer
ln Rule of Acquisition
Number 285:
''No good deed
ever goes unpunished.''
You can access
the Vedek Assembly records
through the Bajoran
Central Archives.
Of course, l can
if l wanted to barge in
like some rank amateur.
This is going to take
a little while.
l'll let you know
when l'm done.
lt happened right about here.
Bek hanged himself in front
of dozens of witnesses.
Caused quite a stir.
At least he had the decency
to feel guilty
about what he'd done.
Strange.
Bek and l were
passing acquaintances
here on the station.
From what little
l knew about him
l always thought
he was a good man.
A good man does not betray
his own people.
The one thing
l've learned about humanoids
is that in extreme situations
even the best of you are capable
of doing terrible things.
Hey.
Hey, Odo.
The good news is
l broke through
the security seal.
The bad news is,
the file is empty.
All the messages
have been erased.
They're erased, all right.
ls there anything
you can do about it?
l could scan
the empty file for traces
of recurring data fragments.
There's always a faint residue
of the original data,
if you know where to look.
But to unscramble
those fragments
so they make
a coherent pattern
could take a while.
So, what you're telling me is
we're never going
to retrieve that information.
Well, not in time
to do you any good.
But hold on a second.
Let me see something.
l may not be able
to get you the data
but l might be able
to find out who erased it.
Their retinal scan
would have been noted
by the authorization
subroutine when they logged on.
But wouldn't the scans
have been erased, too?
Sure, but even a fragment
of the retinal scan
might be enough
to identify the user.
Here. l'll run a sweep
of the authorization subroutine
see if we can find out anything.
Okay.
These are
mathematical representations
of a fragment
of the retinal scan.
We can use these to reassemble
a portion of the original image.
Not bad.
Now we'll cross-reference this
with the Assembly's main archive
see if we can find out
who it is.
l think we've got something.
Blessings on Kai Bareil.
You.
l trusted you.
l needed you.
And you let me die.
You will be rewarded.
Accept this gift
from the Prophets.
May the Prophets
comfort you, my child.
May they comfort us all.
Come in.
Nerys.
Did you really believe
l wouldn't learn the truth?
The truth is not
always easy to recognize.
l recognize it now
and l don't like what l see.
Why did you do it?
Why did you erase
those transmission records?
Don't make me do this.
l don't have any choice.
Winn is waiting to hear from me.
Do you really want me
to tell her
that you ordered Bek
to give the Cardassians
the location
of that resistance base?
That you are responsible
for the deaths
of those 43 people?
That you killed Kai Opaka's son?
The Cardassians were determined
to eliminate all resistance
in the Kendra Valley.
lf someone hadn't told them
the location of that base
they would have wiped out
every village in the area.
That would have meant the death
of 1,200 innocent Bajorans.
l could not allow that.
There had to have been
another way.
l believed in you...
l defended you
and Winn was right all along.
And now she's going
to destroy you.
No.
l've destroyed myself.
What's our status?
Everything is under control.
You received
a subspace transmission
from Vedek Winn.
She seemed anxious
to talk to you.
Open a channel
to the Vedek Assembly.
Put it on monitor seven.
l might as well
get this over with.
l was wondering
when you'd contact me, child.
l was waiting to complete
my investigation.
l must congratulate you
on a job well done.
l knew the Prophets were right
in picking you to assist me.
You sound like you already know
what l'm going to tell you.
Oh, but l do.
Bareil has just made
a surprise announcement
to the Vedek Assembly.
He's withdrawn himself
from the choosing.
He no longer wishes
to be the next kai.
l know this is painful
for you, child
but you've done a great service
for all of Bajor.
Whoever is chosen
tomorrow as the new kai
will owe you
a debt of gratitude.
May the Prophets guide you.
Are you all right?
lt doesn't make sense.
Vedek Bareil is
an honorable man.
He wouldn't hide
from the consequences
of his actions
by covering them up.
l'm missing something.
Chief.
l need to get back into
the Vedek Assembly archives.
Yes, sir.
Kai Winn.
Your pagh is strong, my child.
Be at peace.
ln time, you will learn
l am not your enemy.
l hope that's true.
l know you do.
Oh, and tell Commander Sisko
l must postpone appearing
with him before the Assembly.
At least for now.
Nerys?
l didn't expect
to see you here.
You forgot to erase
the transit files.
l'm not sure l understand
what you mean.
Oh, you did a wonderful job
erasing the transmission reports
but you forgot
all about the transit files
the files that prove
you weren't a collaborator.
lt's over.
Let it rest.
The people have chosen Winn.
Only because you withdrew
and you didn't have to.
The transit reports clearly show
you were on a personal retreat
at the Dakeen Monastery
during the week
leading up to the massacre.
l checked the Dakeen
transmission reports.
You had contact with no one
except one transmission
after the massacre
ordering you back
to the Vedek Assembly.
That's enough.
No, it is not enough.
There is no way you ordered Bek
to reveal the location of
the Kendra Valley encampment.
You were covering up
for someone else.
Someone who meant more
to you than me.
More to you even
than becoming kai.
Please, Nerys, don't.
Why not?
lt's the truth, isn't it?
Who else meant that much to you?
lt had to be Kai Opaka.
Opaka knew where the resistance
cell was located...
because her son was a member.
She was the collaborator,
wasn't she?
She sacrificed her own son
to save 1,000 people.
l had to protect her.
So...
instead of you,
we have Winn to lead us.
lt is the will of the Prophets.
The question is...
where will she lead us?
Down paths she cannot
possibly imagine.
She's going to need
our help along the way
even if she doesn't
realize it yet.
What happens to us?
What do you want to happen?
Let's go pay our respects
to the new Kai.