And l've downloaded
the new docking procedure
checklist for Bay 6
into the Bay-Prod D-9 file.
That's the only bay
using the new criteria.
Got it.
And be sure to monitor
the power fluctuations
in the secondary fusion core.
lt's got some little kinks in
there l don't like the look of.
l will care for the
secondary fusion core
like it was my own child.
As soon as l get back,
l'm going to run
a full diagnostic,
to make sure there's no...
Chief! We are perfectly capable
of running this place
by ourselves for a week.
Well, if you have any problems
you can reach me on subspace...
Would you please go on vacation
and get out of our hair?
Miles.
Yeah?
Have a good time.
Oh, right.
Thanks, yeah.
l feel relaxed already.
ls he gone?
Finally.
Good. He's been driving me
crazy all day.
You'd think that l was...
Commander...
l forgot to tell you.
l added a new subroutine
to the environmental control
in the Habitat Ring...
Chief O'Brien.
Yes, sir?
You're on leave.
Please disembark this station.
Aye, sir.
lt's okay.
Boone!
O'Brien.
Miles O'Brien.
We served together
on the Rutledge.
Of course! O'Brien.
Oh, it's been a long time.
How are you doing?
l'm fine, just fine.
l work on this station now.
Chief Engineer.
ls that a fact?
Yeah. How long you been
out of Starfleet?
Oh, about eight years now.
l settled on Volon lll.
Well, that's
on the Cardassian side
of the Demilitarized Zone,
isn't it?
Yes. Well, the new treaty, it
really puts us in harm's way.
But l run a ladarium
mining sluice
so as long as the Cardassians
need ladarium
for their warp drives,
they leave me alone.
Well, after what we went
through in the border wars
l don't know
how you can live there.
You were there at Setlik lll.
That's what got me
out of Starfleet.
Really?
That's why l stayed in.
Listen, my wife
is waiting for me
and she hates it when l'm late,
and l always am.
l'm coming back
for another supply pickup
in a month or two.
Okay, let me know when.
O'Brien, Miles O'Brien.
We served together
on the Rutledge.
Miles?
Uh-huh?
Didn't you bring the holo-cam?
Was l supposed to?
You said you were going to.
Did l?
Last night, when we were
going over the list in bed.
Not me.
l was dead as soon as my head
hit the pillow.
You talked to me
for half an hour.
No, there must have been
someone else in bed with us.
What's this?
Oh, just some new
technical update manuals.
Our first vacation
in five years
and you brought
technical update manuals?
You know, maybe we should
have brought Molly with us.
Do you think she'll be okay
with the Petersons?
She likes the Petersons
more than she likes us.
She's fine.
We could swing back, pick up
the holo-cam and Molly
and still only lose
about half a day.
Or we could pick up
the holo-cam
when we get there.
How many did you bring?
What?
Tech update manuals?
Just a few.
Computer, play something
by... Minezaki.
Do these chairs recline?
l wish they did.
You're an engineer.
Do something about it.
l'll make it worth your while.
Mmm...
Vessel approaching.
Bearing 191 mark 6.
ldentify.
Cardassian patrol ship,
Hideki-class.
Shields up!
Try to send an emergency
subspace signal to the station.
l... l can't.
They're jamming all
subspace frequencies.
They're hailing us.
This is Miles O'Brien
of Starbase Deep Space 9.
State your business.
Mr. O'Brien,
we've spoken before.
My name is Evek.
Shut down your drive,
and come to a full stop.
We're beaming
an inspection team aboard.
We're nowhere near
the Cardassian border.
You've no authority here.
We'll argue
about authority later.
For now,
you will either comply
or we will take
preemptive action.
Warning.
Sensors are reading
photo lock-on activation.
You have ten seconds.
Don't worry.
We haven't done anything.
Thank you
for your cooperation.
l have orders to arrest you,
Mr. O'Brien.
Arrest?
Search the ship.
What are the charges?
You have the right to refuse
to answer questions
but such refusal may be
construed as a sign of guilt.
l demand to know
what l'm being accused of.
You deny all knowledge
of this crime, then?
How the hell am l supposed
to deny something
when l don't know what
you're talking about?
So you do not
deny all knowledge?
We are Federation citizens
and we have rights.
Yes, yes, all your rights
as defined by Cardassian
Articles of Jurisprudence
will be protected.
l demand to speak
to my Commander.
We will contact your Commander
and see that your wife
is returned safely
to your station.
You will be taken
to Central Prison
on Cardassia Prime
to await trial.
All right.
l'm not going anywhere with you.
Miles!
No!
Look to the children.
They are the future
of Cardassia
and they will lead the way.
lnvest in their minds.
Teach them carefully...
Remove your clothes.
My name's Miles O'Brien.
My rank, Chief of Operations,
Starfleet.
l'm a Federation citizen.
Remove your clothes.
My name is Miles O'Brien.
My rank is Chief of Operations,
Starfleet.
l'm a Federation citizen.
Would you care to make
a confession?
My name is Miles O'Brien.
My rank is Chief of Operations,
Starfleet.
l am a citizen
of the Federation!
Process him.
My name is...
Miles...
O'Brien.
My rank is...
Chief of...
Operations...
Has he been processed?
He has.
You were told he was
not to be harmed.
He had to be restrained.
Bring him his clothing.
l apologize for the way
you've been treated,
Mr. O'Brien.
l'm Makbar, Chief Archon.
l want your stay here
to be as comfortable
as possible
under the circumstances.
l've scheduled your trial
to begin in two days.
You've been assigned
the venerable Kovat
as public conservator.
As what?
Your lawyer.
Many feel that he's the best
counsel in all Cardassia.
What do l need a lawyer for?
What am l charged with?
Who's accusing me?
All in good time, Mr. O'Brien.
All in good time.
Starfleet has ordered
the Enterprise
the Prokofiev
and the Valdemar
to the border
of the Demilitarized Zone.
Hopefully,
when the Cardassians see
that they are risking the
entire treaty over this...
ln the meantime, my husband
is being violated by them.
Every shred of his humanity
is being violated.
lsn't that true?
We don't know exactly...
Damn it!
Don't lie to me!
They're torturing him
as we sit here.
lt is standard procedure
for the Cardassians
to use torture
in their interrogations.
You are correct, Mrs. O'Brien.
You don't know how many times
Miles spoke to me about this--
what the Cardassians did
to the prisoners
they took at Setlik lll.
What they were like
when they came back.
The thought of it,
it disgusted him.
lt scared him.
We can't leave him there.
We don't even know where he's
being held on Cardassia Prime.
Keiko, l promise you
as soon as we have
more information
l'll do everything
in my power to...
Commander, you have
a subspace transmission
from Cardassia Prime.
On screen.
l'm Benjamin Sisko,
Commander of Deep Space 9.
My name is Makbar.
l'm the Archon representing
the Cardassian Empire
in its case
against Miles O'Brien.
May l speak with him?
That is not possible.
May l see him?
-Commander...
-May l be assured
that he is well
and being treated properly?
Mr. O'Brien is being treated
with great care and respect.
Good, because if he is not
l will hold you
personally responsible.
And if that sounds
like a threat, it is.
Gul Dukat's told me about you.
You live up
to your reputation, Commander.
That's right, l do.
Now, what are the charges
against Chief O'Brien?
The charges will be announced
when the trial begins
as is customary
in Cardassian jurisprudence.
How can we prepare
for the trial
if we don't know the charges?
Mrs. O'Brien, l take it?
Yes.
Mrs. O'Brien, there's nothing
for you to prepare.
Your husband's verdict
has already been determined.
He is guilty.
The trial will reveal
how this guilt was proven
by the most efficient
criminal investigation system
in the Quadrant.
You may, if you desire,
attend this trial, which begins
in two days' time.
We'll be there.
Oh, l'm sorry, Commander.
This is a privilege
enjoyed solely by the spouse
of an offender.
What about his nestor?
His counsel and his nestor
will be assigned by the court.
Nestor?
Advisor to the offender.
Madam Archon, l volunteer to
serve as nestor in this trial.
That is not possible.
The nestor must be
an officer of the court.
l am an officer of the court.
Chief of Security Odo.
l served Gul Dukat on Terok Nor.
You may check my credentials.
l was designated an officer
of the Cardassian Court
four years ago, in order
to testify in criminal cases.
Very well.
lf this is true,
you may accompany Mrs. O'Brien
and serve as nestor.
May l ask, what penalty
does Mr. O'Brien face?
His execution is scheduled
for next week.
How can you schedule
an execution
before a trial even begins?
We believe in swift justice.
Mrs. O'Brien, we should
leave immediately.
Begin a complete security sweep
of the station
and Chief O'Brien's
recent activities.
l want to know if there's
anything out of the ordinary
that might begin
to explain this.
Commander, Chief
O'Brien's attitude
towards the Cardassians
is hardly a secret.
What if he actually
has done something?
Then we need to know
that, too, don't we?
Miles O'Brien?
Eh, yes, of course you are.
l'm Conservator Kovat.
l've been told that l've
already been charged
indicted, convicted
and sentenced.
What would l need
with a lawyer?
Ah, Mr. O'Brien, if it sounds
immodest of me, l apologize.
But the role
of public conservator
is key to the productive
functioning of our courts.
l'm here to help you concede
the wisdom of the state
to prepare you to accept the
inevitable with equanimity.
Ha!
There's an old
Cardassian expression:
''Confession is good
for the soul.''
But it's also good
for the populace to see
people like you confess.
lt makes them feel better
about themselves.
lt makes them-- makes their
lives-- more bearable.
So, that's what this
is all about?
Make the people
of Cardassia feel better, huh?
No, no, no, no.
But that's...
that's not a bad side effect.
Now then, we have
your biographical extracts.
We have
your Starfleet records.
All this will be very useful.
What am l being charged with?
Oh, no need to worry about that
at this point.
This is insane!
Now, whatever you've done
whatever the charges
against you
none of that really matters
in the long run.
What does matter?
This trial is to demonstrate
the futility of behavior
contrary to good order.
Everyone will find it
most uplifting.
Not everyone.
Once again,
justice will be done.
Our lives will be reaffirmed,
safe and secure.
Here on Cardassia,
all crimes are solved
all criminals are punished,
all endings are happy.
Even the poorest of our subjects
can walk the streets
in the dead of night
in perfect safety.
You're only one man,
but your conviction
will be a salutary experience
for millions.
Now then...
the trial opens tomorrow.
Do you have any questions
anything you want to tell me?
Only that l am not guilty
of any crime
and that l hold
this entire procedure
with nothing but contempt.
That's good, that's good.
Maintain that level
of arrogance in the courtroom
and we shall put on
a very good show, indeed.
Oh, l do have one question.
Yes, certainly.
Have you ever won a case?
Winning isn't everything.
Are they all like this?
All of them.
There isn't a photon warhead
left in here.
How could somebody transport
two dozen warheads
off this station
without the perimeter
sensors picking it up?
The metal in these crates
has the same mass
as the warheads.
A transporter
could have been programmed
to switch the two
simultaneously.
The sensors could
have been fooled.
But it would require
a transporter expert.
l know what you're implying,
Major, and l don't like it.
Neither do l,
but there is more.
According to the logs,
O'Brien was in here
just minutes before
his runabout left.
Computer, play
Security Log entry
Stardate 47944.2--
weapons locker.
Request access Weapons Locker 4,
Miles O'Brien
Security Level One.
The computer confirmed
his voiceprint lD
and let him in.
As soon as the door opened
some kind of
field saturation device
was activated that froze all the
security scanners in the room.
l want a full analysis
of that voiceprint.
Make absolutely sure
it was O'Brien.
But it doesn't make sense.
What would he do
with photon warheads?
Give them to the Maquis.
We had an advisory two weeks ago
that a Maquis ship
disabled a Bolian freighter
near the Demilitarized
Zone and stole
a supply of photon launchers.
Launchers but no warheads?
Launchers, but no warheads.
You're suggesting
that Miles O'Brien
took his wife
on a romantic vacation
as an excuse to deliver
warheads to the Maquis?
l don't believe it!
lf these warheads were
in the runabout, they'll be used
as evidence in the trial.
Commander!
We'll find that out soon enough.
lf they were in the runabout
how did the Cardassians
find out?
That's the one question
l want an answer to.
l also want to find out
who the other guy was.
The other guy?
The one who was waiting
to receive these warheads.
l'll have Starfleet lntelligence
begin to pick up Maquis suspects
for questioning.
ln the meantime,
let's see if we can lD
any possible Maquis members
who have been
on the station recently.
Dismissed.
Tell me you're here
to take me home.
l'm sorry.
How have they treated you?
Not so bad.
They did some dental
work when l got here
that wasn't much fun.
All Cardassians are required
to give the Bureau
of ldentification
one of their first molars.
lt's usually extracted
at age ten.
Keiko... is she all right?
She came with me.
She's here? Now?
lt's not permitted
for family members
to visit offenders
in confinement.
She'll be at the trial tomorrow.
The Cardassians
always invite families
to trials and executions
so that the public
can see them weep.
No.
l don't want her there.
l don't want her
to see me like this.
l think that's a mistake.
My lawyer has already told me.
lt's all over but the execution.
l... l don't even know
what l'm charged with!
Did they tell you anything?
No... but we have an idea.
What?
Have you ever had
any dealings with the Maquis?
Dealings?
No. l'm not sure
what you mean.
Do you know anybody
in the Maquis?
No.
Ever supplied
any of them with weapons?
No!
Are you here
to interrogate me, Constable?
ls anyone ever going to tell me
what l'm supposed to have done?
Commander Sisko informed me
a few hours ago
that 24 photon warheads
are missing from the station.
We believe they may have been
in your runabout's cargo bay
intended for the Maquis.
The Cardassians did find
something in the hold.
That's true.
But you know nothing about it?
Nothing.
And you didn't transport them
from Weapons Locker 4
just before you left
the station?
No.
Were you in Weapons Locker 4
before you left the station?
No.
Then why does the log
say that you were?
Why was it your voice
releasing the security lock?
My voice?
Your voice.
l don't know.
You don't know me very well,
Constable, but l... l...
l've been in service
to the Federation-- Starfleet--
all my adult life.
No one has ever questioned
my loyalty.
No one in my entire life
has ever had cause to ask
''Miles O'Brien,
are you a criminal?''
l took an oath...
to defend the Federation
and what it stands for.
l don't steal from them.
l don't lie to them.
l'm no angel,
but l try to live every day
as the best human being
l know how to be.
l need my little girl
to wake up in the morning
and look up at me
and see a man she can respect.
Until now, she always could.
Being accused of a crime
is not a disgrace, Chief.
Some of the great figures
of history
have shared the honor with you.
l didn't figure
on dying a martyr.
Not all of them were martyrs.
Not all of them died.
Some of them were
just innocent men
like you.
Now, l've managed to get myself
named to your defense team.
l'll be there tomorrow.
Your wife will be there,
as well
but she won't be weeping,
and neither will you.
l want the Archon to see
the clear, unwavering eyes
of an innocent man.
ls that understood?
Yes, sir.
Guard!
l'll see you tomorrow.
Odo...
thanks for being here.
The voice modulation patterns
don't match up.
See how the peaks here
and here are out of phase?
So, we can prove
it wasn't O'Brien
who entered the weapons locker.
lt's O'Brien's voice,
but the sentence
was reconstructed
sound by sound.
l've got our Maquis.
l narrowed the suspects down
to 12 people who live
in the Demilitarized Zone
and were on the station
that day.
Raymond Boone, human.
Lives on Volon lll.
Three merchants
on the Promenade
saw him talking to O'Brien
just before he left.
Talking to him and recording
his voice perhaps?
Recording?
Someone doctored
Chief O'Brien's voice
to get
into the weapons locker.
l'll have him picked up.
The offender,
Miles O'Brien, human
officer of
the Federation Starfleet
has been found guilty
of aiding and abetting
seditious acts
against the state.
The sentence is death.
Let the trial begin.
Conservator Kovat,
is the offender
ready to face his judgment?
He is, Madam Archon.
Let him enter.
Mr. O'Brien
you can spare your family
and the Federation
further humiliation by
dispensing with this proceeding
and confessing now.
No, thanks.
Very well.
The Nestor
and Mrs. O'Brien may enter.
Mrs. O'Brien
this court recognizes
the disgrace
your husband has brought to you.
As is prescribed in
the Cardassian Articles
of Jurisprudence,
we hereby offer you
the opportunity to disassociate
yourself from his actions
by testifying against him.
l have no intention
of testifying
against my husband.
Call the first witness.
Madam Archon,
may l confer privately
with the Conservator
before we begin?
l believe
that this is the first time
you are serving as nestor,
so perhaps l should explain
that you have no authority
to address this court.
You assist the defendant,
that is all.
l beg the court's indulgence.
l am new at this.
All of Cardassia is watching
these proceedings.
Private conferences
do not make for good viewing.
You should have done this
before we convened.
Very well.
Make it quick.
Please don't ruin this for me.
l'm only a year away
from retirement.
We have new evidence
to prove O'Brien's innocence.
New evidence?
lf O'Brien is accused
of stealing warheads
from Deep Space 9, we can
prove that he didn't do it.
Of course he did it.
He's been found guilty,
hasn't he?
Someone manipulated
a recording
of his voice to gain entry.
l can produce
that recording here.
No evidence can be submitted
after the verdict
has been reached.
You should know that.
Of course, but l was
hoping that the most
renowned conservator
in all of Cardassia...
You flatter me, sir,
you flatter me.
But we want justice
not chaos in this court.
No, l will have
no part of this.
Enough!
Are you ready to proceed,
Conservator?
l am.
Madam Archon,
may l address the court?
Didn't l just explain to you
that you may not?
But if our Conservator
refuses to bring up
new evidence...
Silence!
...of a manipulated
recording
of the offender's voice
that would prove
his innocence...
You are out of order, sir!
What else am l
supposed to do?
You are supposed to respect
our judicial procedures.
Wouldn't you ask
that we respect your rules
if we were in your court?
Which raises my next point,
Madam Archon.
l would like to move for
a change of venue to my court.
No crime has been committed
against Cardassia.
lt was, in fact, committed
at a Bajoran space station.
Madam Archon,
l am extremely humiliated.
l ask to be relieved
of this assignment.
No!
Sit down!
And you, sir...
do not try the patience
of the Cardassian people.
lf this court finds you
in contempt
you will find the punishment
very unpleasant.
l regret that l have no teeth
to offer your Bureau
of ldentification.
As for new evidence, yes,
l fully expected the Federation
to come up with
remarkable new evidence
in an attempt
to free Mr. O'Brien.
l am sure your experts
can create
all sorts of evidence
to confuse the issues.
That may work in your courts,
but not here.
There will be no new
evidence considered.
Call the first witness!
Look, we're not
after the Maquis.
We're just trying
to help an innocent man.
And l'm telling you.
l don't have
any idea
what you're talking about.
People saw you
talking to O'Brien
just before he left.
Well, since when is
that a crime?
We're old friends
from the Rutledge.
Doesn't it bother you
that an old friend is
about to be executed
by the Cardassians?
Of course, it does.
l wish there was something
l could do to help.
He has a wife
and a five-year-old daughter.
lf you're worried
we'll turn you over
to the Cardassians,
l can assure you that we won't.
Well, l haven't done anything.
l don't have anything
to be worried about.
Hold him
for further questioning.
Computer, lights.
Don't turn around, Doctor.
There's nothing here
you could want.
You have a man in custody
suspected
of arranging the theft
of photon warheads--
Raymond Boone.
That's right.
l'm here to tell you
he is not one of us.
''Not one of us''?
You're from the Maquis.
That's correct.
Why should l believe you?
We knew nothing
about the theft
and this man is not one of us.
And that's all l can tell you.
How do l know you're not
just trying to protect him?
Who else would want photon...
warheads?
The Maquis are savage,
Federation-born killers!
They live to terrorize
and murder innocent Cardassians
as evidenced by these weapons we
confiscated from O'Brien's ship.
These Maquis are based
in the Demilitarized Zone?
They are all
from Federation settlements
inside Cardassian
occupied territory.
Frankly, the situation
is becoming untenable.
How many more innocent
people must die
before the situation
becomes clear?
How do you know
these photon warheads
recovered from
the offender's vessel
were intended for the Maquis?
According to reliable sources,
the Maquis arranged the theft.
l object!
Madam Archon, please!
l thought we went over this
yesterday, Mr. Odo.
What is it this time?
Gul Evek has tied the Maquis
to this plot
by quoting reliable sources.
l think we deserve to know
who these reliable sources are.
Can you provide
any details, Gul Evek?
l am afraid that information
cannot be revealed
without risk to national
security, Madam Archon.
That's an acceptable answer.
Might we know how Gul Evek
learned the warheads
were in the runabout?
Yes, of course.
We learned about them
from reliable sources.
Are you satisfied, Nestor?
Madam Archon...
Enough! This is already
the longest trial
in the history of Cardassia.
Let's try to speed things up,
shall we?
Proceed, Mr. Kovat.
As you wish, Madam Archon.
l'll try to be
as brief as possible.
What is this?
l'd like Dr. Bashir
to give you
a physical examination.
What for?
To help us answer
some questions about you.
What are you talking about?
For example,
why you haven't spoken
to your parents
in eight years.
What's that got to do
with anything?
l never got along with them.
That's not what they told us.
You left your wife
about eight years ago.
You'd been married
a long time--
almost 15 years, wasn't it?
Look, this is none
of your business.
And about the same time
you were discharged
from Starfleet
after failing several crew
performance reviews.
All of this seemed to happen
shortly after Setlik lll.
Bring him over here.
Some romantic vacation
l took you on, huh?
We'll have other chances.
Keiko, l don't want you
to be there next week.
lt isn't over yet.
Don't give them
the satisfaction.
Miles, you can't just...
l mean it.
Court will resume.
The offender will
step forward and testify.
l have nothing
to say to this court.
Under Cardassian law,
you are compelled to testify.
Step forward.
This would be a good time
to advise the offender.
Advise him to do what?
To confess.
To throw himself on the mercy
of the court, of course.
l never heard of a Cardassian
court showing mercy.
That is not the point.
Think of the children, sir.
Allow them to see
a glimmer of enlightenment.
As the offender realizes
that the end is near
let him use his last breath
to show remorse.
Do you wish
to advise the offender
at this time, Nestor?
No, Madam Archon.
Very well.
Proceed, Mr. Kovat.
Mr. O'Brien,
were you abused as a child?
What?
Were your parents
especially abusive?
Did you hate them very much?
l loved my parents.
l see.
Spousal abuse, perhaps?
Was your wife causing you
severe psychological stress?
My wife is the most wonderful
supportive person
l've ever known.
Excuse me for asking.
l'm merely trying to establish
why a fine man like you
could turn into a criminal.
Now, perhaps you could help me.
Sorry, no, l can't help,
because l'm no criminal.
Well...
l tried.
Tell me, Mr. O'Brien
how many Cardassians
have you killed?
Killed?
None.
Since the war, that is.
lncluding the war
how many Cardassians
have you killed?
Madam Archon, what relevance
does Mr. O'Brien's
war experiences have?
His past criminal record
is very much relevant
to these proceedings, sir.
Answer the question.
l'm not sure.
That many, eh?
lt was war.
Both sides did things
they had to do.
Tell me, Mr. O'Brien,
now that we are at peace
do you have a warm place
in your heart
for your Cardassian
neighbors
or are you deeply prejudiced
against Cardassians?
Do you not, in fact,
hate Cardassians?
Have you not
on several occasions
publicly stated
your opposition to the treaty
because, and l quote
''The bloody Cardies
can't be trusted''?
l decline to answer that.
There are no grounds
in Cardassian law
which permit you to decline.
Answer the question.
ls it an accurate quote or not?
lt is.
Madam Archon, at this time
it seems the offender's guilt
has been clearly established
and l see no other alternative
but to concede the verdict.
l do not concede!
You may stand down, Mr. O'Brien.
l am not guilty!
l've committed no crime
and l do not concede
to this court
or the Cardassian Empire!
Madam Archon, l apologize
but l appear to have lost
control of my client.
No matter.
You've done your usual
eloquent job on his behalf
Conservator Kovat.
Thank you, Madam Archon.
This has been
a most difficult case
but it is always an honor
to serve your court.
l object to this.
Madam Archon
how can you continue
to tolerate these intrusions?
Return to your seat.
Once again, the Cardassian
System of Jurisprudence
has worked
to protect its people.
A guilty man
has been brought to justice.
But never let it be said
that there is no room
in this system for compassion.
l sense in Mr. O'Brien--
a man with strong family ties--
the potential
for rehabilitation.
And l'm sure
that he has gained
a new appreciation
of Cardassian law
through this difficult process.
Therefore, l am pleased
in the spirit of furthering
Cardassian-Federation relations
to hereby set aside the verdict
and to release Mr. O'Brien
into the custody
of his Commander
Benjamin Sisko.
What happened?
What...
You won.
l...
They'll kill me.
Then the Maquis
told you about Boone.
When Doctor Bashir
examined him
he discovered that Boone
was missing his first molar.
The DNA analysis confirmed
that he was Cardassian.
He was surgically altered?
Eight years ago, to replace
the real Raymond Boone
who was taken prisoner
at Setlik lll
and apparently
killed in detention.
Well, how did you figure it out?
His ex-wife told us
he came back from captivity
a different man.
She blamed it
on the treatment he received
from the Cardassians,
but it started us to thinking.
So, he was spying
for the Cardassians
even when he was serving
on the Rutledge with me?
But why would they
want to frame Miles?
This trial was never
about your husband,
Mrs. O'Brien.
lt was designed
from the beginning
to discredit the Federation--
to show that the Maquis
had their official sanction.
Gul Evek's testimony
made it clear
that the situation
had become untenable.
Next, they would
have been demanding
that the Federation
colonies be disbanded.
Exactly.
When Makbar saw Boone
in the courtroom
she realized that we had
the goods to embarrass
the High Command
in front of the entire populace.
Oh, l'm just glad
it's all over.
l'm ready to get back
to work.
Oh, no, no, no.
l had to use
all of my influence
to extend your accommodations
at the lagoon.
We'll drop you off
on our way home.
But we haven't any bags,
no holo-cam.
l've nothing to read.
Perfect.