Shoes.
Jake, l've got a terrific
surprise for you.
Oh, yeah?
What is it?
The two of us are going to Bajor
for the start
of the Gratitude Festival.
What's the Gratitude Festival?
lt's the biggest Bajoran
holiday of the year.
Major Kira says
it's pretty spectacular.
And l figured
while we were on the surface
we could visit
those fire caverns
you've been wanting to see.
Sounds great.
When do we leave?
This afternoon,
right after school.
For how long?
Three days.
Three days?
Computer, orange juice.
Dad, do l have to go?
Well, no...
not if you don't want to.
Thanks, Dad.
Nog and l kind of have plans
for tomorrow.
What kind of plans?
There's an Andorian freighter
due in for a maintenance check
tomorrow night.
An Andorian freighter?
Uh, it's supposed to be carrying
a shipment
of those new antigrav tractors.
We're hoping
we'll get a chance to see one.
Uh, let me get this straight.
You would rather hang around
a cargo bay with Nog
than visit the Bajoran
fire caverns with the old man?
Nog's my friend.
No need to thank me, madam.
Here at Quark's
customer satisfaction
is our primary concern.
Now, you run along
back to the dabo table.
Rom, that lady tells me
she misplaced
a fat currency pouch.
Yes, brother?
And that you found it.
Yes, brother.
And that you returned
it to her intact.
l was dazzled by her beauty.
You worthless, tiny-eared fool.
Don't you know
the First Rule of Acquisition?
Yes, brother.
Then say it.
''Once you have their money,
you never give it back.''
Exactly.
You can ponder its meaning
this evening
while polishing
every rail in the place.
Now get out of my sight
before l toss you out
the nearest airlock.
Nog!
ls this what they teach you
at that human school of yours?
Sloth and indolence?
No, Father.
We'll see about that.
Tonight, you'll polish
every rail in the place
until they sparkle.
ls that clear?
Yes, Father, tonight--
every rail.
And, so, the Andorian says
''Your brother?
l thought it was your wife.''
Get it?
''Wife...''
Had to think about that one,
didn't you?
l'm looking for Quark.
You found him.
l'm Krax
and this is my father,
Grand Nagus Zek.
Tell me, is the Grand Nagus here
on business or pleasure?
ls there a difference?
No, of course not.
My father will reveal
the purpose of his visit
when he sees fit.
As for now, he desires
the use of a holosuite.
He's heard
that some of your programs
are quite alluring.
Oh, they are, they are.
But, uh, they may prove
a touch energetic
for his advanced years.
Are you refusing his request?
Not at all, not at all.
ls there a particular activity
he'd like to sample?
The Nagus dislikes
having to choose
between so many
delightful possibilities.
ln that case...
Here's a list of five programs
that rank among
my personal favorites.
l'd be happy
to select one for him.
That won't be necessary.
The Nagus has decided
to try all five.
Sorry l'm late
but the transporter in Ops
needed a minor adjustment
in its upper
molecular imaging scanner.
But never mind that.
All right, let's settle down.
Let's settle down!
Jake, Nog!
What we do is....
Nog!
Thank you.
Now, we only have two more weeks
to get through
before Mrs. O'Brien
returns from Earth.
So that shouldn't be
too difficult.
Right?
Right. Let's get out
our homework padds.
We'll begin
with the older students.
Your last assignment
was to write an essay
defining the term ''ethics.''
Let's start with...
Nog.
l don't have my essay.
Why not?
My padd was stolen.
ls that a fact?
Any idea who stole it?
lt happened at Quark's.
l put it on a table
and there were
some Vulcans nearby...
Hold on.
You're saying Vulcans
stole your homework?
Yes, sir.
Any idea why?
Because they don't have ethics?
All right, that's enough.
lt's the truth.
Ask Jake.
He was with me.
Go on.
Tell him.
l guess so.
You guess so?
He... yeah.
They took it.
l was there.
All right, but l want
that essay in tomorrow.
ls that understood?
Yes.
l hope so.
Did the Nagus happen to mention
how long he'd be
using the holosuite?
The Nagus will be done
when he's done.
What if he injured himself?
My father left
specific instructions
not to be disturbed.
Are you suggesting
we disobey him?
Forget l ever said anything.
The Grand Nagus--
here under our roof.
l've never been so proud.
l hope you can live on pride
because that's all
we'll have left
once he's through with us.
You think he's here
to take over the bar?
Why else would he
have come all this way?
To buy me out
for a fraction of what
the place is worth.
You could always refuse to sell.
Oh, why didn't l think of that?
ldiot!
The Nagus doesn't take
''no'' for an answer.
Quark.
Here.
Good program.
My father requires rest.
l would imagine.
Uh, please feel free
to use my own...
brother's quarters
for as long as you're with us.
That should be satisfactory.
Now, uh, is there
anything else l could do
to make your stay
a pleasant one?
lnvite me to dinner.
l'd be honored.
Chief, l just heard Airlock 9
is jammed again.
l'll get a crew on it
immediately, Commander.
Ensign Jonas?
So, how's school?
We'll muddle through, l imagine
though l'm counting the days
till Keiko gets back.
Are the students
giving you a hard time?
Well, you know how it is, sir.
Kids-- there's nothing
they like better
than to take advantage
of a substitute teacher.
l always did.
l hope Jake's behaving himself.
Jake?
He's a fine lad, sir.
lt's just...
well...
Just what?
lt's just, if he were my son
l'd find a friend for him
other than Nog.
l'm afraid that's
easier said than done.
The two of them have
become inseparable.
l'd find a way
to separate them, sir.
That Nog's a bad influence.
l appreciate the advice,
Chief, but l trust my son.
Besides, if l get
between them now
it would become me versus Nog
and l'm not going to force
Jake to choose between us.
Why not?
Because l'd probably lose.
Oh, l doubt that, sir.
That's because
your daughter's three.
Wait until she's 14.
Are you sure?
My compliments, Quark.
Mmm! These tube grubs
are chilled to perfection.
Did l say l was finished?
Please, help yourself.
l ran into
your cousin Barbo recently.
Barbo? l thought he
was still in that
Tarahong detention center.
They finally released him.
How fortunate.
He told me
how the two of you sold
those defective warp drives
to the Tarahong government.
Very clever.
Oh, it was nothing.
The Tarahongians are
an incredibly gullible people.
He also told me
how you betrayed him
to the authorities
and left him to rot behind bars
while you kept all the profits.
The Sixth Rule of Acquisition
expressly states...
''Never allow family to stand
in the way of opportunity.''
l certainly never have.
You see?
l told you he had brains.
You've done very well
for yourself, Quark.
Not that well.
Don't contradict your elders.
lt's impolite.
l suppose
l'm doing quite well at that.
lt was a stroke of brilliance
to open a bar so close
to a stable wormhole.
He didn't even know
the wormhole existed!
That's what makes it
so impressive.
He had the instinct, the ears
to make the smart move
before anyone else did.
You could learn
from his example.
Boy!
Can l go now?
l have homework.
Did he say...
...homework?
There's a Federation
school here
run by a hu-man, a female.
And you allow your son
to attend such a place?
Nog, l never want you to
step foot in there again.
Now, go to your room.
And no studying.
My apologies, Nagus.
lt's those
Federation do-gooders--
always sticking their ugly noses
in other people's business.
Most distressing.
Yes, Nagus, most distressing.
Yes, yes.
Now, speaking of business--
Quark, l've come to ask
a favor of you
and one that would be
very important to me.
l need your bar.
l knew it.
And your services as host
for an important conference
to be held here tomorrow
at 9:00 sharp.
l would, uh,
consider it a privilege.
And the purpose
of this conference is, uh...?
The future.
And for Ferengi
business interests
the future is already here
and its name
is the Gamma Quadrant.
Ferengi Transport Sepulo
has put in at Docking Bay 5.
That's the third Ferengi ship
to arrive here
in the last 18 hours.
Maybe it's Quark's birthday.
My advice is to lock
up the silverware.
l don't think we have
to go that far.
Sisko to Odo.
Go ahead, Commander.
About all of these Ferengi
visitors we've been getting...
l'm already on it.
No, no, no!
ls something wrong?
You can't seat
Turot next to Hoex.
They've been bitter rivals
ever since Hoex bought out
Turot's controlling interest
in the cargo ports
on Volchok Prime.
Rom! Change these seating
arrangements immediately.
Quickly, you fool
before l toss you
out the nearest airlock.
l thought you understood
this was to be
a private meeting.
Yes.
Go away!
We're closed!
Shoo! Shoo!
What's the delay?
We await the Grand Nagus.
Well, he better show
his ears soon
or l'm leaving.
No one leaves
until the conference
has concluded.
Still hiding
in your father's shadow?
The Nagus casts
a very long shadow.
Careful you don't
disappear in it!
l see we're all here.
Enough drinks.
All right, l'm going.
Quickly.
No, you stay.
Me?
Gentlemen, be seated.
Hey, Nog.
Where were you this morning?
l'm through with school.
What do you mean through?
l mean l don't have to attend
those boring classes anymore.
ls this your father's idea?
lt's the right decision.
Look, if you want,
l'll talk to Mr. O'Brien.
No.
l don't belong there.
Don't you want to learn things?
You mean like ethics?
Yeah, and other stuff.
You don't understand.
l'm a Ferengi.
For me, school is
a waste of time.
Why is that?
Because there's no profit in it.
So why are you
getting mad at me?
Because you're a stupid hu-man
and l don't know
why l bother with you.
l'm stupid?
You're the one
not going to school.
See if l care.
And lastly, l would like
to salute Nava
whose takeover of the Arcybite
mining refineries
in the Clarius System
is now complete.
l congratulate you all.
Profits are better than ever.
Nevertheless, it is becoming
more and more difficult
to find truly lucrative
business opportunities
here in the Alpha Quadrant.
And why?
Because no matter where we go
our reputation precedes us--
a reputation tainted
by the lies of our competitors
who maliciously spread
the erroneous impression
that we are not to be trusted.
But now, thanks to the discovery
of the wormhole
for the first time, we can now
avoid such falsehoods.
The Gamma Quadrant, gentlemen--
millions of new worlds
at our very doorstep.
The potential
for Ferengi business expansion
is staggering.
And best of all
no one there has
ever heard the name Ferengi.
Our reputation will be
absolutely stainless.
Our word can be our bond.
Until we decide to break it.
lt'll be the good old days
all over again.
And who shall lead us
in this great endeavor?
Who else, but my father?
The Nagus.
The Grand Nagus!
Yes! Yes!
Nagus!
l thank you
for your confidence
but l must decline the offer.
But, Father...
l'm old.
The fire dims.
l'm just not as greedy
as l used to be.
Yes, you are, more so.
No, my mind's made up.
l've already chosen
my successor.
-Ooh.
Ahem.
A leader
whose vision, imagination
and avarice
will oversee Ferengi ventures
in the Gamma Quadrant.
The new Grand Nagus...
Quark!
He's a lobeless amateur!
Father, have you
lost your mind?
l won't stand for it!
This is outrageous!
Congratulations.
l know you'll do
a wonderful job.
Oatmeal lumpy again?
No, l'm just not hungry.
Want to talk about it?
lt's Nog.
His father's pulled him
out of school.
l see.
lt's not fair.
Nog can't even read.
School's not going
to be much fun without him.
You can still get together
with him after school.
Maybe. l don't think he wants
to be my friend anymore.
Did he say why?
He says humans and Ferengis
don't get along.
Usually they don't.
But you're the one always saying
that we should make friends
with other cultures.
l believe that, and l'm glad
you believe it, too
but human values
and Ferengi values
are very different.
We've never been able
to form a common bond.
So Nog goes his way,
and l go mine.
These things happen.
Hey, how about after school,
we play a little baseball?
l can't.
l have something to do.
Grand Nagus Quark.
l love the sound of that.
l'm afraid we were never
formally introduced.
l am Gral,
your new best friend.
You wish to serve me?
l wish to protect you.
Protect me?
From those who are jealous
of your position
and wish to take your place.
They can be very dangerous.
How do l stop them?
Leave it to me.
l'm not going to allow anybody
to harm such a grateful friend
as yourself.
How grateful am l?
Grateful enough to make sure
that l have my pick
of the most lucrative
Gamma Quadrant opportunities.
And if l refuse?
You won't.
Nagus, l'm
in desperate trouble.
So am l-- and please,
call me Zek.
Now, which would you choose--
Risa or Balosnee Vl?
l don't quite follow.
For my vacation.
My first in 85 years.
l'm told, on Balosnee
the soothing harmonies
of the tides
can cause the most
stimulating hallucinations
but when l think of those
voluptuous Risian females...
Nagus, please...
Gral just threatened my life.
So he's the first, is he?
Well, he won't be the last.
But what am l to do?
You picked me
for your successor.
Surely, you must have
some advice.
To survive, you must
surround yourself
with loyal men.
That's good.
But not too loyal.
Never trust anyone
who places your prosperity
above their own.
l see.
And remember, when in doubt,
be ruthless.
Yes. l can do that.
Go on.
Zek?
Zek?!
l didn't do anything.
l don't know, Krax.
20 bars of gold-pressed latinum?
Uh... l'll need
to think about it.
ln a year, it'll be
worth twice as much.
All right, l'll take it.
You want me to be
your bodyguard?
Think of it as a promotion.
But why me?
You're the only one left
l can trust.
You're my closest associate.
My friend, my brother.
But l thought...
since you'll be so busy
being Grand Nagus
l could take over
running the bar.
You-- run my bar?
Not exactly overcome by grief,
are we?
This is
a private funeral service.
Hmm. You have my sympathies
for your loss.
Nevertheless, when someone
dies on my station
there are questions
that must be answered.
There was nothing suspicious
about my father's death.
lt was caused
by a massive infection
of the tympanic membrane--
a chronic condition.
Then l hope you won't mind
if l ask Dr. Bashir
to examine the body.
That would be difficult.
What's this?
My piece of Zek.
You see, when a Ferengi
of my father's stature dies
the body is automatically
vacuum-desiccated
and sold
as a prized collectible.
How touching.
-l know there's...
-l wonder...
Go ahead.
lt wasn't important.
l guess humans and Ferengis
don't have a lot to talk about.
That's what my father says.
Mine, too.
That doesn't mean they're right.
We always had stuff
to talk about before.
So, what do you say--
you still want to be friends?
Yes.
When my father finds out,
he won't be happy.
Neither will mine.
Come on, l have a great idea.
What is it?
Come on.
So, what exactly does it mean
becoming Grand Nagus?
lt means that, from now on,
if you wish to speak to me
you must first make
an appointment with Rom.
Don't be ludicrous.
lt is also customary
to show respect
by kissing my scepter.
l suppose l could make
an exception in your case.
You see the discoloration
around the impact perimeter?
These are sorium
and argine traces.
Aren't they Ferengi explosives?
Exactly. What we have here
is a Ferengi locator bomb
designed to lock on
to a target's pheromones.
You mean they're
attracted to body odor?
Mm-hmm. Very deadly
and very accurate.
lf Quark hadn't lowered
his head at the last second...
-Commander.
-Yes, Doctor?
l've just given Quark
a thorough examination.
He's a bit shaken
up, nothing more.
l guess it's time
to have a little chat
with the Grand Nagus.
l'd be delighted.
When are you
going to get it through
your twisted
little brain that we
are trying to save your life?
You're trying to interfere
in Ferengi affairs of state.
Which are none of your concern.
Now, look here, Quark...
Uh-uh-uh-- Grand Nagus Quark.
Those locator bombs
are damn near foolproof.
You were lucky once.
Next time, we could be
scraping you off the walls.
The Grand Nagus does not ask
for help from outsiders.
l'm sure whoever tried to kill
you is counting on that.
You must have some suspicion
who that could be.
l'm suspicious of everybody.
But who would you say
stands to benefit
the most from your death?
Let's see.
That would have to be Krax.
Yes, if anything
were to happen to me
Krax becomes Nagus.
True, but let's not forget that
it was Gral who threatened you.
Threatened you?
How?
That's none of your concern.
Besides, Gral and Krax
were at the funeral
when the bomb went off
which means that neither one
of them could have set it.
Whoever planned this could
have had an accomplice.
You're sure all of Zek's
associates attended the funeral?
Yes, yes, they were all there.
Look, this is getting us
nowhere.
What about Zek's servant?
You mean Maihar'du?
What about him?
Was he at the funeral?
l don't recall
seeing him there.
Do you?
Now that you mention it--
no, l don't.
lnteresting.
Hupyrian servants are renowned
for their devotion
to their employers.
For Maihar'du
not to have shown up
at Zek's funeral
is very odd indeed.
You were out pretty
late last night.
l was?
You came in after midnight.
Uh... l guess l got
kind of busy doing stuff.
What kind of stuff?
Nothing important,
just hanging around.
With Nog.
We weren't doing anything wrong.
Good. Then you can
tell me all about it.
l can't.
lt's private.
Private?
l got to go,
or l'll be late for school.
l want you home
in time for dinner.
Understood?
Understood.
The thing is, uh... Nagus
l feel l've done all l can
in the field of gouge mining.
You wish to find profit
elsewhere?
Yes, Nagus.
Where would that be?
l'd like the chance
to introduce synthehol
to the Gamma Quadrant.
A very lucrative opportunity.
Tell me, Nava
when Zek announced
l was to succeed him
were you pleased?
Uh... no, Nagus.
Did you come to me
and offer your support?
No, Nagus.
Yet now you call me Nagus
but is it
out of true friendship?
No, you only pretend
to show me respect
so l will grant you
this immense opportunity.
Which l'm willing
to split with you-- 50-50?
Well, in that case
let's hope the Gamma Quadrant
develops a taste for synthehol.
Oh, yes.
A very smart deal, Nagus.
l seem to have
a knack for it, don't l?
Yes, Nagus.
The rest will have
to come back tomorrow.
All this benevolence wearies me.
Yes, Nagus.
As you wish, Nagus.
l think
l'll head over to the bar
and check the receipts.
-Yes, Nagus.
lf he keeps handing out
these choice opportunities
he's going to become
very popular.
We'll just have to come up
with a new plan.
Something more reliable
than a locator bomb.
Something that
can't possibly fail
to kill my dear brother.
Come in.
l was going to ask you
to join me in a round
of Jokarian chess
but l can see you're just
sitting down to dinner.
l sat down half an hour ago
about the time Jake
was supposed to be home.
Aubergine stew.
Looks delicious.
So, where's Jake?
Where else?
With Nog.
Going through my own adolescence
was difficult enough.
Surviving my son's
is going to take a miracle.
Maybe it's time you had
a little talk with Jake.
Children need to know
their boundaries.
l should know.
l've been a mother three times
and a father twice.
Which was easier?
Actually, l wasn't
very successful either way
so... feel free to reject
what l'm about to say
but if l were you,
l would go find Jake
and bring him here
to eat his dinner.
You would?
Absolutely.
Computer, locate Jake Sisko.
Jake Sisko is in Cargo Bay 14.
Thanks, old man.
...are four...
teen, fourteen...
''Planets...''
''...planets
in the Bajoran s...''
What's that word?
''System.''
That was pretty good.
Want to try some more?
''The lar...
''largest planet is Bajor.
''lt has... three...
moons?''
You got it!
Keep going, keep going.
Okay.
''The third... moon...
it has...''
You clumsy idiot.
You want to strangle me?
My apologies, Nagus.
Stop daydreaming.
Pay attention to your work.
Yes, Nagus.
When do we leave?
Just as soon
as you're ready, Nagus.
l've always wanted
to take a trip
through the wormhole.
Still, it's odd...
Zek never mentioned
that he'd traveled
to the Gamma Quadrant
let alone opened negotiations
with one of its worlds.
Negotiations that you will have
the honor of completing.
According to Krax
Stakoron ll contains
rich deposits of mizainite ore.
A very lucrative opportunity.
Quark?
What now?
About the bar...
you have so much,
and l have so little...
Which is exactly
how it was meant to be.
Come.
Let's not keep
our new partners waiting.
May l say, Nagus,
that my father himself
never looked more commanding.
l've been thinking
maybe it would be wise
to take a dabo girl along
with us.
Whatever for?
A pretty woman by my side
would only add to my prestige.
Never underestimate
the importance
of a first impression.
One look
at your imposing features
and the Stakoron negotiators
will give us
everything we ask for.
All right.
lf you really think
l won't need her...
Believe me, you won't.
Shall we?
This is an historic moment.
Nagus.
There must be some mistake.
There's no ship docked here.
Wait!
Rom, you idiot!
Krax, what are you
standing there for?
What's the matter with you two?
Open the door!
Do you hear me?!
Open up!
You must obey your Nagus!
Sorry, Quark, but you've just
been voted out of office.
Rom!
Brother!
Please!
So, you were going
to toss me out an airlock.
l never meant it.
Well, l do.
''Rom's.''
Nice name for a bar,
don't you think?
Enough talk.
Let's get this started.
Would you like
to do the honors?
Or should l?
Let me out!
Let me out of here!
Please...
Release him!
Nagus!
-You're alive!
Well, Quark
looks like you needed
my help after all.
Don't you recognize your father?
You died.
l saw it happen.
You saw me enter
a Dolbargy sleeping trance.
Maihar'du taught it to me.
But why, Father?
lt was a test
to see if you were
ready to take my place
and you failed... miserably!
But, Father, l am ready.
l am ready.
You saw for yourself
l was about to grab power!
You don't grab power.
You accumulate it quietly
without anyone noticing.
But l don't understand.
The bar, you fool.
That was the key.
All those visitors stopping by
on their way
to and from the wormhole.
You could have sat there quietly
at your leisure
and gathered up
all the information you needed
about the Gamma Quadrant.
What about him?
Oh, you could have let him
hold the scepter
while you controlled everything
from the shadows.
And then, when everything
was running smoothly
only then would you take over.
But, Father...
No! l'm not interested
in excuses!
Go back to the ship.
We'll be leaving here shortly.
Yes, Father.
lt's like...
it's like talking to a Klingon.
l guess this
still belongs to you.
Yes.
lt looks like l'll have
to remain Grand Nagus
long enough to establish
a Ferengi presence
in the Gamma Quadrant.
And l was really looking
forward to retirement.
lf l hear of any good
Gamma Quadrant deals
you'd be right for,
l'll let you know.
You know where to find me.
You've done a very
profitable job
with this place.
Who knows, maybe one day
l'll come back
and buy it from you.
So, Rom...
you were going to toss
me out an airlock.
Forgive me, brother.
Forgive you?!
Why, brother...
l didn't think
you had the lobes.
Such wonderful treachery
deserves a reward.
l'm going to make you
the assistant manager
of policy and clientele
here at Quark's.
What exactly does that mean?
How should l know?
l just made it up.
Come on, l'll buy you a drink.
So what time tomorrow?
How about as soon
as you get out of school?
-Whoa.
Jake.
Dad.
What are you doing here?
l was waiting for you.
Dad...
You're a great boy,
you know that?
Now go be with your friend.