Dress uniform?
l haven't worn this
in almost three years.
l must have lost
a little weight.
Feels kind of baggy.
Ah, it looks great.
Besides...
baggy's quite fashionable
on Bajor right now.
Lemonade.
Since when are you interested
in Bajoran fashions?
Well, a lot of Bajoran girls
come to the station...
with their families.
Since when are you interested
in Bajoran girls?
Dad...
Wasn't it just a few weeks ago
that you were playing
with model starships?
Try a few years ago.
You and l have got to have
a talk, young man
about women.
That's okay.
l mean it.
There are some things
you have got to know.
l already know them, Dad.
Oh, yeah?
And who told you?
Nog.
So, all you know about women
you've heard
from the Ferengi boy.
We were just talking.
Great.
Listen, l don't have time now
but, obviously, l have
a lot of damage control
to do with you on this subject.
Let's set aside
some time tomorrow.
Fine.
Okay, tomorrow morning,
first thing.
Fine. What's going on anyway?
A Vulcan ship has made contact
with a new species called Wadi
in the Gamma Quadrant
three weeks ago.
We're expecting a delegation
from their planet.
Rolling out the red carpet, huh?
First Contact is our most
important mission, Jake.
lt has to be handled delicately.
You might say
it's sort of like...
a first date
with a girl.
You have to show
a certain respect for...
Ops to Sisko.
Go ahead.
The Wadi ship has just come
through the wormhole.
We're sending them
to Docking Bay Four.
l'll meet you all there.
Sisko out.
Tomorrow morning.
l'm positive
l packed my dress uniform.
l can't understand it.
You look fine, Julian.
Relax.
l mean, they are aliens,
aren't they?
l mean, they won't know
our protocol.
lt'll be fine.
Where's your uniform, Doctor?
Huh? Uh... l can't seem
to find it, sir.
l mean, l'm certain l packed it.
Listen to me,
this is no dress rehearsal.
This is the real thing--
our first formal reception
for a delegation
from the Gamma Quadrant
and l want things to go right
from this moment on.
-Clear?
-Y-Yes.
Let's do it.
l am Falow,
Master Surchid of the Wadi.
Welcome in the name of Bajor
and the United
Federation of Planets.
l am Commander Benjamin Sisko
and on behalf
of my senior staff officers--
Major Kira, Lieutenant Dax
and Dr. Bashir...
Yes, yes, yes.
Now, where are the games?
Games?
We were told you had games.
Quark's.
Take us to Quark's.
Right this way.
First Contact is not
what it used to be.
Do they have money?
We don't know.
We didn't ask.
And that's not the point.
lt may not be your point,
but it's mine.
Damn it, Quark,
this is a new life-form
from the Gamma Quadrant.
l expect you to treat them...
Commander... l'm a host.
A host is an ambassador
of goodwill.
The more goodwill
that l can generate
the longer they'll stay...
the greater my profits.
l think we're talking
the same language here.
Not quite.
Allow me to put
your concerns to rest.
So, uh...
do you fellows do
a lot of gambling
where you come from?
We like games.
Doesn't everybody?
You know,
those virgin territories
in the Gamma Quadrant
are ripe for dabo franchising.
Quark...?
You and l might want to talk
about an investment
opportunity...
Heh... at some point.
So, uh, have you figured out
the essentials of the game yet?
l believe we have.
Give her a spin.
One time on the house.
Ah!
Two pinch showing.
Oh, too bad.
Nothing ventured,
nothing gained, l always say.
What would you care to wager?
Ah.
Oh.
What a handsome container.
There's an old
Ferengi expression--
good things come
in small packages.
Sticks?
Klon peags.
Highly sought in our culture.
They have... many...
different...
uses.
l'm sorry, but l have
enough sticks right now.
What's this?
Alpha-currant nectar.
lt's priceless.
Oh.
One man's priceless
is another man's worthless.
Quark...
take the juice.
Sorry, not interested.
Then, we really
have nothing to wager...
except... this.
Get these folks some drinks.
McCoullough.
McCoullough?
Captain McCoullough.
That's the name
l've been trying to remember
for the past six hours.
Dabo!
Good lord, they've won again.
McCoullough's the one
who wrote the revised
First Contact procedures
for Starfleet.
ls that right?
l wish he was here now
instead of me.
Dabo!
No...
they couldn't
have doubled again.
With all due respect
to procedures and to McCoullough
l have had it.
This is as far as duty takes me.
Keep them happy.
lf they ever get tired
of playing dabo, let me know.
Good night.
What's good about it?
Getting ready
to call it a night?
We've only just started.
But...
the girl's arm must
be getting tired.
All that spinning.
Replace her.
Very well.
Broik...
take the wheel.
Oh...
one pinch showing.
An unfortunate reversal.
What are you still doing up?
Nog and l were setting up
a reactive ion impeller
for school.
Nog is older than you, Jake.
He stays up later.
He probably does things--
things with girls,
for instance--
you're not ready for yet.
Come on.
We were just working on
a school project.
You know what time you're
supposed to go to bed.
We never had any problems
with it until Nog.
Dad, l'm 14.
l'm glad we agree on something.
Go to bed.
Fine.
So, how did it go?
Great. Just great.
l've done nothing
for the past six hours
but eat Ferengi lokar beans...
and watch people
play childish games.
Broik!
You disreputable swindler.
l've put up with your cheating
for the last time.
Sit.
Look, uh...
why don't we just call it even,
and no hard feelings, huh?
Or, uh, take another spin...
on the house
or two or three.
A free visit to a holosuite, eh?
Do you know what a holosuite is?
Do you have sex on your world?
Look, take it all back--
all the gemstones
and l'll throw in a case
of Andolian brandy
to make your trip home
a little more enjoyable, huh?
You like our gemstones?
You will have the opportunity
to win more...
a lot more.
l will?
ln a new game.
An honest game.
Very unusual.
l don't think l know this game.
What's it called?
Chula.
What are the rules?
These are your players.
We'll start them
at the second shap.
The second shap?
Can't we start at the beginning?
Only children enter
at the first shap.
Sisko to Ops.
Sisko to Security.
Computer, freeze program.
End program.
Exit!
You?
Shap two.
Move along.
Move along home.
Where is this place?
Where have you brought me?
Move along home!
Falow!
Doctor.
Oh, thank God!
Ah. l thought
l was having a nightmare.
l couldn't wake up.
You, too?
What was all that yelling?
Well, haven't you
ever had
to wake yourself up
out of a bad dream?
This isn't a dream.
We're guests of the Wadi.
What do they want?
l don't know yet.
l just had a strange
run-in with Falow.
He had said something
about ''moving along home.''
Home?
Perhaps they're giving us
some sort of behavioral test
like a laboratory rodent
who must work his way
out of a maze.
Behavioral test?
Now wait a minute.
There doesn't seem to be
any immediate threat, Major.
Oh, no, l'm sure
all you Starfleet explorers
find this absolutely fascinating
but l'm
a Bajoran administrator.
This is not
what l signed up for!
l don't find this
fascinating either, Major
but l suggest we take Falow's
advice and find our way home.
Do the combadges
still work?
As long as we can
maintain contact
it should be reasonably safe
for us to split up
and see if any of us
can find a way out of here.
Use your tricorders
for proximity checks
every two minutes.
And if all else fails,
just yell again, Doctor.
We'll find you.
Mr. Sisko, how can l help you?
Do you know
where my dad's gone?
You can't find him?
Last night,
he was making a big deal
about us having
a talk this morning
but, when l got up,
he was gone.
Have you checked his office?
The computer says
he's not on the station.
Why don't you go on to school
while l track him down.
School's closed
while Mrs. O'Brien's
back on Earth.
Nog and l were going over
to Airlock Three
and watch the Bajoran
transport passengers
come on board.
You mean, to look at the girls.
No.
We were just, uh...
Go on.
When l find out where
your father went
l'll let you know.
Thanks, Odo.
Computer, confirm
that Commander Sisko
is not on the station.
Confirmed.
What time did he log out?
That information is not on file.
What ship did he leave on?
Constable Odo...
good morning to you.
Where's Major Kira?
Didn't report for duty
on time this morning.
None of the senior officers did.
And you don't find that odd?
l heard that Wadi party
went on all night.
How long have you been
a security officer, Lieutenant?
Six years. Why?
Lost many Commanders?
Lost?
Because you've lost one now.
Sisko's off the station,
missing.
All of the senior officers
may be missing.
l want a sweep of this station.
And if the others
are missing, too
l want to know the last time
anybody saw them.
l'm going to contact all ships
that have departed
since last night.
Understood?
Yes, Constable.
And don't call me ''Constable.''
l'm Chief of Security.
Yes, sir.
Last wagers.
The board is ready.
lt is?
How much do you wish to risk
on the second shap?
Um...
uh...
is there a minimum wager?
Roll.
Roll? Roll?
But you haven't even
told me the rules yet.
You're required to learn
as you play.
Roll.
Chula!
Did l win?
Hardly.
Your pieces
will meet the Chandra.
The Chandra?
What does that mean?
ls it good or bad?
Neither. Both.
l don't understand.
Ah, but there's the key.
Some will never understand
while others will consider it...
mere child's play.
Allamaraine, count to four
Allamaraine, then three more
Allamaraine, if you can see
This is Sisko.
l found something.
Allamaraine,
you'll come with me.
Allamaraine, count to four
Allamaraine, then three more
Allamaraine, if you can see
Allamaraine...
Allamaraine, count to four
Allamaraine, then three more
Allamaraine, if you can see
Allamaraine,
you'll come with me
Allamaraine, count to four
Allamaraine, then three more
Allamaraine, if you can see
Allamaraine,
you'll come with me
Allamaraine, count to four
Allamaraine, then three more
Allamaraine, if you can see
Allamaraine,
you'll come with me
Hello.
Allamaraine, count to four
Allamaraine, then three more...
Can you tell us where we are?
Allamaraine, if you can see
Allamaraine...
ls there a way to leave?
Do you think we're supposed
to do something?
Well, this is the first door
that's opened for us.
l want to know where it goes.
Are you all right?
Allamaraine...
l'll be okay.
Some kind of ionic field.
She goes right through it.
The panels on the floor.
She steps on certain panels
which must allow her
to go through the field.
''lf you can see,
you'll come with me.''
...you'll come with me,
Allamaraine...
Watch this.
Allamaraine, count to four
Allamaraine, then three more
Allamaraine, if you can see
Allamaraine,
you'll come with me...
But l did everything she did.
No, Julian, you didn't.
l followed her footsteps,
exactly.
But you didn't say the rhyme.
Allamaraine, count to four
Allamaraine, then three more
Allamaraine, if you can see
Allamaraine
You'll come with me
Come on, just say the rhyme.
Allamaraine, then three more
Allamaraine, if you can see
Allamaraine,
you'll come with me
Allamaraine...
Allamaraine, count to four
Allamaraine, then three more
Allamaraine, if you can see
Allamaraine, then three more...
Allamaraine
You'll come with me.
Allamaraine.
Third shap.
Allamaraine!
l think l'm getting
the hang of this.
Choose their path.
Path?
Short or long.
What's the difference?
The short path
doubles the peril
to your four players.
lt also doubles your winnings.
Doubles my winnings?
Well, in that case...
Choose carefully.
lf none of your players
makes it home
you lose everything you've won.
Oh...
l see why you find
this game so interesting.
Do you?
Yes.
You know, l might have room
for another gaming table
or two
on the second floor.
We might, uh, negotiate
a licensing agreement.
Perhaps we could discuss...
Quark.
l'm busy.
Yes, l can see.
When was the last time
you saw Sisko?
Last night,
when he went home to bed.
Did he say anything to you
about leaving the station?
Not a thing.
Choose their path.
Quark!
Really, Odo, you'll have to...
He's missing, and so are Kira
Dax and Bashir.
Four officers
have just disappeared.
You're sure you have no idea?
Why would l know
anything about...?
Four?
Did you say four officers
are missing?
Yes.
Double their peril...
double your winnings.
Bet or leave.
Odo...
how about taking my place, huh?
Choose their path.
l'll, uh...
take the safer path.
Roll.
Rhymes and riddles and mazes.
What's the logic
behind all this?
What do they want from us?
Move along home.
That's what the man
told the Commander.
A game.
Home is often the destination
in a game.
The Wadi do love games.
Think of it.
We've been given directions,
clues, obstacles to overcome...
Pawns.
Excuse me...
This has gone far enough.
Will somebody please tell me
what is going on around here?!
Why are you doing this to us?!
What is wrong
with you people?!
Madam, this is
no laughing matter.
Don't eat or drink anything.
Maybe it's the Wadi's way
of providing nourishment.
Or maybe it's drugged...
or poisoned.
Falow...
Drink?
We're not playing anymore.
Move along.
Move along home.
You brought us here.
You take us home.
The smoke.
Not... bothering them.
You're hurting us.
Can't you see... that?
Drink!
lt's the antidote.
How did you know?
Scientific method.
Actually, l took a guess.
lt didn't seem like
l had much to lose.
Shap...
four.
Let's go.
Allamaraine!
Now, wouldn't your scans pick up
human life-signs on their ship?
Usually.
But we've never encountered
Wadi technology before.
lsolate that energy flux
on their second deck.
Some kind of intense
bipolar current.
What would cause
something like that?
Got me.
The only thing we've got
that would put out
that type of current
would be a transporter
but a transporter burst
would only last
for a few seconds.
Huh... l think we'd
better go take a look.
No, wait a minute, Odo!
You can't just go
storming onto their ship
without their permission.
Oh, i-i-is that
Starfleet policy?
That's right.
Well, l'm not in Starfleet.
Set the coordinates
to midway down
the second deck corridor.
Uh...
ls it against
Starfleet policy
to press a few buttons?
Energizing.
Choose their path.
No! This game is finished
right now.
Stop the game
lose your players.
Odo...
just stay out of it.
Quark!
l'm doing fine;
they're doing fine.
Choose their path.
Double their peril,
double your winnings.
Quark!
Fine, fine!
The safer path.
Roll.
An unfortunate roll.
lsn't it simply a matter
of figuring out
how to win this game?
Simply?
l don't think we have
any other choice.
Well, seriously, we've gone
from the second shap
to the third shap
to the fourth shap already.
What is a shap?
l have no idea
but we're making progress,
whatever it is.
We're playing
for our lives here, Doctor.
l don't think you're taking this
very seriously.
On the contrary, Major.
l find the stakes
to be highly motivating.
Listen.
l'm reading high
magnetic field variations.
lntense flux patterns.
lt's coming toward us.
Find cover if you can.
Falow!
Next move.
What happened to that one?
Why is it there?
Next move.
Choose your path.
Listen to me.
l want that player back!
lf you would care to play
the game after he's done
it can be arranged.
Choose their path.
Double their peril,
double your winnings.
Give me the shortcut.
The shortcut?!
lt's the right thing to do.
Are you crazy?!
Double the stakes.
Wait!
l know what l'm doing.
l've spent my life
figuring the odds
on all sorts of games.
Now, l'm just learning
this one, that's true
but l know this
is the right move.
The right move
to make you rich.
More than that.
Look at the board.
The shortcut skips
a whole level.
l've learned there are risks
in every roll of the dice.
This way, they can advance
all the way home
on just one move.
Trust a gambler.
Roll.
What?
Blow on them.
Would you please just...?
Thialo.
What?
What does it mean?
Sacrifice one
so that two may live.
You can't ask him to do that.
lf you do not sacrifice one,
all three will be lost.
l can't. Please.
Which player?
l don't even know
which one is which.
Select one to be sacrificed,
or this game is finished!
Fine! Fine!
Fine. Fine.
l can't do it.
l beg of you.
A terrible mistake
has been made.
This is all a misunderstanding.
Please.
l-l've learned my lesson.
l'll never cheat again.
l'll never cheat again!
Please!
Just don't make me do this.
Anything but this.
Please! Please!
Please!
Oh!
Plea...
Oh, please, please.
Very well.
l don't have to sacrifice
one of them?
No. You do not.
We'll program the game
to select one at random.
Final wagers.
Last move.
We should have eaten
something at the party
when we had the chance.
Commander Sisko!
Doctor.
Over here! Hurry!
Where's it coming from?
Spread out.
l can see it!
l found the way home!
Over here.
l found an open door.
Come on, Dax!
Julian!
Hurry up!
Julian, are you all right?
Dax!
Ah! My leg.
Don't move.
Nothing's broken.
What's taking so long?
We're almost out of here.
Can't you see it?
Doctor.
We need some help.
Dax is hurt.
Thialo.
Move along home.
Shap...
six.
l'm reading a tectonic shift
of two ground masses.
We are directly
over the fault line.
The cavern wall structure
has been significantly
weakened by the stress.
lt's not going
to hold much longer.
See if you can put
some weight on it.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
l'll never make it across.
There's got to be
a way around this.
Benjamin, you and Kira
can make that jump.
We're not leaving you here.
This cavern is going to collapse
and kill all of us
if you don't go now.
Seven lives is more
than enough for a Trill.
You haven't even finished one.
How could l live out that life
knowing l left you behind,
old man?
Don't let sentiment
get in the way...
-...of command decisions.
-Of command decisions.
Yeah.
l've heard that one somewhere.
lf you were hurt...
l'd leave you behind.
Then l'm glad l'm not
the one who's hurt.
Major.
Major, you go across.
We'll find a way around.
We'll be all right.
Major, l gave you
a direct order.
Court-martial me.
l can't.
You're not in Starfleet.
lf l were a superior officer
l'd court-martial both of you.
Oh!
Only a few meters more.
Hang on!
Benjamin!
They made it!
l won.
l had full confidence
in you, Commander.
There wasn't a moment's doubt
that you would prevail
in this outrageous...
No, Quark.
l'm afraid all your players
were lost.
What? You mean...
we were never
in any real danger?
lt's only a game.
Time to move along home.
Not so fast.
This may all have
been a game to you
but we take First Contact
with a new species
very seriously
and l don't appreciate...
Excuse me, Commander.
Yes, Odo.
Before you blame them
you might want to ask Quark
just how this all started.
Quark.
l wish l could explain it.
Uh... they just had
a run of bad luck
and then they blamed
me for their losses.
And, uh...
That's not what you said
when you were groveling
on the floor.
Oh, that's right.
You were here for the groveling.
Uh...
You said something
about cheating, didn't you?
Cheating?
l would have said anything
to end the ordeal.
lt was too much for me to bear.
You have no idea
the pressure l was under,
Commander.
lf you will excuse us...
Perhaps someday...
a rematch.
You know...
this game could work here.
lt really could.
Excuse me.
Falow?
Uh, Mr. Falow?
A word with you, sir.
What's your hurry?
l think you'll like this.
Mr. Falow!